<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantified Self on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/categories/quantified-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantified Self on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:32:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/categories/quantified-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Waves</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:32:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</guid>
      <description>So far today has been enjoyable, until around noon when someone texted me with a url pointing to nu.nl, showing an article about the Data Protection Authority telling me it is forbidden for employers to use wearables to track their employees (also on tweakers.net). The research the article points to is actually two companies that run my dashboards. Before I get into details, let me state the following:
 The privacy of an employee is of utmost importance!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lecture in Ghent</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:25:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I gave a lecture in Ghent, a beautiful city and so I decided to spend the weekend at an AirBnB host to enjoy the city! Here&#39;s a picture I took:
I&#39;ve uploaded all the slides from the lecture on Slideshare for you to enjoy.

It was my longest lecture and I&#39;ve learned some useful things while doing so. I find that having a storyline with little pieces is harder to keep up over longer times, so next time I will try to venture more in depth of some of my personal tracking experiments, for example my phone usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Phone Usage with iPython</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:35:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</guid>
      <description>Technology is making it easier to collect data, for example phone usage. From the 1st of January I tracked how much I&#39;ve used my phone by installing an app called Moment. It runs in the background and silently tracks how much you use your phone. As said, the first step towards behaviour-change is providing insight in current behaviour. Lately I&#39;ve been exploring iPython for data-analysis and sharing snippets of data. I&#39;ve started a Github repository that contains some notebooks I&#39;m working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick list of all my recent things in the media</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 09:22:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</guid>
      <description>September has been good on me so far. I&#39;ve started my third year of my bachelor degree while on the opposite end my work seems to increase. I&#39;ve been interviewed for a new TV-programme called Toekomstmakers. It&#39;s in dutch but the video is can be found here:
I&#39;ve also written a column about the Quantified Self an the influences it could create within the health sector. The column has been added to the book Diagnose Zorginnovatie and has been presented at the Diagnose Zorg Innovatie congres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fitbit organisation dashboard</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 18:54:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>The Fitbit (affiliate link) is one of the best tools for activity tracking.The interface is nice and the hardware is durable and syncs wirelessly. For a personal level is good, but using group-wise or equipping all employees with a Fitbit turns out to be non-existent.
During the past few days I&#39;ve spend some time building a dashboard that lets people see the data from all users within a group. It gets all data trough the Fitbit API and summarizes it into a view per day/week/month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe Conference</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 11:42:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve spend past weekend enjoying what I do most, submerge in a community driven event, to come out two days later sleep deprived but full with ideas and enthusiasm. As one of the organisers of the conference you might think that it&#39;s a though thing to do, coordinating it all, but with a wonderful group of people from america and the QS Amsterdam team it was a blast!
The atmosphere of the group was really great and we had almost 300 people at the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Health Dashboard with Panic&#39;s Statusboard</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-15-building-personal-health-dashboard-panics-statusboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 22:43:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-15-building-personal-health-dashboard-panics-statusboard/</guid>
      <description>When Panic released their Statusboard app and I discovered it was possible to use JSON and html to embed it into pages, my mind raced with ideas about what to build. Both the Zeo and Fitbit API offer JSON output thus could be embeddable. To give a quick overview what it looks like with dummy data embedded, have a look at the following image:

The next step is to implement a simple server side script that shapes and caches the JSON data in the correct format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the TV for VPRO Labyrint</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:47:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</guid>
      <description>On sunday evening, the VPRO aired a new episode of Labyrint, a show for popular science. This episode included coverage of the Quantified Self and an interview with me (in dutch)! I&#39;ve included the video for you to watch below:

I&#39;m very happy with the end result! As tracking becomes more ubiquitous more people will start to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pecha Kucha about The Quantified Self and Permanent Beta</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 14:55:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</guid>
      <description>On the 7th of February I gave my first Pecha Kucha talk. Together with Jan-Henk Bouman we introduced the crowd (around 100 people) into the world of QS. With a geek to non-geek dialogue we kept our pace trough our 6:40 of fame. The video is below (in dutch):

Watch the Permanent Beta meetup group for upcoming events about The Quantified Self!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite testing with Talking20</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 20:13:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</guid>
      <description>When I arrived home this weekend, a small package was waiting for me. It included the Talking20 metabolite kit I&#39;d pre-ordered. And tonight I finally got around of donating some of my blood to the spot card. The package included, 3 spot cards and envelopes, and for each spot-card: an alcohol wipe, bandage and 3 lancets.

It&#39;s quick and easy to get started, but I also got some helpful assistance from my mother :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quantified Self and the New Aesthetic</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 01:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>The Quantified Self is all about getting data about ourselves. We distill information and use that to our knowledge to improve our lives and that of others. Self-knowledge trough numbers. As we use algorithms in our lives we don&#39;t think that often about how they see us, but this is exactly what the New Aesthetic is about.
And here&#39;s the cross-over between the New Aesthetic and QS. Machines and algorithms run our lives, and how they look at the world causes us to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe 2011</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:02:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</guid>
      <description>In one year I started with my idea to go the the first Quantified Self Conference in San Francisco, Mountain View. The idea brought me there, with all the helping hands of people supporting me. When Martijn and me got back, we agreed to organize a second conference in Amsterdam.
The QS Amsterdam crew joined in and at the 26 &amp;amp; 27th of November we organized QS Europe. I never organized a conference so big and it was truly fantastic to see 250 people enjoying their time at the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moon phases and sleep patterns</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-06-moon-phases-and-sleep-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 10:54:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-06-moon-phases-and-sleep-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Even before I got a Zeo, I was wondering if the phases of the moon are of influence of my sleep quality. With the Zeo that offers an API, I finally had a chance to investigate. As it turns out after four months of experimenting: the phase of the moon doesn&#39;t have any influence on my sleep quality or the time it takes to fall asleep.
I&#39;ve been building my own interface for the Zeo, because the flash based website doesn&#39;t suit my needs, here&#39;s a small screenshot:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing personal caloric values</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 09:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve started tracking my food intake with Foodzy about 13 days ago. And while doing that I already came across some interesting things. I&#39;ve never been fully tracking my food intake, but the Foodzy app on my iPhone with extensive database (including typical dutch food) makes it quite easy. I&#39;ve been tracking for thirteen days now.
The first step I wanted to take is to generate a baseline of my typical food consumption(and thus caloric values), this way I can see where I can make improvements and measure the changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First nights with the Zeo sleep monitor</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:53:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</guid>
      <description>During the QS Conference the awesome guys from Zeo gifted me one of their sleep monitors. And 1 week ago it arrived by mail. I promised to create as much value in return if I liked the Zeo. And I do, I absolutely do. Here is why:
As an average person sleep 8 hours a day you spend 1/3 of your life lying in bed... That&#39;s a lot of time spend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.
Together with Martijn Aslander I&#39;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.
I volunteered at the the conference which brought me way more then being just there as a guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what am I tracking?</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 12:26:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll figured out to publish this, not only for my archives, but also to share some insight into the data that a person could generate. Have a look at the things I&#39;m tracking to function as an archive or feedback loop. If I have some more time, I&#39;ll explain the things I use to make this all possible.
 Distance travelled (which cities did I visit?) Which people do I meet everyday?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Brussels</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 21:55:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</guid>
      <description>This week I travelled to Brussels so I could give a talk at the Quantified Self Meetup group there. And I&#39;ve been involved in the startup Scanadu which is about broadcasting your health. Together with people like Walter de Brouwer and Misha Chellam we are going to take a different approach to health. During my stay in Brussels I&#39;ve learned a lot (including my level of French, it&#39;s really bad!). Really liked the city though!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring mouse interaction</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 22:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</guid>
      <description>I am an avid user of shortcuts and like to improve my workflow and I would like to discover hidden patterns. This is what happens next. When I bought my Mac 2 months ago I dumped my mouse in favor of the trackpad. Did this influence my mouse/trackpad interaction? Sadly I can&#39;t draw any conclusions about it because I switched my operating system too!
However more recently I started using MacLogger and together with Jelle I&#39;ve made some custom python and processing scripts that should offer more insight into my mouse usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dabblings in Processing</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-08-dabblings-in-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 14:20:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-08-dabblings-in-processing/</guid>
      <description>The collected data of 2010, mostly trough PersonalStats, but Foursquare and Twitter too, is a huge amount. Next to interpreting this data and using the information to create a feedback moment, the data can also turned into art. Nicholas Felton makes a perfect example: his highly interesting Annual Report fascinates me in both visual and informational ways.
As Kees discovered Processing, it left me wondering what I could do with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on data portability</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 14:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</guid>
      <description>I am troubled by data portability. It is a highly overlooked factor. And in many services I used for collecting the export function was simply not present.. If i left the service I lost my data, a sad case... Recent actions of social networks like facebook allow a user to export data, but only by rules set by facebook. Another example could be Runkeeper, which i use to collect my efforts of exercising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopatterns from Foursquare</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-24-geopatterns-from-foursquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 14:44:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-24-geopatterns-from-foursquare/</guid>
      <description>Visualization of my foursquare checkins since I started using it. Quite nice patterns and it would be awesome to use your own geo-data!  Joost Plattel&#39;s Checkins by WeePlaces.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Der Mensch als Industriepalast</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-18-der-mensch-als-industriepalast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 13:02:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-18-der-mensch-als-industriepalast/</guid>
      <description>Der Mensch als Industriepalast [Man as Industrial Palace] from Henning Lederer on Vimeo. Via Kees. Visions of The Quantified Self during history...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>On 20 september the first Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup took place in het volkskrantgebouw. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A full recap can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on vimeo. Sebastiaan ter Burg provided the video/photo capture and Kees Plattel made a wonderful intro! I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoTracking: streaming GPS locations</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 21:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to publish my blogposts in English to reach a wider public. However since English is my second language please forgive me my spelling errors.
Since reading about self-tracking I was fascinated by GPS location and geospatial analysis. As it turns out …. experiments had been done before and I wanted to experience what you could do with the data.

I wondered if it were possible for me recreate this, using my less then basic programming skills and no more utilities then my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self Meetup Amsterdam</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-23-quantified-self-meetup-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 21:47:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-23-quantified-self-meetup-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>Samen met Maarten Den Braber (@mdbraber) en James Burke (@lifesized) organiseer ik de eerste Quantified Self Meetup in Amsterdam. Op 20 september hebben wij de primeur in Nederland, en zelfs europa. Al komt QSLondon eer toe, omdat ik anders nog geen idee had over de opzet hier in Nederland.
The Quantified Self (QS) letterlijk vertaald is de gekwantificeerde zelf. Met onderwerpen zoals lifelogging, self-tracking of personal genomics, proberen mensen zo veel mogelijk informatie in kaart te brengen over zichzelf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Haptic Compass Anklet, een extra zintuig</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-29-the-haptic-compass-anklet-een-extra-zintuig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 18:50:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-29-the-haptic-compass-anklet-een-extra-zintuig/</guid>
      <description>De afgelopen weken heb ik bizar veel gelezen over één onderwerp:
Het toepassen van materialistische dingen zodat je daarmee je perceptie, lichaam of denkwijzen kan uitbreiden of verbeteren. Een stukje #lifehacking, maar dan inclusief hardware.
Om uit te leggen wat ik precies bedoel, The North Paw, een haptic compass anklet:

Eric Boyd - The North Paw: A Haptic Compass Anklet from Loren Risker on Vimeo.
The North Paw gebruik je dus eigenlijk als uitbreiding op de normale zintuigen die je tot je beschikking hebt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-tracking in de NY Times</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-21-self-tracking-in-de-ny-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 13:19:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-21-self-tracking-in-de-ny-times/</guid>
      <description>Op 26 april verscheen er een enorm artikel over self-tracking in de New York Times. Een must-read voor iedereen die wil beginnen met self-tracking of er al mee bezig is!
Vooral medische toepassingen lijken veel mensen te overtuigen van het voordeel van self-tracking. Maar er zijn ook mensen die er negatief tegenover staan. Laat je het zo ver gaan dat je alles meet en ben je dan nog wel menselijk. Kortom waar ligt de grens en wordt het hinderlijk voor je omgeving?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifelogging met de ViconRevue</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-01-06-lifelogging-met-de-viconrevue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 14:49:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-01-06-lifelogging-met-de-viconrevue/</guid>
      <description>De Sensecam is een apparaat waarmee iemand zijn eigen leven kan vastleggen. Een soort black-box, maar dan voor een mensenleven. Eind vorig jaar zou Vicon het mogelijk maken om een Sensecam onder hun naam aan te schaffen voor persoonlijk gebruik.
Op de manier waarop ik het bekijk zitten hier talloze voordelen aan, en wordt het voordeel in de toekomst steeds groter. De ViconRevue is in combinatie met de juiste software en databases geeft een fotografisch geheugen aan iedereen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gereedschap voor self-tracking</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-28-gereedschap-voor-self-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 12:37:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-28-gereedschap-voor-self-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Onlangs ben ik gestopt met Daytum, dat ik gebruikte voor self-tracking. Het was een handige tool met leuke visualisaties, maar na meer dan 100 dagen werd de barriere om dagelijks gegevens in te voeren mij te hoog, desondanks heb ik er een aantal leuk dingen uit kunnen halen en heb ik er veel van kunnen leren. Een iPhone applicatie zou Daytum in ieder geval makkelijker maken!
Ik ben nu opzoek naar een andere tool, met een nog mindere barriere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardlopen met RunKeeper</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-27-hardlopen-met-runkeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 18:28:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-27-hardlopen-met-runkeeper/</guid>
      <description>Ze zijn nu 4 weken in mijn bezit en lopen nogsteeds heerlijk. Ik heb het over mijn Vibram Five Fingers :D Omdat ik graag wat data wil zien, en graag mag klooien met mashups, was ik opzoek gegaan naar een iPhone applicatie die voor mij het loggen van een stuk hardlopen overnam. Voorheen tekende ik braaf een lijntje op Google Maps erbij, maar dat kostte teveel moeite.
En ik ben dan wel zo iemand die het zichzelf zo gemakkelijk mogelijk maakt ;) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wakoopa, tracking voor gebruik van software</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-26-wakoopa-tracking-voor-gebruik-van-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 16:09:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-26-wakoopa-tracking-voor-gebruik-van-software/</guid>
      <description>Als je altijd al hebt willen weten wat je altijd doet als je achter de computer zit is Wakoopa de oplossing.Daarnaast lijkt het mij geschikt voor een tool die te gebruiken is voor self-tracking en dat intresseerd mij natuurlijk :)
Wakoopa houd bij wat voor software je gebruikt en maakt hier mooie grafiekjes van:

Maar om die grafieken te maken heeft wakoopa gegevens nodig. Dit wordt gedaan met een &#39;tracker&#39;, dat is een klein programmatje die je installeerd en daarna inlogt op je account die je hebt aangemaakt op de website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Your Happiness!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-21-track-your-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 11:47:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-21-track-your-happiness/</guid>
      <description>De afgelopen 2 maanden heb ik meegewerkt aan het Track Your Happiness project. Dat is een wetenschappelijk onderzoek in een online jasje, dat onderzoek doet naar de &#39;happiness&#39; van alle mensen die eraan meewerken. Elke dag kreeg je 3 keer een email met een link naar een interview, deze vulde je in. En 2 maanden later was er een rapport van jezelf opgesteld, voor mij waren dit de meest opzienbarende resultaten:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>