<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cooker on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/cooker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cooker on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 15:56:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/cooker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous-vide food with a rice cooker</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-20-sous-vide-rice-cooker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 15:56:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-20-sous-vide-rice-cooker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been on my &lt;em&gt;tinker-list &lt;/em&gt;for around 4 years, and I&#39;ve finally got around doing it. I made a little temperature controlled relay to my rice-cooker which enables me to use it as a sous-vide apparatus. That&#39;s wonderful, because it&#39;s now easier to prepare meat, and most importantly, eat 67 °C eggs. So how did I do it? I bought a really cheap PID &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dx.com/p/digital-temperature-controller-66334?r=41389038&#34;&gt;from DealExtreme&lt;/a&gt;, and with some help of Martin Deen I had everything set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s where things got wrong 4 years ago... The PID didn&#39;t seem to function properly, I couldn&#39;t find a way to calibrate it and I was missing tools and manuals to create a good enclosure for the PID. So I left the project catching dust in a drawer..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking up and getting down in Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 15:54:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>I made a small visit to Paris at the start of November and I had the opportunity to visit the Lab Store. I&#39;ve read about the concept in a book called The Lab that I&#39;ve bought during my first visit to San Francisco. It&#39;s just pure luck that I come across that book in a little bookstore, but it feels like the adventure is just about to start..
While visiting the Lab Store I had to buy one of the Le Whaf&#39;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>