<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>italy on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/italy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in italy on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:42:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On holiday in Italy: Rome, Florence, Pisa &amp; Cinque Terre</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</guid>
      <description>This summer I spend 2 weeks in Italy together with Chantal. We started off in Rome, spending our time in Trastevere. We visited all the main tourist attractions, because I hadn&#39;t visited Rome before. Time passed by pretty quickly and we traveled to Florence by BlaBlaCar. After a day of traveling, it&#39;s great to jump in a pool!
Florence is an amazing city, especially when you can watch the sun set over the city, the food is good and if you dive a bit into Italian culture you&#39;ll find hidden gems!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lago di Garda</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 17:43:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been on a little holiday!The destination was Moniga del Garda, Italy. And I&#39;ve shot some great panorama&#39;s that I wanted to share with you:
This summer I&#39;m visiting Sri Lanka and I bought a little pocket camera to help me with some better pictures. I chose the S120, because of Neistat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small bite of news</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 20:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</guid>
      <description>Just two quick bits of newsworthy stuff I wanted to share with you since I got back from Italy (which was really wonderful!):
I gave a small interview about big-data for the dutch television programme Bedrijf in Beeld. Quite happy with the result:

Also, we reached the local dutch newspaper De Spits. The Quantified Self was mentioned by the Rode Kater, a famous little comic:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>