<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>keyboard on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/keyboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in keyboard on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 21:01:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finalizing the hardware for a wearable keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 21:01:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown physical prototypes of a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;m developing. The goal of this keyboard is to provide me with a way to type while walking or just standing/sitting somewhere. I want to blind-type notes while keeping my attention at other things.
Most of the comments I get have to do with why I don&amp;rsquo;t use dictation. There are several reasons for that, namely I&amp;rsquo;m taking my notes bilingual (English &amp;amp; Dutch) and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to shout around my ideas while being nearby other people, as this might be annoying or even rude&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January: Project Month</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:40:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</guid>
      <description>Before the start of this month, I made a commitment to myself to focus all of my attention to personal projects. Just in between clients I could focus purely on my own things! And when January got started, an idea started in my mind that I wanted to take 3 projects to make some progres on.
As it turned out, I worked on way more than 3 projects, still did some work for clients, but looking back at this month, I surely achieved making significant progres on at least 3 of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in previous posts, a wearable keyboard is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a bluetooth Sudoku keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 21:17:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>My girlfriend loves to solves sudoku&amp;rsquo;s and most of the time she&amp;rsquo;s doing so on her iPhone.. As a belated birthday gift I made her a custom sudoku-keyboard with just 9 keys. Who needs more if you just want to do a sudoku right?
This was a perfect opportunity for me to dive some more into hardware and especially bluetooth things&amp;hellip; The entire body is 3D printed and has threaded inserts with M3 screws and basic keycaps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
