<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in previous posts, a wearable keyboard is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandwith problems with Human Computer Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 11:03:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about the bandwidth problem we face with computer interaces. When typing with a keyboard or dictating trough speech, the computer cannot keep up with a stream of thoughts. Our bandwidth is limited by our output.
One of the more future forwards solutions is Neuralink, but to me it seems like quite an invasive solution, not without any risks..
Often times we may find solutions for this in a different space, in this case, a pointer can be found in the legal system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring wearable input devices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 08:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the internet for input devices. From keyboards to voice or gestured controlled ways to get thoughts out of my head as fast/good as it can be possible. I wanted to dive deeper into why this is important to me and why I&amp;rsquo;m interested in this space.
Traditionally pen &amp;amp; paper was the solution that was flexible enough. But it lacked the searchability and ways of exploring it on different tangents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
