<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:18:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Mainsail With Zerotier</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-05-16-configuring-mainsail-with-zerotier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:18:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-05-16-configuring-mainsail-with-zerotier/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost mostly functions as a reminder to myself on how to configure Mainsail to use Zerotier. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with any of the two, the first one is a operating system made for running a 3D printer and the second one allows for a network layer for personal computing, connecting devices over SD-WAN &amp;amp; VPN.
I was running Octoprint for a while, but after a tip by David from Dato I went on to explore Mainsail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VT-40 custom keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:15:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to making keyboards and while I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering with creating a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon many other builds of people that do interesting stuff.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been browsing the usual reddits (r/mk, r/ErgoMechKeyboards and the likes) I stumbled upon a nice looking project that would get me into ortholinear&amp;hellip; I wanted a keyboard different enough that it&amp;rsquo;s worth building. So I ended up with the VT-40.
My brother ordered the pcbs and components, I ordered the keycaps &amp;amp; switches since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Taxonomy (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-12-personal-taxonomy-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 10:28:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-12-personal-taxonomy-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the previous part I highlighted how I managed my notes in folders. In this part I would like to explain a bit more on how make the decision between tags &amp;amp; a linked note.
For people unfamiliar with the difference, this is a #tag and a bi-directional linked notes works like so: [[Note Title]]. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s implemented in Obsidian. It might be different in other tools, but the ideas can stay the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Taxonomy (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 10:07:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>While explaining and introducing Obsidian to people I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the free form way of setup allows for so much flexibility. This results in an big amount of questions on how you would structure the links, tags and your vault. And while there are some solutions like PARA or LYT, I think the best system is the one you create yourself.
One of the main reasons is that you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about how you think about the data relevant to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software architecture for a wearable computer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-06-10-software-for-a-wearable-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:11:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-06-10-software-for-a-wearable-computer/</guid>
      <description>As you can read in previous posts. I&amp;rsquo;ve spend the last year designing a wearable keyboard that would allow you to type while walking. When I finally soldered everything, checked the connections for no shorts I tried flashing micropython on the Wemo D32 Pro&amp;rsquo;s that I use one didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work.. Luckily I had a replacement on hand (learned that the hard-way, I&amp;rsquo;ll always be ordering extra now!).
Before I want to dive into the software architecture, I wanted to explain why I don&amp;rsquo;t went with QMK or at least, not directly (more on that later!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhizomatic notetaking</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 08:15:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</guid>
      <description>The past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the philosophy of Deleuze &amp;amp; Guattari in which I focus mostly on the rhizome. As the rhizome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a start or end, grows from within itself and into multiple directions I saw similarities on how I started to take more notes recently.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my own Obsidian Clipper chrome extension to clip short amounts of text and those are automatically tagged with 🌱.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finalizing the hardware for a wearable keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 21:01:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve shown physical prototypes of a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;m developing. The goal of this keyboard is to provide me with a way to type while walking or just standing/sitting somewhere. I want to blind-type notes while keeping my attention at other things.
Most of the comments I get have to do with why I don&amp;rsquo;t use dictation. There are several reasons for that, namely I&amp;rsquo;m taking my notes bilingual (English &amp;amp; Dutch) and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to shout around my ideas while being nearby other people, as this might be annoying or even rude&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January: Project Month</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:40:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</guid>
      <description>Before the start of this month, I made a commitment to myself to focus all of my attention to personal projects. Just in between clients I could focus purely on my own things! And when January got started, an idea started in my mind that I wanted to take 3 projects to make some progres on.
As it turned out, I worked on way more than 3 projects, still did some work for clients, but looking back at this month, I surely achieved making significant progres on at least 3 of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Query Language plugin published</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just published my first plugin for Obsidian! As a huge fan of the software the possibility of writing your own plugins to work with the data you create is just awesome! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Obsidian for over 8 months now and one of the first things I created was the clipper.
Since a few months Obsidian now allows users to write plugins in Typescript. While I&amp;rsquo;m not that versed in the Typescript/Javascript verse I did manage to write my first plugin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in previous posts, a wearable keyboard is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandwith problems with Human Computer Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 11:03:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about the bandwidth problem we face with computer interaces. When typing with a keyboard or dictating trough speech, the computer cannot keep up with a stream of thoughts. Our bandwidth is limited by our output.
One of the more future forwards solutions is Neuralink, but to me it seems like quite an invasive solution, not without any risks..
Often times we may find solutions for this in a different space, in this case, a pointer can be found in the legal system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring wearable input devices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 08:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the internet for input devices. From keyboards to voice or gestured controlled ways to get thoughts out of my head as fast/good as it can be possible. I wanted to dive deeper into why this is important to me and why I&amp;rsquo;m interested in this space.
Traditionally pen &amp;amp; paper was the solution that was flexible enough. But it lacked the searchability and ways of exploring it on different tangents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
