<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 10:07:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Taxonomy (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 10:07:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>While explaining and introducing Obsidian to people I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the free form way of setup allows for so much flexibility. This results in an big amount of questions on how you would structure the links, tags and your vault. And while there are some solutions like PARA or LYT, I think the best system is the one you create yourself.
One of the main reasons is that you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about how you think about the data relevant to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhizomatic notetaking</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 08:15:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</guid>
      <description>The past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the philosophy of Deleuze &amp;amp; Guattari in which I focus mostly on the rhizome. As the rhizome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a start or end, grows from within itself and into multiple directions I saw similarities on how I started to take more notes recently.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my own Obsidian Clipper chrome extension to clip short amounts of text and those are automatically tagged with 🌱.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My daily journaling scripts for Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 09:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;m quite a heavy user of Obsidian I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of my scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve written for it. Please note that all of the scripts make use of Keyboard Meastro as a way to activate them and some of them use javascript automation within Mac OS X. So it&amp;rsquo;s Apple only for now.
Within Obsidian I&amp;rsquo;m keeping a folder in which there are files that are used as a templates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
