<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>QS on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in QS on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:05:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalstats</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/personalstats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:05:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/personalstats/</guid>
      <description>A little web application that pulls in data from Workflowy to make it more understandable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lecture in Ghent</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:25:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I gave a lecture in Ghent, a beautiful city and so I decided to spend the weekend at an AirBnB host to enjoy the city! Here&#39;s a picture I took:
I&#39;ve uploaded all the slides from the lecture on Slideshare for you to enjoy.

It was my longest lecture and I&#39;ve learned some useful things while doing so. I find that having a storyline with little pieces is harder to keep up over longer times, so next time I will try to venture more in depth of some of my personal tracking experiments, for example my phone usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe Conference</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 11:42:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve spend past weekend enjoying what I do most, submerge in a community driven event, to come out two days later sleep deprived but full with ideas and enthusiasm. As one of the organisers of the conference you might think that it&#39;s a though thing to do, coordinating it all, but with a wonderful group of people from america and the QS Amsterdam team it was a blast!
The atmosphere of the group was really great and we had almost 300 people at the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the TV for VPRO Labyrint</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:47:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</guid>
      <description>On sunday evening, the VPRO aired a new episode of Labyrint, a show for popular science. This episode included coverage of the Quantified Self and an interview with me (in dutch)! I&#39;ve included the video for you to watch below:

I&#39;m very happy with the end result! As tracking becomes more ubiquitous more people will start to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite testing with Talking20</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 20:13:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</guid>
      <description>When I arrived home this weekend, a small package was waiting for me. It included the Talking20 metabolite kit I&#39;d pre-ordered. And tonight I finally got around of donating some of my blood to the spot card. The package included, 3 spot cards and envelopes, and for each spot-card: an alcohol wipe, bandage and 3 lancets.

It&#39;s quick and easy to get started, but I also got some helpful assistance from my mother :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quantified Self and the New Aesthetic</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 01:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>The Quantified Self is all about getting data about ourselves. We distill information and use that to our knowledge to improve our lives and that of others. Self-knowledge trough numbers. As we use algorithms in our lives we don&#39;t think that often about how they see us, but this is exactly what the New Aesthetic is about.
And here&#39;s the cross-over between the New Aesthetic and QS. Machines and algorithms run our lives, and how they look at the world causes us to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Heuristics</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:21:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>At the third Quantified Self Conference in Stanford last week I gave a talk about Plugin Heuristcs, a term that describes something I&#39;ve come across during my years of self-tracking experiments. Here are the slides:

Plugin Heuristics confines an architecture that I propose for self-tracking things with a side-effect. For example when tracking my food intake for at least a month, it changed the way my brain remembers all the things I&#39;ve eaten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up Inspiration: Mijn Reis naar #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:41:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>Op 19 september was ik bij Stand Up Inspiration en mocht daar mijn verhaal van mijn reis vertellen. Gelukkig is dit op video opgenomen door Daan van Bergen (Videologic). Ik startte wat zenuwachtig, maar ben wel erg blij met het resultaat:
http://vimeo.com/30073493</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what am I tracking?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 12:26:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll figured out to publish this, not only for my archives, but also to share some insight into the data that a person could generate. Have a look at the things I&#39;m tracking to function as an archive or feedback loop. If I have some more time, I&#39;ll explain the things I use to make this all possible.
 Distance travelled (which cities did I visit?) Which people do I meet everyday?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>On 20 september the first Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup took place in het volkskrantgebouw. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A full recap can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on vimeo. Sebastiaan ter Burg provided the video/photo capture and Kees Plattel made a wonderful intro! I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoTracking: streaming GPS locations</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 21:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am trying to publish my blogposts in English to reach a wider public. However since English is my second language please forgive me my spelling errors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reading about self-tracking I was fascinated by GPS location and geospatial analysis. As it turns out …. experiments had been done before and I wanted to experience what you could do with the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/8545134&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wondered if it were possible for me recreate this, using my less then basic programming skills and no more utilities then my iPhone. So I ventured into python and after reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://eric-blue.com/2010/08/28/geolocation-gps-and-self-tracking/&#34;&gt;Eric Blue’s blog&lt;/a&gt; I came up with a solution.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>