<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>obsidian on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/obsidian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in obsidian on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 21:55:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/obsidian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workspaces instead of applications</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-02-12-workspaces-instead-of-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 21:55:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-02-12-workspaces-instead-of-applications/</guid>
      <description>As most of my work I do lives on my computer one of the main things I do is switch applications. When referencing something on the internet and applying it in a editor or copy-pasting an address from a contact to google maps search, most of it is done while switching applications.
For some switches the friction is reduced, for example lookups through Alfred.app or pretty printing some JSON with jq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January: Project Month</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:40:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</guid>
      <description>Before the start of this month, I made a commitment to myself to focus all of my attention to personal projects. Just in between clients I could focus purely on my own things! And when January got started, an idea started in my mind that I wanted to take 3 projects to make some progres on.
As it turned out, I worked on way more than 3 projects, still did some work for clients, but looking back at this month, I surely achieved making significant progres on at least 3 of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Query Langauge plugin published</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just published my first plugin for Obsidian! As a huge fan of the software the possibility of writing your own plugins to work with the data you create is just awesome! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Obsidian for over 8 months now and one of the first things I created was the clipper.
Since a few months Obsidian now allows users to write plugins in Typescript. While I&amp;rsquo;m not that versed in the Typescript/Javascript verse I did manage to write my first plugin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Clipper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/obsidian-clipper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:23:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/obsidian-clipper/</guid>
      <description>This is an unofficial clipper for Obsidian that allows you to easily clip a selection to a note in Obsidian. More information can be found on Github or in this blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My daily journaling scripts for Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 09:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;m quite a heavy user of Obsidian I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of my scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve written for it. Please note that all of the scripts make use of Keyboard Meastro as a way to activate them and some of them use javascript automation within Mac OS X. So it&amp;rsquo;s Apple only for now.
Within Obsidian I&amp;rsquo;m keeping a folder in which there are files that are used as a templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for a knowledge system</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-knowledge-systems-obsidian-markdown-roam-research-workflowy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 13:24:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-knowledge-systems-obsidian-markdown-roam-research-workflowy/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a system which would augment my own thinking with the help of the computer. One of the main promises of a digital life is things could more efficient. Or easily shareable and more resilient (Once you have backups..). For a meriad of reasons the switch should be obvious but for the most of us, that&amp;rsquo;s not what we experience. Why is that?
I started of with just Word documents in folders.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
