<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>holiday on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/holiday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in holiday on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/holiday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>London on a double-bike</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</guid>
      <description>On sunday the 10th of June I left my parents place on a double-bike. Together with a friend we cycled to Zwolle, took a train and prepared ourselves in the evening for a trip to London. As we took the boat to Harwich the next day I didn&#39;t know what to expect as I hadn&#39;t visited England before.

As we talked with locals it turns out it&#39;s much more enjoyable if you take the small hilly roads towards your destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka for holiday!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 14:30:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</guid>
      <description>Long overdue, but now I have some time to spend writing a blogpost. The previous month I&#39;ve spend 3 weeks in Sri Lanka! For two weeks, we discovered the island, visiting beaches, jungle, towns and cities. The culture is wonderful and people are very friendly. It&#39;s also been a great opportunity to try out some new things, for example dabbling in photography and exploring apps like VSCO. In this post, all of the pictures have been shot with a S-120 and then improved with VSCO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday to Denmark, Berlin and the south of France</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 10:11:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</guid>
      <description>i&#39;ve been on holiday for most the past month. The urge to travel has been growing since a few years, and this year I&#39;ve been to several new cities in Europe. After the QS Conference in San Francisco in June, I came back, only to pack my bags once again to hop on a bus to Denmark. My father organises a yearly travel group to the Haervejsmarchen. Together with Chantal we joined him!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lago di Garda</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 17:43:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been on a little holiday!The destination was Moniga del Garda, Italy. And I&#39;ve shot some great panorama&#39;s that I wanted to share with you:
This summer I&#39;m visiting Sri Lanka and I bought a little pocket camera to help me with some better pictures. I chose the S120, because of Neistat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a tandem bicycle to Bregenz</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 17:40:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I left the small village of Sloten in The Netherlands with a lofty goal, to reach Rome in Italy. On a tandem bicycle with a friend.
A total distance around 2300km was meant to be covered. In the fourth day, we left the Netherlands and went into Germany.. Traveling trough the Ruhr area and cycling next to the Rhine.
Next, the Swabian Jura and with 2 weeks we covered most of Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>