<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qs conference on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs-conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in qs conference on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:21:34 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs-conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Heuristics</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:21:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>At the third Quantified Self Conference in Stanford last week I gave a talk about Plugin Heuristcs, a term that describes something I&#39;ve come across during my years of self-tracking experiments. Here are the slides:

Plugin Heuristics confines an architecture that I propose for self-tracking things with a side-effect. For example when tracking my food intake for at least a month, it changed the way my brain remembers all the things I&#39;ve eaten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.
Together with Martijn Aslander I&#39;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.
I volunteered at the the conference which brought me way more then being just there as a guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De durftevragen nieuwjaarsboost!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-23-de-durftevragen-nieuwjaarsboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 13:04:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-23-de-durftevragen-nieuwjaarsboost/</guid>
      <description>Via Jeroen was ik uitgenodigd om een workshop te geven bij de Durftevragen Nieuwjaarsboost 2011. Helemaal in Eindhoven! Maar na een lange reis vanuit het zuidwesten van Friesland belandde ik op mijn bestemming. Ik liep naar buiten en keek op mijn iPhone waar ik naar toe moest.... Oei, dat was nog wel een kilometer of 2 te voet. Een goed moment om de LifeLapse uit te testen, daarover in een andere blogpost meer!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>