<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 09:22:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick list of all my recent things in the media</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 09:22:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</guid>
      <description>September has been good on me so far. I&#39;ve started my third year of my bachelor degree while on the opposite end my work seems to increase. I&#39;ve been interviewed for a new TV-programme called Toekomstmakers. It&#39;s in dutch but the video is can be found here:
I&#39;ve also written a column about the Quantified Self an the influences it could create within the health sector. The column has been added to the book Diagnose Zorginnovatie and has been presented at the Diagnose Zorg Innovatie congres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoTracking: streaming GPS locations</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 21:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to publish my blogposts in English to reach a wider public. However since English is my second language please forgive me my spelling errors.
Since reading about self-tracking I was fascinated by GPS location and geospatial analysis. As it turns out …. experiments had been done before and I wanted to experience what you could do with the data.

I wondered if it were possible for me recreate this, using my less then basic programming skills and no more utilities then my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>