<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>usage on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/usage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in usage on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:35:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Phone Usage with iPython</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:35:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology is making it easier to collect data, for example phone usage. From the 1st of January I tracked how much I&#39;ve used my phone by installing an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/moment-track-how-much-you/id771541926?mt=8&#34;&gt;Moment&lt;/a&gt;. It runs in the background and silently tracks how much you use your phone. As said, the first step towards behaviour-change is providing insight in current behaviour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I&#39;ve been exploring iPython for data-analysis and sharing snippets of data. I&#39;ve started a Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/notebooks&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; that contains some notebooks I&#39;m working on. And I&#39;ve embedded the one below where I analyse my phone usage:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning about power-usage data from my home</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-21-learning-about-power-usage-data-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 10:32:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-21-learning-about-power-usage-data-home/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved to a new home, and I got a freshly installed new electricity meter that&#39;s a little bit more intelligent. It was now possible for me to sign up for slimmemeterportal.nl, that let&#39;s you access the power-usage data from the meter by a 15 minute window. That&#39;s quite some data to play with!
Being interested in the data, I wrote a little scraper that collects it for me and stores it in a SQL database, from there on, with Flask and Peewee it was quite simple to create a little API for my own dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>