<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:59:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel member @ Big Brother Awards</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:59:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-awards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalstats</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/personalstats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:05:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/personalstats/</guid>
      <description>A little web application that pulls in data from Workflowy to make it more understandable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Waves</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:32:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</guid>
      <description>So far today has been enjoyable, until around noon when someone texted me with a url pointing to nu.nl, showing an article about the Data Protection Authority telling me it is forbidden for employers to use wearables to track their employees (also on tweakers.net). The research the article points to is actually two companies that run my dashboards. Before I get into details, let me state the following:
 The privacy of an employee is of utmost importance!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on transparency</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-16-musings-on-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 15:10:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-16-musings-on-transparency/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been thinking about and exploring transparency a lot lately. As I&#39;m building dashboards for employees, transparency is one of the key factors of integration within the workforce. But there are some funny things about transparency and this is why most companies and organisations are having difficulty adopting a transparant way of working.
 Ownership is spread when sharing processes, this lessens your level of power, but this world is not just about ownership any more, access is what it is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the Intelligence Room</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months I&#39;ve been steadily involved with a project that aims to recreate an war/control/intelligence room that you see in movies. The one difference is that the room is ment for decision-makers within bigger companies. Often, urgent en relevant questions go unanswered, but the Intelligence Room helps fixing this.
During the Big Improvement Day we showcased our concept and I&#39;ve created a little Django app that matches all attendees based on topics they provided when signing up for the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metabiography, written in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 22:04:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Last month, most of my time was spend on a project for Yuri Veerman &amp;amp; Elsbeth Fraanje, who are part of the Quantified Reality project by het Mediafonds &amp;amp; the Sandberg Institute. Elsbeth and Yuri are exploring the possiblities of (auto)generating a biography from somebody&#39;s meta-data and created the the aptly named Metabiography.
I was asked by Yuri &amp;amp; Elsbeth to build a working prototype For now, it&#39;s in pre-beta phase, but below is a screenshot how it could look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought Kinetics at Coded Matters: Extended Senses</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-02-thought-kinetics-coded-matters-extended-senses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 18:33:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-02-thought-kinetics-coded-matters-extended-senses/</guid>
      <description>Last sunday my brother and I had an exhibition with Thought Kinetics and artist-talk at Coded Matters: Extended Senses. We showed our static prototype exploring the visualization of datasets that are collect and visualized in a static way. This is our first step towards a more realtime system where we can use any data and visualize it on a canvas in an abstract way.

We also gave a talk about our process how we got from a prototype towards a more solid system that uses Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datavisualisatie voor het CBS</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-16-datavisualisatie-voor-het-cbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 11:43:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-16-datavisualisatie-voor-het-cbs/</guid>
      <description>Het CBS organiseert de eerste seminar over interactieve data visualisaties op 3 februari in Den Haag. Voor de seminar is een wedstrijd gemaakt en ik had een vrije middag over om er mee aan de slag te gaan.
Nadat ik alle drie de data-sets heb bekeken leek het mij het beste om de derde (Landbouw; economische omvang naar omvangsklasse, hoofdbedrijfstype &amp;amp; regio) aan de slag te gaan. Nadat ik de data had gedownload heb ik eerst Google Refine gebruikt om de data schoon te maken en te filteren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobypicture Export</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-10-mobypicture-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 19:42:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-10-mobypicture-export/</guid>
      <description>I love Mobypicture. It&#39;s the service I use to post my pictures onto Twitter, Flickr and Facebook. It makes uploading photos from my mobile phone as simple as it could possibly be. Even better, the service is free to use, unlike Flickr which only allows access to last 200 images if you go with their freemium model. But sadly using Mobypicture isn&#39;t without downsides. There is no export functionality as of yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on data portability</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 14:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</guid>
      <description>I am troubled by data portability. It is a highly overlooked factor. And in many services I used for collecting the export function was simply not present.. If i left the service I lost my data, a sad case... Recent actions of social networks like facebook allow a user to export data, but only by rules set by facebook. Another example could be Runkeeper, which i use to collect my efforts of exercising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verrijkte Publicaties, een workshop door SURF Academy</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-04-05-verrijkte-publicaties-een-workshop-door-surf-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 10:06:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-04-05-verrijkte-publicaties-een-workshop-door-surf-academy/</guid>
      <description>Afgelopen donderdag ben ik naar Tilburg geweest voor de workshop Verrijkte Publicaties van SURF. Om 6 uur s&#39;ochtends het bed uit, en om half tien was ik op tijd in Tilburg. Het was nog even zoeken naar de bibliotheek, maar toen ik ook die had gevonden stond er een lekker kopje koffie voor mij klaar.
Om 10 uur gingen we van start en na een korte introductie over wat verrijkte publicaties precies zijn kregen we een aantal voorbeelden te zien.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>