<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>836pm on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/836pm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 836pm on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/836pm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 years of 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</guid>
      <description>Today marks something special. Ten years ago, inspired by Buster Benson I started taking a picture at 8:36pm every day. A simple thing you might think, but in the end I kept doing it and to this day I still do.
Keeping a habit for 10 years makes it a bit extraordinairy and I can say I will continue taking a picture! Below you will find this years movie of all the photos I took.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and reflections about 2015</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 17:34:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</guid>
      <description>Another year passed an I&#39;m due to update my projects page and create another one for next year! To close past year and explore the next I&#39;ve used YearCompass for my reflections. It took me over 3 afternoons to completely fill it out, but it&#39;s an enjoyable ride! It&#39;s great looking backwards into your calendar and see all that you have achieved.
I&#39;ve also concatenated all my 8:36pm photos into a video like I do every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm, a 2014 video!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</guid>
      <description>This is my fourth year that I&#39;m taking pictures everyday at 8:36pm. A little something that I plan to keep on doing for my entire life. Every year I make a small movie off all the pictures! Have a look:

Highlights of this year including a holiday across the netherlands, moving to a new home and Italy! Hope 2015 will be as great as last year! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the 8:36pm photos of 2013</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:06:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</guid>
      <description>Like last year, I made a small video of all my 8:36pm photos. With a bit of help from my brother, I managed to get everything into after effects and put it together. Let the nostalgia commence:

Looking back in a glance, the things I notice are: less computer work, more socializing and the increment in the amount of beverages and food photos. Next to that, I failed keeping up this year and missed a lot of photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2012</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 23:26:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</guid>
      <description>Without further comments, all my 8:36pm photo moments collected during 2012, stitched together in a movie:

All I can say is, thanks to all the people who made 2012 an awesome year! I&#39;m sure 2013 is going to be the same!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shoot a photo at 8:36pm?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-09-why-shoot-a-photo-at-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 11:24:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-09-why-shoot-a-photo-at-836pm/</guid>
      <description>On the second of January 2010 I started shooting a picture everyday at 8:36pm, inspired by Buster Benson. Curiosity brought me into it, and if people asked me why I often could not give a sufficient answer. As if it were a form of art.
But now I often wonder about history... How people lived and how further back you go, the less we remember or can find. Technology nowadays could help us bring a more complete image to our future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>