<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beer on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/beer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beer on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 19:49:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/beer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating my brewery (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-17-automating-my-brewery-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 19:49:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-17-automating-my-brewery-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As an avid home-brewer I own a setup that I use for testing out recipes and recreating my favorite beers with my own twist. Over the last years, my gear has improved a bit and one of my main projects is automating my own brewery. I wanted to document this, so maybe other people could use this as well.
My brewing system consists of a Brew in a Bag (BIAB) system, build on a modified Weck-kettle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing a new batch of beer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-26-new_batch_nooitop_kratfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:51:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-26-new_batch_nooitop_kratfunding/</guid>
      <description>Past week we spend a day at a brewery! We made a new batch for our brewery Nooitgedacht. We improved our recipe of our tripel and you can now fund our brewery buy pre-ordering a crate of beer trough Kratfunding, we only ship to the Netherlands currently!
Our plan is to use Kratfunding in a way to organise enough money to be self-sufficient as a brewery. And as an organization we want to enable more homebrewers to scale up more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brouwerij Nooitgedacht</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/brouwerij_nooitgedacht/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 17:56:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/brouwerij_nooitgedacht/</guid>
      <description>Brouwerij Nooitgedacht is our brewery that I run together with friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something&#39;s brewing!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 11:12:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</guid>
      <description>And it&#39;s beer! Well it&#39;s stored now and bubbling away! Yesterday afternoon I&#39;ve brewed my first batch of beer. With the gear and knowledge of a friend, we manufactured 48 liters of pale ale. The sunny afternoon also was a perfect opportunity for my new camera, so I took some tests shots. Here&#39;s the brewery in my backyard:
The recipe we decided on included star-anise and lemongrass. Sadly the coriander seeds got lost and we skipped those.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>