<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>API on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in API on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 13:46:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinkering with the Meetup API</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-07-02-meetup-api-tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 13:46:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-07-02-meetup-api-tinkering/</guid>
      <description>Meetup.com is a service that I use and have been using to organize events for networks. Even though I like Meetup as a service, there are some thing you just cannot do. For example it&#39;s kind of hard to make use of the internal knowledge or connections that people have within the network itself. And you are limited to Meetup for sending messages to everyone.
About a week ago I sat down to explore their API, to see if you could somehow build upon their service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Moves data for?</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:29:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</guid>
      <description>In July I wrote a little wrapper for the Moves App API. But I didn&#39;t develop the ideas I had for it any further due to time constraints. But other projects got me into it and I wanted to share what I&#39;m currently building. I&#39;ve drawn the same concept of a fitbit dashboard over to a Moves Dashboard, so we can use the same data. And I&#39;ve got some friends who come up with great ideas too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jawbone API Python library</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:15:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been wearing a Jawbone UP for the last few months. There are things I like about it, the app, the sleep interface and the options you have for notifications. Some other things I dislike, the 3.5mm jack for syncing for example... It&#39;s annoying. They have it solved with the next version though.

As with all the other devices that I&#39;ve been wearing I wanted to get the data out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A python library for the Moves App API</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 19:52:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</guid>
      <description>For Quantified Self starters I recommend the really nice Moves App. The interface is really nice and the battery drain isn&#39;t that bad if you recharge it twice a day. They recently opened up their API enabling developers like me to create apps based on their platform. For me the first step towards creating an app is a easier way to communicate with the API.
As with the fitbit, I&#39;ve written a open-source library for you to use!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storify as slides for talks</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 15:34:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</guid>
      <description>I like Storify, a service that lets you curate your own story based from sources like Twitter, Facebook or other social networks. And sometimes I wonder what would happen if you let people curate it live on a beamer during festivals or want to use it for public talks... Then the website isn&#39;t that handy or slide-enabled.
But it shouldn&#39;t be that hard to extract all data from Storify and glue everything together into a slide-ready format right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python library for the FitBit API</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:50:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</guid>
      <description>My quest of building API wrappers in python continues with the FitBit. The handy devices tracks most of my activities and movements during daytime. So it&#39;s an excellent self-tracking device, especially with the wireless sync. There wasn&#39;t an API interface available in python, so with some borrowed code I decided to build my own.
I made an GitHub repository with the code and an example for you to use. Please fork and correct any changes that you think would be useful for me to learn!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>