<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photos on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/photos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photos on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm, a 2014 video!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</guid>
      <description>This is my fourth year that I&#39;m taking pictures everyday at 8:36pm. A little something that I plan to keep on doing for my entire life. Every year I make a small movie off all the pictures! Have a look:

Highlights of this year including a holiday across the netherlands, moving to a new home and Italy! Hope 2015 will be as great as last year! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the 8:36pm photos of 2013</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:06:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</guid>
      <description>Like last year, I made a small video of all my 8:36pm photos. With a bit of help from my brother, I managed to get everything into after effects and put it together. Let the nostalgia commence:

Looking back in a glance, the things I notice are: less computer work, more socializing and the increment in the amount of beverages and food photos. Next to that, I failed keeping up this year and missed a lot of photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2012</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 23:26:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</guid>
      <description>Without further comments, all my 8:36pm photo moments collected during 2012, stitched together in a movie:

All I can say is, thanks to all the people who made 2012 an awesome year! I&#39;m sure 2013 is going to be the same!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>On 20 september the first Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup took place in het volkskrantgebouw. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A full recap can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on vimeo. Sebastiaan ter Burg provided the video/photo capture and Kees Plattel made a wonderful intro! I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifelogging met de ViconRevue</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-01-06-lifelogging-met-de-viconrevue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 14:49:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-01-06-lifelogging-met-de-viconrevue/</guid>
      <description>De Sensecam is een apparaat waarmee iemand zijn eigen leven kan vastleggen. Een soort black-box, maar dan voor een mensenleven. Eind vorig jaar zou Vicon het mogelijk maken om een Sensecam onder hun naam aan te schaffen voor persoonlijk gebruik.
Op de manier waarop ik het bekijk zitten hier talloze voordelen aan, en wordt het voordeel in de toekomst steeds groter. De ViconRevue is in combinatie met de juiste software en databases geeft een fotografisch geheugen aan iedereen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>