<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photos on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/photos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photos on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:36:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2021</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-20-836pm-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:36:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-20-836pm-2021/</guid>
      <description>Long overdue, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing more photos then I&amp;rsquo;d like, here&amp;rsquo;s the 8:36pm video of 2021! Thanks to Quinten Swagerman with helping out making it into a video! (Switching to a new mac broke the old After Effects I was still using&amp;hellip;)
Onto another year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2020 &amp; Planning January</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-06-2020-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 15:18:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-06-2020-836pm/</guid>
      <description>As 2020 is over and 2021 is just beginning I once return to the yearly habits that I&amp;rsquo;ve grown into doing. One of them is completing the Year Compass together with my girlfriend. To other was stuck for a while to the fact that OS X Catalina only supports 64 bit applications, which sucks if you run an outdated version of After Effects.
I had to ask my brother to render the yearly movie of all my 8:36pm photos and thankfully he did, so without further ado, here it is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 years of 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</guid>
      <description>Today marks something special. Ten years ago, inspired by Buster Benson I started taking a picture at 8:36pm every day. A simple thing you might think, but in the end I kept doing it and to this day I still do.
Keeping a habit for 10 years makes it a bit extraordinairy and I can say I will continue taking a picture! Below you will find this years movie of all the photos I took.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>On 20 september the first Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup took place in het volkskrantgebouw. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A full recap can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on vimeo. Sebastiaan ter Burg provided the video/photo capture and Kees Plattel made a wonderful intro!
I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
