<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/categories/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/categories/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>London on a double-bike</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</guid>
      <description>On sunday the 10th of June I left my parents place on a double-bike. Together with a friend we cycled to Zwolle, took a train and prepared ourselves in the evening for a trip to London. As we took the boat to Harwich the next day I didn&#39;t know what to expect as I hadn&#39;t visited England before.

As we talked with locals it turns out it&#39;s much more enjoyable if you take the small hilly roads towards your destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday to Denmark, Berlin and the south of France</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 10:11:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</guid>
      <description>i&#39;ve been on holiday for most the past month. The urge to travel has been growing since a few years, and this year I&#39;ve been to several new cities in Europe. After the QS Conference in San Francisco in June, I came back, only to pack my bags once again to hop on a bus to Denmark. My father organises a yearly travel group to the Haervejsmarchen. Together with Chantal we joined him!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interview for the Perfect Human and other publications</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-06-08-perfect-human-vpro-tv-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 07:55:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-06-08-perfect-human-vpro-tv-publications/</guid>
      <description>Two months ago I spent some time before a camera for a documentary series of the VPRO. The series is called The Perfect Human and explores how technology helps us create a better being. My project with Colliers: The Quantified Workplace is highlighted in the interview. You can watch it online here.
At the end of the past year, I spend an afternoon at the Ministry of Health, Welfare and Sport, to contribute towards a document about e-Health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something&#39;s brewing!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 11:12:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</guid>
      <description>And it&#39;s beer! Well it&#39;s stored now and bubbling away! Yesterday afternoon I&#39;ve brewed my first batch of beer. With the gear and knowledge of a friend, we manufactured 48 liters of pale ale. The sunny afternoon also was a perfect opportunity for my new camera, so I took some tests shots. Here&#39;s the brewery in my backyard:
The recipe we decided on included star-anise and lemongrass. Sadly the coriander seeds got lost and we skipped those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lago di Garda</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 17:43:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been on a little holiday!The destination was Moniga del Garda, Italy. And I&#39;ve shot some great panorama&#39;s that I wanted to share with you:
This summer I&#39;m visiting Sri Lanka and I bought a little pocket camera to help me with some better pictures. I chose the S120, because of Neistat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm, a 2014 video!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</guid>
      <description>This is my fourth year that I&#39;m taking pictures everyday at 8:36pm. A little something that I plan to keep on doing for my entire life. Every year I make a small movie off all the pictures! Have a look:

Highlights of this year including a holiday across the netherlands, moving to a new home and Italy! Hope 2015 will be as great as last year! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Years of computing</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-10-04-3-years-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 22:42:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-10-04-3-years-computing/</guid>
      <description>This picture below might seem blurry to you, and indeed it is, but for me it is a significant picture that reflect 3 years of working behind my computer.

I&#39;ve been running the Lifeslice program for over 3 years now and I thought it was about time to do something with it! The picture above is generated with over 4000 webcamshots taken during that time.
There&#39;s a trove of other data in too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned building Django projects: 2</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-09-16-lessons-learned-building-django-projects-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:42:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-09-16-lessons-learned-building-django-projects-2/</guid>
      <description>As of recently I&#39;ve started my graduation phase of my current study. I&#39;ve managed to get my own project in for my graduation thesis, which means I&#39;ll be spending more time developing with Django. This post is more of a reminder of the things I&#39;ve learned so far... The previous post can be read here.
 The inspectdb tool is priceless when using other databases in which you have no schema&#39;s yet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From east to west in The Netherlands</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-08-07-east-west-netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 15:53:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-08-07-east-west-netherlands/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s holiday, and I&#39;ve spend most of my time last month in The Netherlands hiking. From the east to the west, to complement what we did two years ago. And I wanted to share some pictures of my adventure:

In 19 days we hiked over 360 kilometers, staying at farmers, friends, campinggrounds or somewhere else. It was a blast! We&#39;ll see where we end up next year! For those interested, the route is called the Marskramerspad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self Europe Conference #3</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-05-14-quantified-self-europe-conference-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 10:35:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-05-14-quantified-self-europe-conference-3/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I spend my time at the Casa400 hotel for the Quantified Self Europe Conference. With around 250 attendees and 30% of the people giving a talk, you could truly say that&#39;s been an carefully curated unconference.
 I gave a lunch-time ignite talk about my project Qount.us and people liked it! Hopefully the video will be up soon. And I pre-ordered a few Vitalconnect patches for experimenting, including Thought Kinetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The curious corner on video</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 20:21:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve curated 6 editions of the Curious Corner of the Internet until this day. It started out as an experiment of just showing my saved-for-later links in a presentation. The newsletter essentially was a second format, and I didn&#39;t explore my chances for a talk much further. Until now, during the Week for the Entrepreneur in the Netherlands, that I&#39;d give it another shot. Sadly, it&#39;s in dutch, but here&#39;s the video:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taping interviews</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-13-taping-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 13:23:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-13-taping-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Last week I&#39;ve spend some time before camera lenses. On wednesday I got a call for an interview for RTL Nieuws about CES and wearables. A quick interview got me 2 minutes of fame (on from 18:10) on television. On thursday, a longer interview for Arte TV, that will be shown later this month (viewable online too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking up and getting down in Chemistry</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 15:54:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>I made a small visit to Paris at the start of November and I had the opportunity to visit the Lab Store. I&#39;ve read about the concept in a book called The Lab that I&#39;ve bought during my first visit to San Francisco. It&#39;s just pure luck that I come across that book in a little bookstore, but it feels like the adventure is just about to start..
While visiting the Lab Store I had to buy one of the Le Whaf&#39;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Corner of the Internet</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-27-curious-corner-of-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 20:47:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-27-curious-corner-of-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been walking around with a newsletter idea for some months now. It all started at Permanent Beta where I gave a talk together with my twin. Basically it wasn&#39;t really a talk, just a roadshow of awesome stuff we come across on our daily surf on the web. The audience loved it! Why not curate this content into a newsletter?
That&#39;s just what I did with The Curious Corner of the Internet, a monthly newsletter stocked with the stuff I find during that last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twins in New York!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-29-twins-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 21:31:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-29-twins-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Being in de United States is a perfect excuse for visiting my brother! After enjoying a 5 hour flight (with wifi!) and a delayed subway ride: here&#39;s the two of us before the skyline of New York City:
 I&#39;ve had 8 days to explore the city, mostly by foot and metro. The first I found the most enjoyable, while the latter turned out to be faster most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late night TekTok, talking QS and education</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-04-late-night-tektok-talking-qs-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 22:22:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-04-late-night-tektok-talking-qs-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Last month a give a small talk around the Quantified Self and how it fits into the education:

What amazed me was that the room was full of inspiring people designing stuff for the &#39;now&#39;, thus implementing it only when the future is already happening. Nevertheless I&#39;m sure some good things will follow because people are aware and the connectedness helps solving these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into hardware!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-06-12-moving-into-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 20:34:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-06-12-moving-into-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Software is not all there is, I&#39;m diving into hardware! For the last month a lot of electronics have passed my hands, including sensors, arduinos and others. I&#39;ve been given a Makey Makey by Loes and now doing a hardware project in collaboration with Setup and it involves a big red button.
I&#39;ll try my best to keep you posted of my hardware adventures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small bite of news</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 20:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</guid>
      <description>Just two quick bits of newsworthy stuff I wanted to share with you since I got back from Italy (which was really wonderful!):
I gave a small interview about big-data for the dutch television programme Bedrijf in Beeld. Quite happy with the result:

Also, we reached the local dutch newspaper De Spits. The Quantified Self was mentioned by the Rode Kater, a famous little comic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pecha Kucha about The Quantified Self and Permanent Beta</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 14:55:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</guid>
      <description>On the 7th of February I gave my first Pecha Kucha talk. Together with Jan-Henk Bouman we introduced the crowd (around 100 people) into the world of QS. With a geek to non-geek dialogue we kept our pace trough our 6:40 of fame. The video is below (in dutch):

Watch the Permanent Beta meetup group for upcoming events about The Quantified Self!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2012</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 23:26:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</guid>
      <description>Without further comments, all my 8:36pm photo moments collected during 2012, stitched together in a movie:

All I can say is, thanks to all the people who made 2012 an awesome year! I&#39;m sure 2013 is going to be the same!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Weekend Utrecht</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-11-20-startup-weekend-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 11:31:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-11-20-startup-weekend-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I participated in Startup Weekend Utrecht. At almost 100 attendees, we&#39;ve got the 8th floor of the Nijenoord building pretty stocked.
As I predicted, I got an idea during the pitching process. Luckily I was able to pitch it anyhow and after the voting procedure the announcement was made that I made it to the top 13 viable ideas. So now I had to go and create a team!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quantified Self and the New Aesthetic</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 01:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>The Quantified Self is all about getting data about ourselves. We distill information and use that to our knowledge to improve our lives and that of others. Self-knowledge trough numbers. As we use algorithms in our lives we don&#39;t think that often about how they see us, but this is exactly what the New Aesthetic is about.
And here&#39;s the cross-over between the New Aesthetic and QS. Machines and algorithms run our lives, and how they look at the world causes us to act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Heuristics</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:21:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>At the third Quantified Self Conference in Stanford last week I gave a talk about Plugin Heuristcs, a term that describes something I&#39;ve come across during my years of self-tracking experiments. Here are the slides:

Plugin Heuristics confines an architecture that I propose for self-tracking things with a side-effect. For example when tracking my food intake for at least a month, it changed the way my brain remembers all the things I&#39;ve eaten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking 500 kilometers</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-08-25-hiking-500-kilometers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 18:50:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-08-25-hiking-500-kilometers/</guid>
      <description>That&#39;s what I did this summer, together with a friend. And here&#39;s one of the pictures I took:
(if your interested, you can find the route as KML here)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showertrack!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-07-15-showertrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 22:06:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-07-15-showertrack/</guid>
      <description>So much projects, so little time... But hey, let&#39;s just use some of my spare time for keeping you guys updated on the stuff I do. I&#39;ve been doing several things, but the most interesting right now is a new iPhone app concept that we&#39;ve been developing since last month. Together with Nils Waanders and Willemijn Edens we are creating an app which helps people save water while showering. It&#39;s called Showertrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storify as slides for talks</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 15:34:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</guid>
      <description>I like Storify, a service that lets you curate your own story based from sources like Twitter, Facebook or other social networks. And sometimes I wonder what would happen if you let people curate it live on a beamer during festivals or want to use it for public talks... Then the website isn&#39;t that handy or slide-enabled.
But it shouldn&#39;t be that hard to extract all data from Storify and glue everything together into a slide-ready format right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Zeo Raw Data for performances</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-03-27-using-zeo-raw-data-for-performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:11:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-03-27-using-zeo-raw-data-for-performances/</guid>
      <description>Together with my brother I run a little experiment called Hoofdbeelden. It&#39;s a exploration for both of us as an artist and how we can use data generated by me as a person can be used for audio/visual performances. We&#39;ve had a few gigs so far, but our last at Fiber Festival certainly made sure for the both of us that this is something we want to do.
In short Hoofdbeelden is a system which allows us tap into devices hooked onto my body for real-time information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video&#39;s of a few talks I gave last few months</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-02-15-videos-of-a-few-talks-i-gave-last-few-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 13:03:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-02-15-videos-of-a-few-talks-i-gave-last-few-months/</guid>
      <description>During the last few months I&#39;ve given several talks about the Quantified Self and lifehacking. The video&#39;s of two of these talks are embedded below. Enjoy!
Urban Screens

Inspirationshot #3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011, A Summary</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-01-2011-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 16:35:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-01-2011-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>Last year has been full with adventures! Going to San Francisco, organizing QS Europe and starting another bachelor degree in Media Technology... And of course I continued with taking a picture everyday at 8:36pm.
http://vimeo.com/34264892
Let&#39;s see what 2012 brings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up Inspiration: Mijn Reis naar #QS2011</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:41:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>Op 19 september was ik bij Stand Up Inspiration en mocht daar mijn verhaal van mijn reis vertellen. Gelukkig is dit op video opgenomen door Daan van Bergen (Videologic). Ik startte wat zenuwachtig, maar ben wel erg blij met het resultaat:
http://vimeo.com/30073493</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of my San Francisco Report</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 10:39:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</guid>
      <description>For the people who sponsored me for my trip to San Francisco, I&#39;m building a report inspired my Nicholas Felton about my trip. I wanted to show you a small preview on the right:
I&#39;m aiming to have at least 4 page worth of data to show you. Since I&#39;ve never dived deep into Processing, the building time is somewhat extended, so I don&#39;t know when it&#39;ll be finished. I started studying Media Technology as well, so spare time is a little bit limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I would like to write.</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-08-17-how-i-would-like-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 09:50:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-08-17-how-i-would-like-to-write/</guid>
      <description>From how to live safely in a sciencefictional universe by Charles Yu.
I’m typing, even though strictly speaking I am using the TM-31’s cognitive-visual-motor-sound-activated recording module, which operates, as you might guess, by simultaneously tracking output from the user’s neural activity, voice, finger movements, retinal movements, and facial muscle contractions. It’s part keyboard, part microphone, part optical scan, and part brain scan.
When I want to type, I raise my hands up in front of me, palms down, in a position approximating typing, and a virtual QWERTY layout materializes in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.
Together with Martijn Aslander I&#39;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.
I volunteered at the the conference which brought me way more then being just there as a guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extendability</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-15-extendability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 08:52:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-15-extendability/</guid>
      <description>It started millions of years ago with fire and the invention of language. Then simple tools and in later stages, clothing and shoes. Nowadays the trend continues with more sophisticated technology. Smartphones and watches are some of the things we keep on us at all times. Humans have developed the habit to extend themselves by using technology. In such a way that it sprouted a certain feeling of loss when not having access to the technology of which we&#39;ve made our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welkom!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-18-welkom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 12:29:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-18-welkom/</guid>
      <description>Dit is de eerste nieuwe post op jplattel.nl, een verhuizing vanaf laborantje.nl. Ik had hier verscheidene redenen voor:
 Met de username ‘laborantje’ was ik uiteindelijk niet zo tevreden. Ik had graag liever iets met mijn eigen naam erin. Ik hoef met mijn naam niet persé verbonden te zijn aan de chemie (alhoewel dit zeer interessant is!). Laborantje.nl ging al snel over iets anders. Mijn blog kon wel een nieuw format gebruiken.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>