<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clients on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clients on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:00:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/client/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Symbiose Studio</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/symbiose-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/symbiose-studio/</guid>
      <description>Working with Bertrand from Symbiose Studio I&amp;rsquo;ve build the technical side of Intimate Implant. Three objects, each representing an regenerative implant. Three stories that investigate ethics, sacrifice and our relation to technology that disappears. Learn more at Symbiose Studio.
Photo by Ivar Pel
Each object carries a microcontroller that is running micropython and a speaker that allows telling stories (or by headphones). The LEDs in combination with a accelerometer creates an object that invites persons to interact with the objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dilmah Tea Europe</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/dilmah-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/dilmah-tea/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve helped Dilmah Tea with the ordering and forecasting proces.
More information soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOVN</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</guid>
      <description>Sovn (previously known as Jawsaver) creates smart earbuds to stop teeth grinding &amp;amp; clenching. Bruxism is a problem and to solve that I was asked to create several prototypes of mechanics to see what&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting strategy to develop into a product.
All prototypes where supported with a dynamic earbud platform that let&amp;rsquo;s a user test different mechanics. Arduino&amp;rsquo;s, micropython, 3D printing and rapid prototyping are things that we&amp;rsquo;re used in this development proces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitale Fitheid</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/digitale-fitheid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/digitale-fitheid/</guid>
      <description>For digital fitness (Digitale Fitheid in dutch) I&amp;rsquo;ve created a questionnaire where people can discover how well versed they are with technology and digital tools. The small test is developed in Svelte &amp;amp; run on AWS with DynamoDB / Chalice as a backend.
Curious about the test? It&amp;rsquo;s dutch only for now, but you can find it here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front404</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/front404/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/front404/</guid>
      <description>Bas van Oerle and Thomas voor &amp;rsquo;t Hekke asked me to develop a series of crystals and 3D print them for immersive theater. I&amp;rsquo;ve designed a set of 16 crystals that can be filled with LEDs for interactivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amsterdam University of Applied Science</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 11:55:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>For the Amsterdam University of Applied Science I&amp;rsquo;ve build an application that let&amp;rsquo;s people discover &amp;amp; connect with Talent initiatives within the Amsterdam Metropolitan Region. The goal of the application is to bridge the gap between organisations and talent initiatives.
The entire stack of the web application is based on modern technology &amp;amp; build entirely with javascript. The backend is done with Strapi and the frontend run with Sapper &amp;amp; Svelte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EsperantoXL</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/esperantoxl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 10:15:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/esperantoxl/</guid>
      <description>For EsperantoXL I make custom solutions to extend the possibilities of no-code applications with the help of Serverless &amp;amp; computing providers like AWS &amp;amp; Azure.
This solution allows for processing million lines of codes in a unsupported datafile, analyze &amp;amp; run queries on it and return it through a callback towards the no-code platform once again. Most of the implementations are based on Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</guid>
      <description>For Dropper I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented improvements for their Django application. Dropper was a startup that was into last-mile delivery. Optimization where mostly on the performance side of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vogsy</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/vogsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:19:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/vogsy/</guid>
      <description>For Vogsy I developed several intergrations in CRMs (Hubspot, Salesforce &amp;amp; Copper) and financial applications (Quickbooks, Exact &amp;amp; Xero). I also provided a base for a Zapier application that lets users automate things together with Vogsy.
All API integrations where build with Python on App Engine. For each integration a seperate integration layer is build with full test-coverage. The architecture is based on Domain Driven Design (DDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wafl</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/wafl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:13:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/wafl/</guid>
      <description>For Maurice van Dinther and Wafl.nu I developed several questionnaire tools, this allowed him to get more clients or create something that his clients could use. All of those tools were build with Svelte. If a backend was required it was build with Chalice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nolostcapital</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</guid>
      <description>For Nolostcapital I build a tool that lets them put out questionnaires for specific goals towards well-being and HR. The tool offers direct insights from all the results from those questionnaires, enabling organizations to quickly act.
The backend service was done in python &amp;amp; Django and the front-end in Vue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundsup</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:15:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</guid>
      <description>To enable target marketing towards startups and investors alike, I helped Fundsup create a single database for campaigns and meta-data for their platform. The main technology of this stack was python &amp;amp; Django for the backend and the API and Vue for the front-end. The database was PostGres with JSON fields allowing for querying non-schema based fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watermelon</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</guid>
      <description>In two weeks I created the first REST API for a chatbot service that Watermelon is offering to their clients.
Once I got started I also converted their current stack to support Docker &amp;amp; implemented an auth gateway that would take in older auth flows and support better authentication for the API. The API was build in python &amp;amp; Django with Django Rest Framework (DRF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colliers</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</guid>
      <description>Together with Colliers we created the Quantified Workplace, an experiment in which we tracked physical activity, heart-rate, computer usage, productivity and personal scores troughout the day. This data was collected in a dashboard that would enable employees to discover insights about their health and well-being during the workday.
During the entire year of tracking Phoebe V. Moore as researcher investigated the impact of the platform.
As for the technology stack, custom API&amp;rsquo;s for interfacing with different trackers were all built with Python and the main dashboard is based on Django.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Koninkrijksrelaties</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/bzk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:25:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/bzk/</guid>
      <description>Based on LinkedIn data, I created insights for The Ministry of the Interior. Each year over 200 trainees are joining the government and their skills can be employed more wisely and based on interest next to experience from the traineeship itself.
My work consisted out of gathering the data, visualisation and future strategy on how to match talent within the government. Most work is done in Python and Jupyter notebooks as the technology stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustrans</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/sustrans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 19:01:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/sustrans/</guid>
      <description>For Sustrans in the United Kingdom I made a custom dashboard that allows people to gain insights into their own mobility based on the Moves app (sadly, now deprecated!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SETUP - Utrecht</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 19:01:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/setup/</guid>
      <description>For SETUP I contributed on several projects by building prototypes on the topics on ethics, privacy and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-up</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/partup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 22:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/partup/</guid>
      <description>Data strategy &amp;amp; API</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
