<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3D printing on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3D printing on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in previous posts, a wearable keyboard is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an ARM Terminal</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 15:41:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</guid>
      <description>For long I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by future interfaces commonly seen in science fiction movies and other things like comics or concept art. I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the Cyberdeck reddit for some time and when I came accross the ARM Terminal by Back7 I knew I had to build one..
Fast forward a few months and one 3D printer later, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to print most of the parts (For smaller printers like the Prusa Mini I have it&amp;rsquo;s better to split the bigger parts and glue them together later with superglue).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making and Fixing Things</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 21:25:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</guid>
      <description>I bougth a 3D printer together with my brother. It&amp;rsquo;s not new technology, but it&amp;rsquo;s at a place where it&amp;rsquo;s solid and developed enough that I chose to buy one. That way I can spend my time with one as efficiently as possible, while developing new skills!
As for what you can do with it? Fixing stuff for example, a custom bracket that broke in one of my kitchen appliances is now easily fixable by measuring the broken part en replicating it in 3D software like Fusion360.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
