<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3d Printing on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3d Printing on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;a wearable keyboard&lt;/em&gt; is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look at other devices like the Keyer or the &lt;code&gt;asetniop&lt;/code&gt; keyboard, I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my focus to develop a wearable keyboard with real keys. As the feedback of pressing a button is quite nice to have, especially when dealing with chording or any form of stenography. The first thing I did was to create a form of my palm &amp;amp; wrist with polymorph, a plastic that allows for easy formation when warm and hardening when cooling down. This form would be the basis for the first prototypes. While testing the ergonomics turned out be be hard, as curled fingers all the time is quite stressfull for the muscles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an ARM Terminal</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 15:41:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For long I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by future interfaces commonly seen in science fiction movies and other things like comics or concept art. I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/cyberDeck/&#34;&gt;Cyberdeck reddit&lt;/a&gt; for some time and when I came accross the &lt;a href=&#34;https://back7.co/home/arm-terminal&#34;&gt;ARM Terminal by Back7&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to build one..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few months and one 3D printer later, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to print most of the parts &lt;em&gt;(For smaller printers like the Prusa Mini I have it&amp;rsquo;s better to split the bigger parts and glue them together later with superglue)&lt;/em&gt;. After the shipment of parts &amp;amp; screen came in, I started the assembly and it currently looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making and Fixing Things</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 21:25:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bougth a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;3D printer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; together with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;my brother&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not new technology, but it&amp;rsquo;s at a place where it&amp;rsquo;s solid and developed enough that I chose to buy one. That way I can spend my time with one as efficiently as possible, while developing new skills!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for what you can do with it? Fixing stuff for example, a custom bracket that broke in one of my kitchen appliances is now easily fixable by measuring the broken part en replicating it in 3D software like &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Fusion360&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
