<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fitbit on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/fitbit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fitbit on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 18:54:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/fitbit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fitbit organisation dashboard</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 18:54:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>The Fitbit (affiliate link) is one of the best tools for activity tracking.The interface is nice and the hardware is durable and syncs wirelessly. For a personal level is good, but using group-wise or equipping all employees with a Fitbit turns out to be non-existent.
During the past few days I&#39;ve spend some time building a dashboard that lets people see the data from all users within a group. It gets all data trough the Fitbit API and summarizes it into a view per day/week/month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing personal caloric values</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 09:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve started tracking my food intake with Foodzy about 13 days ago. And while doing that I already came across some interesting things. I&#39;ve never been fully tracking my food intake, but the Foodzy app on my iPhone with extensive database (including typical dutch food) makes it quite easy. I&#39;ve been tracking for thirteen days now.
The first step I wanted to take is to generate a baseline of my typical food consumption(and thus caloric values), this way I can see where I can make improvements and measure the changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python library for the FitBit API</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:50:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</guid>
      <description>My quest of building API wrappers in python continues with the FitBit. The handy devices tracks most of my activities and movements during daytime. So it&#39;s an excellent self-tracking device, especially with the wireless sync. There wasn&#39;t an API interface available in python, so with some borrowed code I decided to build my own.
I made an GitHub repository with the code and an example for you to use. Please fork and correct any changes that you think would be useful for me to learn!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>