<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the Intelligence Room</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months I&#39;ve been steadily involved with a project that aims to recreate an war/control/intelligence room that you see in movies. The one difference is that the room is ment for decision-makers within bigger companies. Often, urgent en relevant questions go unanswered, but the Intelligence Room helps fixing this.
During the Big Improvement Day we showcased our concept and I&#39;ve created a little Django app that matches all attendees based on topics they provided when signing up for the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metabiography, written in the cloud</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 22:04:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Last month, most of my time was spend on a project for Yuri Veerman &amp;amp; Elsbeth Fraanje, who are part of the Quantified Reality project by het Mediafonds &amp;amp; the Sandberg Institute. Elsbeth and Yuri are exploring the possiblities of (auto)generating a biography from somebody&#39;s meta-data and created the the aptly named Metabiography.
I was asked by Yuri &amp;amp; Elsbeth to build a working prototype For now, it&#39;s in pre-beta phase, but below is a screenshot how it could look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned building Django projects</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-09-lessons-learned-building-django-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 23:39:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-09-lessons-learned-building-django-projects/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been using Django as my go-to framework for the past few months. So far I&#39;ve enjoyed the ride, but have learned some things that I&#39;d like to share with you:
 During project setup, create a virtual environment for yourself to work in. Use the &#39;pip freeze&#39; for creating a requirements.txt that helps you manage dependencies. Don&#39;t use any paths within the views. Instead, use the reverse function for looking up routes that correspond to the url.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>