<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 22:00:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KSU</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/ksu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/ksu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the KSU I build a custom questionnaire tool that runs on Django leverages SSO for ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dropper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Dropper I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented improvements for their &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; application. Dropper was a startup that was into last-mile delivery. Optimization where mostly on the performance side of things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organization.supply</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/organization-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/organization-supply/</guid>
      <description>An inventory management tool build with Python &amp;amp; Django</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nolostcapital</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/business/people/academic/phoebe-moore&#34;&gt;Nolostcapital&lt;/a&gt; I build a tool that lets them put out questionnaires for specific goals towards well-being and HR. The tool offers direct insights from all the results from those questionnaires, enabling organizations to quickly act.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The backend service was done in &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; and the front-end in &lt;em&gt;Vue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundsup</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:15:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To enable target marketing towards startups and investors alike, I helped Fundsup create a single database for campaigns and meta-data for their platform. The main technology of this stack was &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; for the backend and the API and &lt;em&gt;Vue&lt;/em&gt; for the front-end. The database was PostGres with JSON fields allowing for querying non-schema based fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watermelon</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In two weeks I created the first REST API for a chatbot service that Watermelon is offering to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I got started I also converted their current stack to support Docker &amp;amp; implemented an auth gateway that would take in older auth flows and support better authentication for the API. The API was build in &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; with Django Rest Framework (DRF)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colliers</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with Colliers we created the Quantified Workplace, an experiment in which we tracked physical activity, heart-rate, computer usage, productivity and personal scores troughout the day. This data was collected in a dashboard that would enable employees to discover insights about their health and well-being during the workday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the entire year of tracking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/business/people/academic/phoebe-moore&#34;&gt;Phoebe V. Moore&lt;/a&gt; as researcher investigated the impact of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the technology stack, custom API&amp;rsquo;s for interfacing with different trackers were all built with &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; and the main dashboard is based on &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
