<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 10:33:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On solving annoying things</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-29-on-solving-annoying-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 10:33:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-29-on-solving-annoying-things/</guid>
      <description>The dutch government and other (bigger) organisations seem to have a habit to annoy people. One of the reasons they do so is security by obscurity. It has it’s flaw as shown in this blogpost by @levelsio.
He wrote a little script that fetches and forwards all the email, which everyone can do after loggin in with DigiD. As shown, this takes a lot of steps. Automating it can be done with less then 50 lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printing lampshades or any object based on data.</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-12-14-3d-printing-objects-and-lampshades-based-on-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 23:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-12-14-3d-printing-objects-and-lampshades-based-on-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I stayed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://herman.kopinga.nl/&#34;&gt;Herman&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; place for a couple of days. While there we primarily discussed buttons, 3D printers and other nerdy stuff. As it happend I&#39;d look over on his desk and found some test prints for lampshades made of ABS. That got me thinking.. Just a few hours later I was knees deep in code trying to generate something that would look like a 3D model: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/Screen-Shot-2014-12-12-at-11.56.18-AM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3153&#34; src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/Screen-Shot-2014-12-12-at-11.56.18-AM-1024x655.png&#34; alt=&#34;A 3D model in Openscad&#34; width=&#34;620&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Moves data for?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:29:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</guid>
      <description>In July I wrote a little wrapper for the Moves App API. But I didn&#39;t develop the ideas I had for it any further due to time constraints. But other projects got me into it and I wanted to share what I&#39;m currently building. I&#39;ve drawn the same concept of a fitbit dashboard over to a Moves Dashboard, so we can use the same data. And I&#39;ve got some friends who come up with great ideas too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jawbone API Python library</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:15:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been wearing a Jawbone UP for the last few months. There are things I like about it, the app, the sleep interface and the options you have for notifications. Some other things I dislike, the 3.5mm jack for syncing for example... It&#39;s annoying. They have it solved with the next version though.

As with all the other devices that I&#39;ve been wearing I wanted to get the data out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of your phone invoices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-21-making-sense-of-your-phone-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 10:02:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-21-making-sense-of-your-phone-invoices/</guid>
      <description>Telephone companies tend to have a lot of data about a user. This data includes some information that could help you decide whether you could pay for another subscription that fits more to your usage. To fix that problem I&#39;ve build a dashboard which uses all the information available trough the invoices my current company (T-mobile) provides in a PDF. (FYI, I got a version running that&#39;s also working with receipts from Vodafone)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A python library for the Moves App API</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 19:52:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</guid>
      <description>For Quantified Self starters I recommend the really nice Moves App. The interface is really nice and the battery drain isn&#39;t that bad if you recharge it twice a day. They recently opened up their API enabling developers like me to create apps based on their platform. For me the first step towards creating an app is a easier way to communicate with the API.
As with the fitbit, I&#39;ve written a open-source library for you to use!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infographic van OV-chipkaart data</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-01-infographic-ov-chipkaart-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:06:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-01-infographic-ov-chipkaart-data/</guid>
      <description>Ik heb al eerder met de export data van de OV-chipkaart iets gemaakt. Vroeger kon je de locaties van alle stations (inclusief steden en straten) exporteren. Tegenwoordig kan dat niet meer, dus werkte mijn gebouwde app niet meer. De kaart bevat echter teveel waardevolle data die als die op de juiste manier kan worden gerepresenteerd voor inzicht kan zorgen in je gebruik:
 Heb jij een idee op welke dagen je het meeste reist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python library for the FitBit API</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:50:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</guid>
      <description>My quest of building API wrappers in python continues with the FitBit. The handy devices tracks most of my activities and movements during daytime. So it&#39;s an excellent self-tracking device, especially with the wireless sync. There wasn&#39;t an API interface available in python, so with some borrowed code I decided to build my own.
I made an GitHub repository with the code and an example for you to use. Please fork and correct any changes that you think would be useful for me to learn!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync Kindle notes and clippings to Evernote</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-08-kindle-notes-evernote-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 12:11:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-08-kindle-notes-evernote-sync/</guid>
      <description>Since I got my Kindle I started reading a lot more books and articles. And one of the nice things you can do is add notes and clip certain pieces of text. The Kindle saves all those things into a text file for easy access, but I wanted those to be searchable as well in my system.
I wrote a small python script that extracts all notes and clippings from the text file and creates a new note in Evernote for each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My effort for a better readinglist</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-05-08-my-effort-for-a-better-readinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 10:24:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-05-08-my-effort-for-a-better-readinglist/</guid>
      <description>I love the Read It Later List service. Each day I save about 20-30 articles from Google Reader or my Twitter client so I can read them later. However, these amounts make it hard for me to process all the things I save. That&#39;s why I need a readinglist that has additional filtering/speed/shortcuts.
As my endeavors with Python continue, for the last few months I&#39;ve been developing my own version of the perfect readinglist build upon the API of Read It Later List.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring mouse interaction</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 22:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</guid>
      <description>I am an avid user of shortcuts and like to improve my workflow and I would like to discover hidden patterns. This is what happens next. When I bought my Mac 2 months ago I dumped my mouse in favor of the trackpad. Did this influence my mouse/trackpad interaction? Sadly I can&#39;t draw any conclusions about it because I switched my operating system too!
However more recently I started using MacLogger and together with Jelle I&#39;ve made some custom python and processing scripts that should offer more insight into my mouse usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoTracking: streaming GPS locations</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 21:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am trying to publish my blogposts in English to reach a wider public. However since English is my second language please forgive me my spelling errors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reading about self-tracking I was fascinated by GPS location and geospatial analysis. As it turns out …. experiments had been done before and I wanted to experience what you could do with the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/8545134&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wondered if it were possible for me recreate this, using my less then basic programming skills and no more utilities then my iPhone. So I ventured into python and after reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://eric-blue.com/2010/08/28/geolocation-gps-and-self-tracking/&#34;&gt;Eric Blue’s blog&lt;/a&gt; I came up with a solution.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>