<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe Conference</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 11:42:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve spend past weekend enjoying what I do most, submerge in a community driven event, to come out two days later sleep deprived but full with ideas and enthusiasm. As one of the organisers of the conference you might think that it&#39;s a though thing to do, coordinating it all, but with a wonderful group of people from america and the QS Amsterdam team it was a blast!
The atmosphere of the group was really great and we had almost 300 people at the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe 2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:02:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</guid>
      <description>In one year I started with my idea to go the the first Quantified Self Conference in San Francisco, Mountain View. The idea brought me there, with all the helping hands of people supporting me. When Martijn and me got back, we agreed to organize a second conference in Amsterdam.
The QS Amsterdam crew joined in and at the 26 &amp;amp; 27th of November we organized QS Europe. I never organized a conference so big and it was truly fantastic to see 250 people enjoying their time at the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>