<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>electronics on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/electronics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in electronics on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:06:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/electronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Opal</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/opal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:06:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/opal/</guid>
      <description>For Opal I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on hardware prototypes under NDA. I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring different protocols and low level unix interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOVN</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</guid>
      <description>Sovn (previously known as Jawsaver) creates smart earbuds to stop teeth grinding &amp;amp; clenching. Bruxism is a problem and to solve that I was asked to create several prototypes of mechanics to see what&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting strategy to develop into a product.
All prototypes where supported with a dynamic earbud platform that let&amp;rsquo;s a user test different mechanics. Arduino&amp;rsquo;s, micropython, 3D printing and rapid prototyping are things that we&amp;rsquo;re used in this development proces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VT-40 custom keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:15:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to making keyboards and while I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering with creating a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon many other builds of people that do interesting stuff.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been browsing the usual reddits (r/mk, r/ErgoMechKeyboards and the likes) I stumbled upon a nice looking project that would get me into ortholinear&amp;hellip; I wanted a keyboard different enough that it&amp;rsquo;s worth building. So I ended up with the VT-40.
My brother ordered the pcbs and components, I ordered the keycaps &amp;amp; switches since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January: Project Month</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:40:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</guid>
      <description>Before the start of this month, I made a commitment to myself to focus all of my attention to personal projects. Just in between clients I could focus purely on my own things! And when January got started, an idea started in my mind that I wanted to take 3 projects to make some progres on.
As it turned out, I worked on way more than 3 projects, still did some work for clients, but looking back at this month, I surely achieved making significant progres on at least 3 of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a bluetooth Sudoku keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 21:17:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>My girlfriend loves to solves sudoku&amp;rsquo;s and most of the time she&amp;rsquo;s doing so on her iPhone.. As a belated birthday gift I made her a custom sudoku-keyboard with just 9 keys. Who needs more if you just want to do a sudoku right?
This was a perfect opportunity for me to dive some more into hardware and especially bluetooth things&amp;hellip; The entire body is 3D printed and has threaded inserts with M3 screws and basic keycaps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
