<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 years of 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</guid>
      <description>Today marks something special. Ten years ago, inspired by Buster Benson I started taking a picture at 8:36pm every day. A simple thing you might think, but in the end I kept doing it and to this day I still do.
Keeping a habit for 10 years makes it a bit extraordinairy and I can say I will continue taking a picture! Below you will find this years movie of all the photos I took.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm, a 2014 video!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</guid>
      <description>This is my fourth year that I&#39;m taking pictures everyday at 8:36pm. A little something that I plan to keep on doing for my entire life. Every year I make a small movie off all the pictures! Have a look:

Highlights of this year including a holiday across the netherlands, moving to a new home and Italy! Hope 2015 will be as great as last year! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The curious corner on video</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 20:21:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve curated 6 editions of the Curious Corner of the Internet until this day. It started out as an experiment of just showing my saved-for-later links in a presentation. The newsletter essentially was a second format, and I didn&#39;t explore my chances for a talk much further. Until now, during the Week for the Entrepreneur in the Netherlands, that I&#39;d give it another shot. Sadly, it&#39;s in dutch, but here&#39;s the video:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RadBox for the iPad</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-08-radbox-for-the-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 12:19:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-08-radbox-for-the-ipad/</guid>
      <description>I use Read It Later for saving webpages, but if those pages contained video&#39;s I had to visit the webpages, load the video etcetera... It simply does not fulfill my needs for watching video...
While searching Google I discovered RadBox, which does exactly what I want: use a bookmarklet to save video&#39;s to watch later. They offered an API and RSS-feed of my video&#39;s so I decided to build my own based on App Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>On 20 september the first Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup took place in het volkskrantgebouw. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A full recap can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on vimeo. Sebastiaan ter Burg provided the video/photo capture and Kees Plattel made a wonderful intro! I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Minute of Fame - Stand Up Inspiration: 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-18-1-minute-of-fame-stand-up-inspiration-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 13:56:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-18-1-minute-of-fame-stand-up-inspiration-836pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://standupinspiration.com/&#34;&gt;Stand Up Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; Ideeën, gedachten en visies, gebracht door kritische en enthousiaste denkers uit verschillende werelden; inspiratie in interactie met de zaal. Dat is in een notendop #SUI. De laatste editie was gisteren op 17 mei 2010, de 16e. Deze post gaat over die daarvoor, nummer 15. Toen had ik mijn 1 minute of fame vlak na de pauze:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;object classid=&#34;clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;src&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11817627&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11817627&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kort samengevat: blubber in alle kleuren van de regenboog maar trots dat ik het gedaan heb! :D&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>