<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>QS2011 on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in QS2011 on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:02:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/tags/qs2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe 2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:02:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</guid>
      <description>In one year I started with my idea to go the the first Quantified Self Conference in San Francisco, Mountain View. The idea brought me there, with all the helping hands of people supporting me. When Martijn and me got back, we agreed to organize a second conference in Amsterdam.
The QS Amsterdam crew joined in and at the 26 &amp;amp; 27th of November we organized QS Europe. I never organized a conference so big and it was truly fantastic to see 250 people enjoying their time at the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up Inspiration: Mijn Reis naar #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:41:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>Op 19 september was ik bij Stand Up Inspiration en mocht daar mijn verhaal van mijn reis vertellen. Gelukkig is dit op video opgenomen door Daan van Bergen (Videologic). Ik startte wat zenuwachtig, maar ben wel erg blij met het resultaat:
http://vimeo.com/30073493</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of my San Francisco Report</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 10:39:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</guid>
      <description>For the people who sponsored me for my trip to San Francisco, I&#39;m building a report inspired my Nicholas Felton about my trip. I wanted to show you a small preview on the right:
I&#39;m aiming to have at least 4 page worth of data to show you. Since I&#39;ve never dived deep into Processing, the building time is somewhat extended, so I don&#39;t know when it&#39;ll be finished. I started studying Media Technology as well, so spare time is a little bit limited.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>