<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>San Francisco on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/san-francisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in San Francisco on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/san-francisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of my San Francisco Report</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 10:39:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</guid>
      <description>For the people who sponsored me for my trip to San Francisco, I&#39;m building a report inspired my Nicholas Felton about my trip. I wanted to show you a small preview on the right:
I&#39;m aiming to have at least 4 page worth of data to show you. Since I&#39;ve never dived deep into Processing, the building time is somewhat extended, so I don&#39;t know when it&#39;ll be finished. I started studying Media Technology as well, so spare time is a little bit limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.
Together with Martijn Aslander I&#39;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.
I volunteered at the the conference which brought me way more then being just there as a guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actie voor mijn reis naar San Francisco!</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-18-actie-voor-mijn-reis-naar-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 14:30:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-18-actie-voor-mijn-reis-naar-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>Het gaat keihard met mijn spaarpotje voor mijn reis naar Amerika(San Francisco), heel veel mensen hebben al geholpen door te doneren of door het verder te verspreiden. Inmiddels ben ik over de 60%, en heb ik nog twee maanden te gaan. Dat ga ik dus met deze snelheid prima redden!
Om de hele actie een boost te geven heb ik het volgende bedacht:
Ik verloot 1 middag sparren/hulp/brainstormen/(invullen) met mij over bijvoorbeeld Slimmer Werken of The Quantified Self of een ander onderwerp waarbij ik jou kan helpen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>