<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quantifiedself on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/quantifiedself/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quantifiedself on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 20:13:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/quantifiedself/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite testing with Talking20</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 20:13:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</guid>
      <description>When I arrived home this weekend, a small package was waiting for me. It included the Talking20 metabolite kit I&#39;d pre-ordered. And tonight I finally got around of donating some of my blood to the spot card. The package included, 3 spot cards and envelopes, and for each spot-card: an alcohol wipe, bandage and 3 lancets.

It&#39;s quick and easy to get started, but I also got some helpful assistance from my mother :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First nights with the Zeo sleep monitor</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:53:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</guid>
      <description>During the QS Conference the awesome guys from Zeo gifted me one of their sleep monitors. And 1 week ago it arrived by mail. I promised to create as much value in return if I liked the Zeo. And I do, I absolutely do. Here is why:
As an average person sleep 8 hours a day you spend 1/3 of your life lying in bed... That&#39;s a lot of time spend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Brussels</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 21:55:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</guid>
      <description>This week I travelled to Brussels so I could give a talk at the Quantified Self Meetup group there. And I&#39;ve been involved in the startup Scanadu which is about broadcasting your health. Together with people like Walter de Brouwer and Misha Chellam we are going to take a different approach to health. During my stay in Brussels I&#39;ve learned a lot (including my level of French, it&#39;s really bad!). Really liked the city though!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>