<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor></managingEditor>
    <copyright>Joost Plattel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:59:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making todos more magical with n8n</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2025-03-19-n8n-automation-ideas-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:59:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2025-03-19-n8n-automation-ideas-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I lack a lot of spare time (because of reasons) lately, but sometimes I have a couple of hours to tinker around with any of my projects and one of the things on my list to explore was &lt;a href=&#34;https://n8n.io/&#34;&gt;n8n&lt;/a&gt;. I set it up locally on my NAS and authenticated some services too see what I could connect together..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite fast a simple idea was formed: could I transform my todolist (in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.todoist.com/&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt;) into something magical that I wanted to instead of the slog you would normally feel when doing it. So this would be my first automation I would try and build. Lo and behold:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSU</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/ksu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/ksu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the KSU I build a custom questionnaire tool that runs on Django leverages SSO for ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ksu</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/ksu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 09:08:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/ksu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Maurice van Dinther from &lt;a href=&#34;https://wafl.nu&#34;&gt;wafl.nu&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve created a monitoring/questionnaire tool for the KSU. This allows them to gain insights into how their teams are functioning. The application is build with Django and uses &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;SSO&lt;/a&gt; to seamlessly allow users to gather data. The data is shown in dashboards with &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Chart.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Van Benthem en Keulen</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/vbk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 09:08:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/vbk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Van Benthem en Keulen I worked together with Arianove to implement a large language model chat interface that runs on Azure Static Web Applications, using their own Azure endpoint allows VBK to keep their data safely theirs. The custom front-end is made with &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Svelte 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Tailwind&lt;/a&gt;, hosted as a Static Web App (SWA) on Azure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent Acquisition Audit Institute</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/talent-acquisition-audit-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 21:41:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/talent-acquisition-audit-institute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://vandehaterd.nl/en/&#34;&gt;Bas van de Haterd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://nl.linkedin.com/in/champalgijzen&#34;&gt;Champal Gijzen&lt;/a&gt; we started the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ta-audit.com&#34;&gt;Talent Acquisition Audit Institute&lt;/a&gt; (TA Audit for short). Our goal is to create bias-free recruitment processes by auditing companies and their talent acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ta-audit.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/ta-audit-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;TA Audit Institute logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An equal opportunity for everyone to find a job regardless of age, originethnicity or gender, that is our mission. We do this by conducting independent audits and awarding the Bias Free Hiring quality mark.
There is a lot of attention to diversity and inclusion in the Recruitment and HR profession, and yet (un)conscious bias remains a major problem in selection processes. By providing insight into existing bias and its effect, we enable organizations to reduce bias and offer fair opportunities, resulting in the Bias-Free Hiring quality mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using annoyances to learn something new</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-09-19-small-annoyances-to-learn-new-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 14:31:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-09-19-small-annoyances-to-learn-new-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For me this is more of a meta post, as it&amp;rsquo;s mostly the rediscovery of a personal preference of mine. The best way to learn something for me is doing it while scrambling to figure out how it works and asking for help when stuck. As an example doing a carbage-run through England / Wales with a car I know next to nothing about and lacking understanding of how it works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opal</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/opal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:06:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/opal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://opalcamera.com/&#34;&gt;Opal&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on hardware prototypes under NDA. I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring different protocols and low level unix interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptions from Friend in Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-08-12-friend-transcriptions-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 20:55:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-08-12-friend-transcriptions-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BasedHardware/Omi&#34;&gt;Friend / Omi&lt;/a&gt; (not to be confused with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.friend.com/&#34;&gt;other one&lt;/a&gt;) for a couple of weeks. This project is interesting to me because of the open-source component and community that it has. So I made my own, including it&amp;rsquo;s own case. One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a solution for has been trying to get all transcription into my note taking program &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.com&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I figured out a way to do this. Thanks to the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://val.town&#34;&gt;val.town&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudflare.com/r2&#34;&gt;Cloudflare R2&lt;/a&gt; (or any S3 bucket compatible provider) it&amp;rsquo;s quite a chain of things, but it works! You start of with a val.town endpoint with the following code:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a small Pingo clock</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-05-25-small-pingo-clock-with-circuitpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:55:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-05-25-small-pingo-clock-with-circuitpython/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instructables.com/Pingo-Color-Clock-by-Illusionmanager/&#34;&gt;Pingo clock&lt;/a&gt; for quite some time. Finally having some time available between projects I had most components on hand. With the exception for the bigger LED rings. And I also wanted to have the clock run on Circuitpython instead of Arduino. So I designed a smaller one, with only 7 led rings instead of 9. This also allowed me to print more parts, for example the diffusion screen is printed as well as a custom USB-c charging backplate. I&amp;rsquo;ve also switched to a Raspberry Pi Pico W so I can use Circuitpython to automatically grab the time with NTP (just like the original!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy configuration for Circuit Python devices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-02-15-easy-configuration-for-circuit-python-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 20:36:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2024-02-15-easy-configuration-for-circuit-python-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While developing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/project/ov-klok/&#34;&gt;OV Klok&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring how small trinkets and other technological utilities can be configured. Most of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s either trough a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Captive_portal&#34;&gt;captive portal&lt;/a&gt;, a self-served webserver or editing a configuration file. Both options aren&amp;rsquo;t really user friendly to me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The captive portal is fails at times and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work if you have a custom network configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The self served webpage requires a user to type in an address or IP, that&amp;rsquo;s only accessible in a specific mode..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The configuration file is prone to errors and requires a user to edit a text file with an editor that they might not be comfortable with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-serial-to-the-rescue&#34;&gt;Web serial to the rescue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a simple device like the OV Klok a user only needs to configure the device once and I wanted it to be as fool proof as possible while being user-friendly too! I solved this with the power of &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Serial_API&#34;&gt;Web Serial&lt;/a&gt;. This allows a user to connect with a serial port through a webbrowser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OV Klok</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/ov-klok/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 17:09:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/ov-klok/</guid>
      <description>A small hardware project that uses and ESP32 and pressure-forming plastic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple public transport display / clock</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-12-05-simple-public-transport-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 18:16:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-12-05-simple-public-transport-display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My office is located in a different city, so I have to commute both ways.. Always taking the same initial transport from either my office or my home.. On both sides I&amp;rsquo;d love to have a simple display that shows the most recent leaving transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some tinkering I&amp;rsquo;ve cobbled together a piece of hardware (with just 10 solder joints!) and a simple API/crawler that kindly scrapes the latest public transport (with kindly I mean at most once an hour). For the sake of simplicity I chose a crawler above an API as I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time on it. Within a couple of minutes I had numbers show up on the display:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tellart</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/tellart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:06:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/tellart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tellart.com/&#34;&gt;Tellart&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tellart.com/projects/dinner-in-2050&#34;&gt;Dinner in 2050&lt;/a&gt; installation for the UAE Pavilion. For COP28 the goal of this installation is to make people think about climate change in a very personal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors would be asked to tell about their favorite dish which would then be transformed into a dish in 2050 with an ingredient swapped out that would have the most impact on climate change. Over 18.000 meals were generated by the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commandments for personal knowledge systems</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-10-25-commandments-personal-knowledge-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:07:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-10-25-commandments-personal-knowledge-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we tinker around with our personal knowledge systems (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;PKM&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) and make them more intricate and fit for our own patterns, I often tend to look back on how I did things, sometimes to leave them around unchanged.. Since every version is stored in Git, we might as well keep a history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I would start over again, I would guide myself a bit better by using a series of commandments much like religion has it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Ten_Commandments&#34;&gt;The 10 Commandments &lt;/a&gt; is a list of principles that might guide you to lead a good life. And as religion has it everyone kind of runs their own list based on a translation or interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbiose Studio</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/symbiose-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/symbiose-studio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://symbiose.studio/&#34;&gt;Bertrand from Symbiose Studio&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve build the technical side of Intimate Implant. Three objects, each representing an regenerative implant. Three stories that investigate ethics, sacrifice and our relation to technology that disappears. &lt;a href=&#34;https://symbiose.studio/projects/intimate-implant/&#34;&gt;Learn more at Symbiose Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/intimate-implant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Intimate Implant at Betweter Festival&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivarpel.nl/&#34;&gt;Ivar Pel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each object carries a microcontroller that is running &lt;code&gt;circuitpython&lt;/code&gt; and a speaker that allows telling stories (or by headphones). The LEDs in combination with a accelerometer creates an object that invites persons to interact with the objects. Closing the gap between the abdstract idea of an implant and having it inside your body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dilmah Tea Europe</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/dilmah-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/dilmah-tea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve helped &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dilmahtea.nl/&#34;&gt;Dilmah Tea&lt;/a&gt; with the ordering and forecasting proces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://files.jplattel.nl/2023/12/Am1CPA.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing SwiftUI apps With Chat-GPT</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-05-11-writing-swift-ui-mac-os-x-apps-with-chat-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 21:52:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-05-11-writing-swift-ui-mac-os-x-apps-with-chat-gpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chat.openai.com/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; is all the rage nowadays. Personally I&amp;rsquo;ve used it quite a few times and professionally as a software developer it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to use. I don&amp;rsquo;t fear for my job/knowledge (yet!) as it&amp;rsquo;s mostly integrations and not of the shelf code&amp;hellip; (I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried the hardware space in Chat GPT yet&amp;hellip;.. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.decisionproblem.com/paperclips/index2.html&#34;&gt;paperclips might be optimized&lt;/a&gt;..) ✌️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To figure out how useful it might be for me, I embarked on a journey together with ChatGPT to build a piece of software that would solve issues that I&amp;rsquo;d had with the Mac OS X Finder for a while. The shortcomings of Finder can be summed up with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wandering.computer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/wandering-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 18:04:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/wandering-computer/</guid>
      <description>A wearable keyboard made for typing on the go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finder Favorites</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/finder-favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 18:04:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/finder-favorites/</guid>
      <description>A simple app that let&amp;rsquo;s you group column views of favorite folders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 1000 Daily Notes in Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-03-27-reflecting-1000-daily-notes-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 13:46:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-03-27-reflecting-1000-daily-notes-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling for a thousand days using &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. A habit I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do for a long time. Until I found Obsidian I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it work, but it does now! In this post I wanted to reflect on my daily notes and some ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about my current daily note template, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/jplattel/2728178ea89224acff91349c97d1b29b&#34;&gt;gist on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrofitting an old iPod Mini</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-03-11-retrofitting-ipod-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 19:59:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2023-03-11-retrofitting-ipod-mini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After owning a couple of mp3 players in my youth, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the jump to an Apple device with an iPod Mini as my music player. Sadly, it&amp;rsquo;s in no working condition anymore I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s possible to replace the entire inside, but it&amp;rsquo;s more fun to do something else with it. Thus and idea was born that didn&amp;rsquo;t come into fruition until a couple of days ago when I had some time available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOVN</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/sovn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getsovn.com/&#34;&gt;Sovn&lt;/a&gt; (previously known as Jawsaver) creates smart earbuds to stop teeth grinding &amp;amp; clenching. Bruxism is a problem and to solve that I was asked to create several prototypes of mechanics to see what&amp;rsquo;s the most interesting strategy to develop into a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All prototypes where supported with a dynamic earbud platform that let&amp;rsquo;s a user test different mechanics. Arduino&amp;rsquo;s, micropython, 3D printing and rapid prototyping are things that we&amp;rsquo;re used in this development proces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Workflows for Calibre</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-12-18-reading-workflows-calibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 18:45:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-12-18-reading-workflows-calibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading books on my Kindle for a years and I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had a pretty workflow for it, all the books just simply end up in Calibre and I manually sync my library with the device itself. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve spend some time automating the process a bit and I wanted to share that with you! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using plugins that solve things for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?t=123281&#34;&gt;Goodreads Sync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you mark a book as read on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/4883795-joost-plattel&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; the &amp;lsquo;Date Read&amp;rsquo; column is automatically updated with todays date. Which is pretty awesome, since it saves me updating the date seperately. It will also move it to the &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; bookshelf on Goodreads, which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A history and list of wearable keyboards</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-08-02-a-brief-history-of-wearable-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 15:41:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-08-02-a-brief-history-of-wearable-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While exploring the internet for inspiration and ideas around a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve come across multiple sites, persons and ideas. It seems there&amp;rsquo;s not really a good index or overview of the history on wearable keyboards. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make one myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This overview might not be complete, if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking I&amp;rsquo;m missing a crucial part, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/contact/&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; or open a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/jplattel.nl&#34;&gt;Github issue&lt;/a&gt;!. Some links might have alternatives or other, but I chose to keep the main influences in this list only!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on wandering.computer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-07-24-progress-wearable-keyboard-wandering-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:04:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-07-24-progress-wearable-keyboard-wandering-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely I&amp;rsquo;m making progress on my personal project. Creating a wearable keyboard that can be used while walking has been a dream of mine for a couple of years. One of the decision I made upfront is that I makes no sense to rush this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason is that most of the stuff I create these days either have to be brought to market as soon as possible (by yesterday please!). The other reason is that cutting corners for such a unique problem I try to solve results into missing certain details or solutions that might not be obvious at first sight. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this is going to be a product, I do try to learn on how to design for manufacturing. Thanks to the wonderful folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://dato.mu/&#34;&gt;Dato&lt;/a&gt; as sparring partners. There&amp;rsquo;s just soo much to learn when developing something from scratch with no previous examples or solutions available&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Mainsail With Zerotier</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-05-16-configuring-mainsail-with-zerotier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:18:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-05-16-configuring-mainsail-with-zerotier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blogpost mostly functions as a reminder to myself on how to configure &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.mainsail.xyz/&#34;&gt;Mainsail&lt;/a&gt; to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;Zerotier&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with any of the two, the first one is a operating system made for running a 3D printer and the second one allows for a network layer for personal computing, connecting devices over SD-WAN &amp;amp; VPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was running Octoprint for a while, but after a tip by David from &lt;a href=&#34;https://dato.mu/&#34;&gt;Dato&lt;/a&gt; I went on to explore Mainsail. Mainsail is a better way to run your printer, and it&amp;rsquo;s way faster then Octoprint. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve been running it for a week and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy about it! The only thing that was missing was the remote connection I had with Octoprint, made possible by Zerotier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2021</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-20-836pm-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:36:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-20-836pm-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long overdue, and it&amp;rsquo;s missing more photos then I&amp;rsquo;d like, here&amp;rsquo;s the 8:36pm video of 2021! Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quintenswagerman.nl/&#34;&gt;Quinten Swagerman&lt;/a&gt; with helping out making it into a video! (Switching to a new mac broke the old After Effects I was still using&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/701275241&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto another year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating VT-40 custom keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:15:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-04-15-vt-40-custom-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/&#34;&gt;making keyboards&lt;/a&gt; and while I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering with creating a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wandering.computer/&#34;&gt;wearable keyboard&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon many other builds of people that do interesting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been browsing the usual reddits (&lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/mechanicalKeyboards/&#34;&gt;r/mk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ErgoMechKeyboards/&#34;&gt;r/ErgoMechKeyboards&lt;/a&gt; and the likes) I stumbled upon a nice looking project that would get me into ortholinear&amp;hellip; I wanted a keyboard different enough that it&amp;rsquo;s worth building. So I ended up with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vladantrhlik/VT-40/&#34;&gt;VT-40&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ikbenke.es/&#34;&gt;My brother&lt;/a&gt; ordered the pcbs and components, I ordered the keycaps &amp;amp; switches since. With a few weeks passing and a couple of hours soldering stuff together, here&amp;rsquo;s the end result:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; ideas on storage systems</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-03-16-storage-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 20:42:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2022-03-16-storage-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As most of my posts, the main reason I write them is to share some thoughts on recent things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. This one is also one of them, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been cleaning up, moving and mostly re-organizing my stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s all about storage and that might seem a bit boring and at times it is. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason for me to write about this as I&amp;rsquo;ve got some things that I do that might be benificial for any of you!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitale Fitheid</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/digitale-fitheid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/digitale-fitheid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For digital fitness (Digitale Fitheid in dutch) I&amp;rsquo;ve created a questionnaire where people can discover how well versed they are with technology and digital tools. The small test is developed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://svelte.dev/&#34;&gt;Svelte&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; run on AWS with &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/&#34;&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/chalice/index.html&#34;&gt;Chalice&lt;/a&gt; as a backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://files.jplattel.nl/2022/08/SCR-20220809-nuy.png&#34; alt=&#34;Digitale Fitheid zelftest&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious about the test? It&amp;rsquo;s dutch only for now, but you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://zelftest.digitalefitheid.nl/&#34;&gt;find it here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping an unread list</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-12-30-keeping-an-unread-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 11:31:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-12-30-keeping-an-unread-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all the things I organize, inbox zero might just be one of the biggest achievements. Frequently less then 5 emails are in my inbox and every day I work, the todo-list shrinks. But there&amp;rsquo;s one list that keeps on growing, and that&amp;rsquo;s my read it later list in &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting stuff I read and find on the internet. Mostly due to my newsletter, &lt;a href=&#34;https://curiouscorner.nl/&#34;&gt;The Curious Corner of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;, but also to keep a list of things to inspire me and discover again at a later stage&amp;hellip; For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to empty out that list during a holiday, but I never managed to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Taxonomy (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-12-personal-taxonomy-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 10:28:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-12-personal-taxonomy-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous part I highlighted &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/&#34;&gt;how I managed my notes&lt;/a&gt; in folders. In this part I would like to explain a bit more on how make the decision between tags &amp;amp; a linked note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people unfamiliar with the difference, this is a &lt;code&gt;#tag&lt;/code&gt; and a bi-directional linked notes works like so: &lt;code&gt;[[Note Title]]&lt;/code&gt;. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s implemented in &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. It might be different in other tools, but the ideas can stay the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Taxonomy (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 10:07:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-11-10-personal-taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While explaining and introducing &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; to people I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the free form way of setup allows for so much flexibility. This results in an big amount of questions on how you would structure the links, tags and your vault. And while there are some solutions like PARA or LYT, I think the best system is the one you create yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons is that you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about how you think about the data relevant to you. This in turn forces you to think about how you structure the notes around it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for single purpose tools in these digital times</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-09-23-single-purpose-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 14:58:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-09-23-single-purpose-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this age of digital tools I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if we really need the computer or phone to be the one tool that does it all. You see, specialized tools have been of all times,
but we try to develop a smartphone that can do more and more, but if it tries to do everything it most likely will fail to do anything good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a carpenter bring only one tool to the job, you;ll need a drill, hammer and other specialized tools to do the work you want to do.
In some ways we can apply this to our digital work as well. Yes we can write on our computer, but if you&amp;rsquo;re not distracted, the amount of styling options only keeps you from writing
what you really want to. Have you tried reading a long blogpost on your computer? Interrupted with ads, notifications about a new email, thoroughly tracked on your reading habits, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure if the computer is really helping out here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ical2roam</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/ical2roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 18:42:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/ical2roam/</guid>
      <description>A small little web-application that lets you import iCal exports to Roam Research</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does muscle memory have a spatial or orientation component?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-08-31-muscle-memory-spatial-orientation-component/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 09:06:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-08-31-muscle-memory-spatial-orientation-component/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning to type again with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-07-03-learning-to-write-new-keyboard-layout/&#34;&gt;my keyboard&lt;/a&gt; I think I&amp;rsquo;ve gained quite a few insights on muscle memory. The event of sitting behind a keyboard again after a month of being on a holiday and getting right back into typing has been fascinating me time and time again. However while learning to type with my wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the orientation of the hands or the spatial component is often a determinant for muscle memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to work with a new keyboard &amp; layout</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-07-03-learning-to-write-new-keyboard-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 22:53:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-07-03-learning-to-write-new-keyboard-layout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/&#34;&gt;the wearable keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, one of the biggest fears I had was about the learning-curve. Most people will ask about it once they grok the chording keyboard, but I found myself unable to answer on how hard it would be to learn..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17841832&#34;&gt;loads of people searching on the web for the best ways to learn&lt;/a&gt; a new keyboard layout, most of the time swichting away from &lt;code&gt;qwerty&lt;/code&gt; to another layout like Dvorak or Workman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front404</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/front404/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/front404/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://front404.com/&#34;&gt;Bas van Oerle and Thomas voor &amp;rsquo;t Hekke&lt;/a&gt; asked me to develop a series of crystals and 3D print them for immersive theater. I&amp;rsquo;ve designed a set of 16 crystals that can be filled with LEDs for interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/crystals-front404.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A crystal being printed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software architecture for a wearable computer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-06-10-software-for-a-wearable-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:11:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-06-10-software-for-a-wearable-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can read &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/&#34;&gt;in previous posts&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve spend the last year designing a wearable keyboard that would allow you to type while walking. When I finally soldered everything, checked the connections for no shorts I tried flashing &lt;a href=&#34;https://micropython.org/&#34;&gt;micropython&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;code&gt;Wemo D32 Pro&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s that I use one didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work.. Luckily I had a replacement on hand &lt;em&gt;(learned that the hard-way, I&amp;rsquo;ll always be ordering extra now!)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I want to dive into the software architecture, I wanted to explain why I don&amp;rsquo;t went with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qmk/qmk_firmware/&#34;&gt;QMK&lt;/a&gt; or at least, not directly (more on that later!). While QMK is an awesome piece of software I wanted a bit more flexibility for my project. Interfacing with a SD, running a webserver and such are not things that QMK is meant for. I also wanted to explore Micropython a bit more in depth, since I&amp;rsquo;ve only done small projects with it. So, that&amp;rsquo;s the way to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amsterdam University of Applied Science</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 11:55:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amsterdamuas.com/&#34;&gt;Amsterdam University of Applied Science&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve build an application that let&amp;rsquo;s people discover &amp;amp; connect with Talent initiatives within the Amsterdam Metropolitan Region. The goal of the application is to bridge the gap between organisations and talent initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://files.jplattel.nl/2021/11/91e1ec44012eb8ca6a7d37eee26343c3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire stack of the web application is based on modern technology &amp;amp; build entirely with &lt;em&gt;javascript&lt;/em&gt;. The backend is done with &lt;a href=&#34;https://strapi.io/&#34;&gt;Strapi&lt;/a&gt; and the frontend run with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sapper.svelte.dev/&#34;&gt;Sapper&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://svelte.dev/&#34;&gt;Svelte&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhizomatic notetaking</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 08:15:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-05-04-rhizomatic-notetaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the philosophy of Deleuze &amp;amp; Guattari in which I focus mostly on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Rhizome_(philosophy)&#34;&gt;rhizome&lt;/a&gt;. As the rhizome doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a start or end, grows from within itself and into multiple directions I saw similarities on how I started to take more notes recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my own &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-10-09-obsidian-clipper-chrome-extension/&#34;&gt;Obsidian Clipper&lt;/a&gt; chrome extension to clip short amounts of text and those are automatically tagged with &lt;code&gt;🌱&lt;/code&gt;. Next I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/&#34;&gt;Obsidian Query Language&lt;/a&gt; block that&amp;rsquo;s set up to track the last few seedling notes that I&amp;rsquo;ve created:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finalizing the hardware for a wearable keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 21:01:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-04-19-finalizing-hardware-for-a-wearable-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/&#34;&gt;a previous post&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve shown physical prototypes of a wearable keyboard I&amp;rsquo;m developing. The goal of this keyboard is to provide me with a way to type while walking or just standing/sitting somewhere. I want to blind-type notes while keeping my attention at other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the comments I get have to do with &lt;em&gt;why I don&amp;rsquo;t use dictation.&lt;/em&gt; There are several reasons for that, namely I&amp;rsquo;m taking my notes bilingual (English &amp;amp; Dutch) and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to shout around my ideas while being nearby other people, as this might be annoying or even rude&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the ANT PCB Maker head</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-03-07-improving-the-ant-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 20:12:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-03-07-improving-the-ant-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-05-02-ant-pcb-maker/&#34;&gt;ANT PCB Maker&lt;/a&gt; for some time now. I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite a few problems with gcode controller that suddenly stops working and the controller has been in a plastic box without enough space for easy modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the last one I devised a plan together with my brother to create a additional space below the CNC itself. There&amp;rsquo;s more then enough room and with a piano hinge everything is easily accessible! So that&amp;rsquo;s the easy upgrade. The other problem was the overheating Z-axis motor. I wanted to switch to a NEMA-11 stepper driver but to do so required me to design a new head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspaces instead of applications</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-02-12-workspaces-instead-of-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 21:55:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-02-12-workspaces-instead-of-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As most of my work I do lives on my computer one of the main things I do is switch applications. When referencing something on the internet and applying it in a editor or copy-pasting an address from a contact to google maps search, most of it is done while switching applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some switches the friction is reduced, for example lookups through Alfred.app or pretty printing some JSON with &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. But oftentimes I find myself lost when I tab wrong once or I end up in a random tab of Chrome that was last open. There are switching costs here and the last month I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking on how this might evolve in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January: Project Month</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:40:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-31-closing-january/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before the start of this month, I made a commitment to myself to focus all of my attention to personal projects. Just in between clients I could focus purely on my own things! And when January got started, an idea started in my mind that I wanted to take 3 projects to make some progres on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, I worked on way more than 3 projects, still did some work for clients, but looking back at this month, I surely achieved making significant progres on at least 3 of my projects. And I&amp;rsquo;ve even been &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/&#34;&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; them for sure! I want to highlight the 5 biggest things I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Query Language plugin published</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-28-obsidian-query-plugin-published/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just published my first plugin for &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;! As a &lt;strong&gt;huge fan&lt;/strong&gt; of the software the possibility of writing your own plugins to work with the data you create is just awesome! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Obsidian for over 8 months now and one of the first things I created was &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/project/obsidian-clipper/&#34;&gt;the clipper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a few months Obsidian now allows users to write plugins in Typescript. While I&amp;rsquo;m not that versed in the &lt;em&gt;Typescript/Javascript&lt;/em&gt; verse I did manage to write my first plugin! (well, technically not the first, but the only one published!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable keyboard prototypes</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-20-wearable-keyboard-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;a wearable keyboard&lt;/em&gt; is one of my main projects this month. In this post I want to show you some pictures of the first prototypes and tell you a bit more about the proces of designing a keyboard. Remember I&amp;rsquo;ve got really no experience on ergonomics or knowledge about user-interface, I mostly go by feel here as it&amp;rsquo;s a highly personalized product (for now!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at other devices like the Keyer or the &lt;code&gt;asetniop&lt;/code&gt; keyboard, I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my focus to develop a wearable keyboard with real keys. As the feedback of pressing a button is quite nice to have, especially when dealing with chording or any form of stenography. The first thing I did was to create a form of my palm &amp;amp; wrist with polymorph, a plastic that allows for easy formation when warm and hardening when cooling down. This form would be the basis for the first prototypes. While testing the ergonomics turned out be be hard, as curled fingers all the time is quite stressfull for the muscles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandwith problems with Human Computer Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 11:03:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-14-bandwith-problems-human-computer-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the bandwidth problem we face with computer interaces. When typing with a keyboard or dictating trough speech, the computer cannot keep up with a stream of thoughts. Our bandwidth is limited by our output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more future forwards solutions is &lt;a href=&#34;https://neuralink.com/&#34;&gt;Neuralink&lt;/a&gt;, but to me it seems like quite an invasive solution, not without any risks..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times we may find solutions for this in a different space, in this case, a pointer can be found in the legal system. During a lawsuit a minute taker (sometimes even multiple) is the person who tries to log all the speech done by any of the parties present. The typing speed required for this is immense and one of the solutions is combining shorthand or stenography with a chorded keyboard. This results in a higher output speed allowing the minute taker to keep up with the tempo of speech.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring wearable input devices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 08:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-11-wearable-input-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the internet for input devices. From keyboards to voice or gestured controlled ways &lt;em&gt;to get thoughts out of my head as fast/good as it can be possible&lt;/em&gt;. I wanted to dive deeper into why this is important to me and why I&amp;rsquo;m interested in this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally pen &amp;amp; paper was the solution that was flexible enough. But it lacked the searchability and ways of exploring it on different tangents. Right now we&amp;rsquo;re mostly digital and rely on our keyboards to create mainly text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2020 &amp; Planning January</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-06-2020-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 15:18:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2021-01-06-2020-836pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As 2020 is over and 2021 is just beginning I once return to the yearly habits that I&amp;rsquo;ve grown into doing. One of them is completing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://yearcompass.com/&#34;&gt;Year Compass&lt;/a&gt; together with my girlfriend. To other was stuck for a while to the fact that OS X Catalina only supports 64 bit applications, which sucks if you run an outdated version of After Effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to ask my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;brother&lt;/a&gt; to render the yearly movie of all my 8:36pm photos and thankfully he did, so without further ado, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a bluetooth Sudoku keyboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 21:17:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-11-11-bluetooth-sudoku-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend loves to solves &lt;em&gt;sudoku&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s and most of the time she&amp;rsquo;s doing so on her iPhone.. As a belated birthday gift I made her a custom sudoku-keyboard with just &lt;strong&gt;9 keys&lt;/strong&gt;. Who needs more if you just want to do a sudoku right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a perfect opportunity for me to dive some more into hardware and especially bluetooth things&amp;hellip; The entire body is 3D printed and has threaded inserts with M3 screws and basic keycaps. After prototyping the electronics I soldered the keycaps together and tadaa:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian Clipper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/obsidian-clipper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:23:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/obsidian-clipper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an unofficial clipper for &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to easily clip a selection to a note in Obsidian. More information can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/obsidian-clipper&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-10-09-obsidian-clipper-chrome-extension/&#34;&gt;this blogpost&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RPV_UwWLtU_EZ14u8wtTdiSPtEDJV6xHLU1u2rkGOJmPEJGDLLni1yZQ1EV18NQgDvuLMZyQAmUeGQw6S3PVB5g9=w640-h400-e365-rj-sc0x00ffffff&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Obsidian Clipper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-10-09-obsidian-clipper-chrome-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:08:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-10-09-obsidian-clipper-chrome-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might have distilled from previous post I am an avid user of &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. The application is under heavy development and their plugin API is not ready yet. Not wanting to wait, I set out to develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/&#34;&gt;some scripts&lt;/a&gt;. In this post I wanted to share my latest project on an idea that is strongly connected to this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I used Evernote and often I would clip things from the web. With Obsidian this wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://quotebacks.net/&#34;&gt;Quotebacks&lt;/a&gt; for getting clips into markdown and pasting them into Obsidian. But the longer I did that the more cumbersome it looked to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an ARM Terminal</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 15:41:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-09-08-building-an-arm-terminal-back-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For long I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired by future interfaces commonly seen in science fiction movies and other things like comics or concept art. I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/cyberDeck/&#34;&gt;Cyberdeck reddit&lt;/a&gt; for some time and when I came accross the &lt;a href=&#34;https://back7.co/home/arm-terminal&#34;&gt;ARM Terminal by Back7&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to build one..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few months and one 3D printer later, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to print most of the parts &lt;em&gt;(For smaller printers like the Prusa Mini I have it&amp;rsquo;s better to split the bigger parts and glue them together later with superglue)&lt;/em&gt;. After the shipment of parts &amp;amp; screen came in, I started the assembly and it currently looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EsperantoXL</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/esperantoxl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 10:15:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/esperantoxl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://esperantoxl.nl/&#34;&gt;EsperantoXL&lt;/a&gt; I make custom solutions to extend the possibilities of no-code applications with the help of Serverless &amp;amp; computing providers like AWS &amp;amp; Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This solution allows for processing million lines of codes in a unsupported datafile, analyze &amp;amp; run queries on it and return it through a callback towards the no-code platform once again. Most of the implementations are based on &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome plugins for RPA</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-16-chrome-plugin-rpa-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 20:58:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-16-chrome-plugin-rpa-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who creates shortcuts and automations all the time I often get asked questions about certain things to automate that aren&amp;rsquo;t really like the things I personally do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time this has to do with web applications and the barrier of create an entire app (if there even is an API available) is way to high based on price or time spend. More recently I discovered that an easy way of packaging and shipping things for individuals to larger groups could often be in the form of a &lt;em&gt;Chrome extension&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My daily journaling scripts for Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 09:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-14-obsidian-scripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m quite a heavy user of &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of my scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve written for it. Please note that all of the scripts make use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&#34;&gt;Keyboard Meastro&lt;/a&gt; as a way to activate them and some of them use javascript automation within Mac OS X. So it&amp;rsquo;s Apple only for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Obsidian I&amp;rsquo;m keeping a folder in which there are files that are used as a templates. Whether that is the &lt;em&gt;daily note&lt;/em&gt; or some other template I often use. Keyboad Meastro just reads these files and paste the contents right at the cursor when I type a certain string.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting systems within Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-interacting-knowledge-systems-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-interacting-knowledge-systems-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; as my go-to note-taking application. Moving from &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; and from Roam back into the habit of writing local markdown. I wanted to write about one of the biggest benefits I’m experiencing, and it’s about interacting of systems which where previously disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The systems I’m talking about are &lt;em&gt;CRM&lt;/em&gt;’s, &lt;em&gt;time-tracking&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;personal knowledge management&lt;/em&gt; and others like creating a fountain for intersecting ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I started out with a home-grown CRM, allowing me to keep everything by myself, but the burden of developing an entire interface just for managing stuff took me for long way around…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search for a knowledge system</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-knowledge-systems-obsidian-markdown-roam-research-workflowy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 13:24:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-08-06-knowledge-systems-obsidian-markdown-roam-research-workflowy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a system which would augment my own thinking with the help of the computer. One of the main promises of a digital life is things could more efficient. Or easily shareable and more resilient (Once you have backups..). For a meriad of reasons the switch should be obvious but for the most of us, that&amp;rsquo;s not what we experience. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started of with just Word documents in folders. This failed within weeks due to the fact that sometimes information would belong to two or more different files. How could I keep those in order when updating the content? Thus I started looking for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/dropper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Dropper I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented improvements for their &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; application. Dropper was a startup that was into last-mile delivery. Optimization where mostly on the performance side of things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vogsy</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/vogsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:19:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/vogsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Vogsy I developed several intergrations in CRMs (Hubspot, Salesforce &amp;amp; Copper) and financial applications (Quickbooks, Exact &amp;amp; Xero). I also provided a base for a Zapier application that lets users automate things together with Vogsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All API integrations where build with &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; on App Engine. For each integration a seperate integration layer is build with full test-coverage. The architecture is based on Domain Driven Design (DDD).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an Ant PCB Maker</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-05-02-ant-pcb-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 14:37:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-05-02-ant-pcb-maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strange times we live in these days. Staying at home does allow me to work on projects which have been slowly progressing over time. And one of those is the Ant PCB Maker. A CoreXY based small CNC mill that can make printed circuit boards (PCBs). Contrary to the guide I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to built mine a little bigger. This should allow me to create PCBs which are up to 200x200mm without any problems. Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the build:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brouwerij Nooitgedacht</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/brouwerij_nooitgedacht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:56:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/brouwerij_nooitgedacht/</guid>
      <description>Brouwerij Nooitgedacht is our brewery that I run together with friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization.supply</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/organization-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/organization-supply/</guid>
      <description>An inventory management tool build with Python &amp;amp; Django</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Pi camera mount for the Prusa Mini</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-03-05-custom-camera-mount-prusa-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 15:33:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-03-05-custom-camera-mount-prusa-mini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since a month I own a small 3D printer: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prusa3d.com/original-prusa-mini/&#34;&gt;the Prusa Mini&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve printed almost half my current spool of filament and I can say I love the way the Prusa Mini works for me. Once of the upgrades I have done is move towards &lt;a href=&#34;https://octoprint.org/&#34;&gt;Octoprint&lt;/a&gt; for my workflow, this allows me to connect everything together from my own computer. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I design a component or body with &lt;strong&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/strong&gt;, and in the &amp;lsquo;Make&amp;rsquo; menu option I choose to pass the file to the Prusa Slicer application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Prusa Slicer&lt;/strong&gt; I configure any supports required or tweak any print settings. I then slice the code and send it towards Octoprint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Octoprint&lt;/strong&gt; shows the file and let&amp;rsquo;s me print directly the gcode file directly. Without moving any USB disk around I can start my print, straight from design to reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octoprint does offer more functionality and one of them is the ability to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.octoprint.org/en/master/&#34;&gt;add a camera to not only create timelapses, but also monitor the print itself&lt;/a&gt;. For other printers there are more than enough mounts for cameras. But one for the Prusa Mini was missing. This was an opportunity for me to design one:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micropython LCD menu: upymenu</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-29-upymenu-lcd-micropython-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 21:28:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-29-upymenu-lcd-micropython-menu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve published my first library to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/upymenu/&#34;&gt;PyPi&lt;/a&gt;! It is a simple utility function you can use in micropython to build menus for LCD displays. I was used to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino-libraries/LiquidCrystal&#34;&gt;Liquid Crystal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VaSe7u/LiquidMenu&#34;&gt;Liquid Menu&lt;/a&gt; while developing on an Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I made the switch towards micropython I saw no such thing existed. But having a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Finite-state_machine&#34;&gt;statemachine&lt;/a&gt; like menu is quite easy in Python and I wanted to abstract it a bit into a library, this way it is easier to use for other people!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My setup for Python projects</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-19-python-projects-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:07:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-19-python-projects-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@markdlavin/my-python-environment-setup-fcddd0e99e5b&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jacobian.org/2019/nov/11/python-environment-2020/&#34;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt; that I follow I wanted to share my current setup for Python projects that I use personally. This setup might vary based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/client/&#34;&gt;clients&lt;/a&gt; that I have, but for my own projects this is what I mostly use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTerm, &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/jplattel/34f14bb95854c84a547d7049142270b0&#34;&gt;my own coloured theme.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VSCode, with the following plugins:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python for VSCode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autopep8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bracket pair colorizer 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indent rainbow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git Lens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtualenv (with &lt;a href=&#34;https://virtualenvwrapper.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;virtualenvwrapper&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All environments are saved in the &lt;code&gt;~/.environments&lt;/code&gt; folder,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;isort&lt;/code&gt; for code-formatting and sorting imports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pytest for tests, with coverage (&lt;code&gt;pytest-cov&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes my projects are inside a Docker container and don&amp;rsquo;t need the virtual environment, a specific dockerfile for that Python version is sufficient enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 years of 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 20:13:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2020-01-04-celebrating-ten-years-836pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today marks something special&lt;/em&gt;. Ten years ago, inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://busterbenson.com/&#34;&gt;Buster Benson&lt;/a&gt; I started taking a picture at &lt;strong&gt;8:36pm every day&lt;/strong&gt;. A simple thing you might think, but in the end I kept doing it and to this day I still do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping a habit for 10 years makes it a bit extraordinairy and I can say I will continue taking a picture! Below you will find this years movie of all the photos I took. And if you want to have a look at all the videos, checkout this &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/showcase/6688367&#34;&gt;Vimeo collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the Podcast: Side Project Show</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/side-project-show-abn-amro-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:14:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/side-project-show-abn-amro-podcast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating my brewery (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-12-19-automating-my-brewery-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 23:23:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-12-19-automating-my-brewery-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this part of building my own automated brewery I want to focus on something I have never done before. And that this: &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.jplattel.nl/file/jplattel-dropshare/Screen-Shot-2019-12-26-17-02-30.64-1577376160.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing my own PCB (printed circuit board) is something I was fascinated in for some time, but I always thought of it as somthing very complex and hard to learn. Luckily I got introducted to EasyEDA by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ikbenke.es/&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; and spend a few afternoons watching video tutorials. After rummaging around a bit and some frustration I ordered my first board.. As always, this one only worked partly, temperature input &amp;amp; lcd worked fine, but the buttons lacked a pull up resistor on some pins and I used one pin that didn&amp;rsquo;t have interupt support on the WeMo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating my brewery (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-18-automating-my-brewery-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 21:55:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-18-automating-my-brewery-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-17-automating-my-brewery-part-1/&#34;&gt;first part&lt;/a&gt;, I looked at the frame/enclosure for everything that we need to automate my own brewery. In this part I wanted to show which parts are on the inside based functionality. but first a picture of the enclosure while it&amp;rsquo;s being build:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.jplattel.nl/file/jplattel-dropshare/2019-11-03-13.15.05-1574201936.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enclosure of the brewery controller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enclosure contains the following things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backside:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;230V IN: Voltage in, the main power supply for all devices in the enclosure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;230V OUT: Switched by the solid state relay based on the PID algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RJ12 Female connecter: Input for the temperature sensor that is used by the PID algorithm as input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontside:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic-light interface: lights to indicate what is on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LCD Display (16x4): The main interface on which you can see what is happing and change settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Arcade buttons: the main input device for controlling everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twist dial: controlling the speed of the pump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pump input &amp;amp; output: Connections for the pump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inside:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid state relay: switching on the main heating element (230V OUT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pump power adapter: the pump has it&amp;rsquo;s own power converter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wemo D1 Mini lite: the main brains of the device, running micropython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 volt adapter: Used by the Wemo D1 Mini lite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnetically coupled pump: The main circulation device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom PCB: More on this later!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most electric wiring is done with couplers, and only the lower voltages for the button and controllers are based on pins or screwterminals, which are less secure, but hey! In the next version I might want to make the shield for the wemo plug into the one for the display, saving another 4 wires.. But that&amp;rsquo;s for another time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small mention in an article about data monitoring in De Telegraaf</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-werkvloer-you-telegraaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 13:59:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-werkvloer-you-telegraaf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontys interview about curiousity</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/fontys-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 12:34:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/fontys-interview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating my brewery (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-17-automating-my-brewery-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 19:49:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-11-17-automating-my-brewery-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an avid home-brewer I own a setup that I use for testing out recipes and recreating my favorite beers with my own twist. Over the last years, my gear has improved a bit and one of my main projects is automating my own brewery. I wanted to document this, so maybe other people could use this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brewing system consists of a Brew in a Bag (&lt;a href=&#34;https://biabbrewing.com/&#34;&gt;BIAB&lt;/a&gt;) system, build on a modified &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weckenonline.com/inmaakketels-en-toebehoren&#34;&gt;Weck&lt;/a&gt;-kettle. I&amp;rsquo;m able to brew a batch of around 20L depending on how well filtration and mashing goes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been driving the mashing schedule based on a temperature meter just in the middle of the kettle and eye-balling it on how well it keeps the temperature. (&lt;em&gt;insulation helps keeping it more stable of longer periods time!&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wafl</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/wafl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:13:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/wafl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Maurice van Dinther and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wafl.nu&#34;&gt;Wafl.nu&lt;/a&gt; I developed several questionnaire tools, this allowed him to get more clients or create something that his clients could use. All of those tools were build with &lt;a href=&#34;https://svelte.dev/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Svelte&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If a backend was required it was build with &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/chalice/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chalice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea Machine</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-10-21-the-idea-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:36:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-10-21-the-idea-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boredom is something we all experience in different ways. And the solution isn’t always that easy. You might dwell for a certain amount of time on the couch.. Or restless as you are think about thinks you might want to do, but they never seem to come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a certain part boredom is necessary to facilitate ideas and other serendipitous discoveries. However there might be times, in which you would like for the pure boredom to disappear. After talking to my girlfriend about this we wanted too see what kind of a solution we could think of. And here is the result:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.jplattel.nl/file/jplattel-dropshare/B02CEF3D-4D51-4AC9-A94F-3487D6E89813-1571747019/B02CEF3D-4D51-4AC9-A94F-3487D6E89813.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;The Idea Machine&#34;&gt;
It looks like a coffee grinder, but it is an idea machine, meant for only one purpose and only allowing one simple interaction. Instead of grinding coffee,  you pull open the drawer to reveal a print-out of and idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eerst Hulp Bij Abonnementen (EHBA)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-08-17-eerste-hulp-bij-abonnementen-ns-ehba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 20:01:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-08-17-eerste-hulp-bij-abonnementen-ns-ehba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my first projects for learning programming and navigating around the digitale sphere was building a visualization based on transport data. As I use public transport for all travel I naturally wanted to know how I spend my money on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question has been popping in and out of my mind ever since and more recently I had some time to tinker again. This time I was wonder if I could recommend subscriptions based on historical data from a person. And lo and behold: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ehba.app&#34;&gt;EHBA&lt;/a&gt; (eerste hulp bij abonnementen) was born!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EHBA.app</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/ehba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:05:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/ehba/</guid>
      <description>Eerste hulp bij abonnementen offers a data-based recommendations train travel subscriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel member @ Big Brother Awards</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:59:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/big-brother-awards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2018</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-01-06-836pm-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:48:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2019-01-06-836pm-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we close out 2018 and start out the new year fresh, the one thing left to do is make a video of all the 8:36pm photos that I took that year. And when uploading this video I checked out when I started, which is 2010. Thus this marks the 10th year that I&amp;rsquo;m doing this&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s the video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/309760850&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew, racking in around 3000 photos so far&amp;hellip; For all I can say is that I will probably be going somewhere with this.. But who knows where.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nolostcapital</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/nolostcapital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/business/people/academic/phoebe-moore&#34;&gt;Nolostcapital&lt;/a&gt; I build a tool that lets them put out questionnaires for specific goals towards well-being and HR. The tool offers direct insights from all the results from those questionnaires, enabling organizations to quickly act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backend service was done in &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; and the front-end in &lt;em&gt;Vue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone XS NFC Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-10-16-iphone-xs-nfc-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 23:38:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-10-16-iphone-xs-nfc-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently gotten a new iPhone and with it some more stuff to tinker with. And one of those things is the ability to read NFC tags natively. Following the rabbit hole I ended up ordering a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;NFC reader&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Albeit a simple one, it turns out it is flexible enought to read most cards and write some as well (and more if you have some time to spend..)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambassador for the Digital Society School Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/ambassador-digital-society-school-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 17:17:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/ambassador-digital-society-school-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 - 2020 I am one of the ambassadors for the Digital Society School located in Amsterdam</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making and Fixing Things</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 21:25:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-08-27-making-and-fixing-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bougth a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;3D printer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; together with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;my brother&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not new technology, but it&amp;rsquo;s at a place where it&amp;rsquo;s solid and developed enough that I chose to buy one. That way I can spend my time with one as efficiently as possible, while developing new skills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for what you can do with it? Fixing stuff for example, a custom bracket that broke in one of my kitchen appliances is now easily fixable by measuring the broken part en replicating it in 3D software like &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Fusion360&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Mag jouw baas je bloeddruk weten als hij jou ermee kan helpen?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/intermediar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 14:51:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/intermediar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundsup</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:15:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/fundsup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To enable target marketing towards startups and investors alike, I helped Fundsup create a single database for campaigns and meta-data for their platform. The main technology of this stack was &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; for the backend and the API and &lt;em&gt;Vue&lt;/em&gt; for the front-end. The database was PostGres with JSON fields allowing for querying non-schema based fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watermelon</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:28:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/watermelon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In two weeks I created the first REST API for a chatbot service that Watermelon is offering to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got started I also converted their current stack to support Docker &amp;amp; implemented an auth gateway that would take in older auth flows and support better authentication for the API. The API was build in &lt;em&gt;python&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt; with Django Rest Framework (DRF)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colliers</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:27:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/colliers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with Colliers we created the Quantified Workplace, an experiment in which we tracked physical activity, heart-rate, computer usage, productivity and personal scores troughout the day. This data was collected in a dashboard that would enable employees to discover insights about their health and well-being during the workday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the entire year of tracking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/business/people/academic/phoebe-moore&#34;&gt;Phoebe V. Moore&lt;/a&gt; as researcher investigated the impact of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the technology stack, custom API&amp;rsquo;s for interfacing with different trackers were all built with &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; and the main dashboard is based on &lt;em&gt;Django&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Koninkrijksrelaties</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/bzk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:25:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/bzk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on LinkedIn data, I created insights for The Ministry of the Interior. Each year over 200 trainees are joining the government and their skills can be employed more wisely and based on interest next to experience from the traineeship itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work consisted out of gathering the data, visualisation and future strategy on how to match talent within the government. Most work is done in &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; and Jupyter notebooks as the technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring an old plane</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-29-restoring_an_old_plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 20:12:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-29-restoring_an_old_plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At one of the stands of a flea market during Kingsday here in the Netherlands, I found an old plane. And for only 2 euro I couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave it behind. I took it on me to restore it to its former glory. First step, dismantle the broken off handle, removing any drops of paint and cleaning the chisel from all the rust. I also took measurements of the old handle and started designing that in Fusion 360. I love it how I just started using that and more projects come my way that need some kind of modeling. I also had to remove a big bolt that was mounted up front:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing a new batch of beer</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-26-new_batch_nooitop_kratfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:51:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-04-26-new_batch_nooitop_kratfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Past week we spend a day at a brewery! We made a new batch for our brewery &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Nooitgedacht&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. We improved our recipe of our tripel and you can now fund our brewery buy pre-ordering a crate of beer trough &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Kratfunding&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, we only ship to the Netherlands currently!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to use Kratfunding in a way to organise enough money to be self-sufficient as a brewery. And as an organization we want to enable more homebrewers to scale up more easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Zorgvisie Ict, De Patient als wetenschaps-instrument</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/zorgvisie-ict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:19:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/zorgvisie-ict/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Arte TV: CES &amp; Wearables</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/arte-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:16:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/arte-tv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Volmaakte Mens (VPRO)</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/volmaakte-mens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:15:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/volmaakte-mens/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous-vide Rice Cooker</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/sous-vide-ricecooker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:14:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/sous-vide-ricecooker/</guid>
      <description>I modified my rice-cooker so I can use it as a sous-vide apparatus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Longboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/diy-longboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:13:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/diy-longboard/</guid>
      <description>I created my own longboard from scratch (with a Mondrian pattern on the back).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De Padvinders</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/de-padvinders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 23:07:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/de-padvinders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first real project that got a bit out of hand and developed in a business while I was a student. Together with 4 other friends I helped people with working smarter on their computer, basically doing as Seth Godin said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go find a geek. Someone who understands Gmail, Outlook, and other basic tools. Pay him to sit next to you for an hour and watch you work. Then say, &amp;rsquo;tell me five ways I can save an hour a day.&amp;rsquo; Whatever you need to pay for this service, it will pay for itself in a week. ~ Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Een Leuk Boek, slimmer en productiever werken</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/een-leuk-boek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 23:01:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/een-leuk-boek/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mondriaantje</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/mondriaantje/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 22:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/mondriaantje/</guid>
      <description>Input your name and get your own personalized Mondrian!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berichtenbox Forwarder</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/berichtenbox-forwarder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 22:18:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/berichtenbox-forwarder/</guid>
      <description>A small utility that enables automagic fetching of messages of our government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: P&amp;O Actueel, The Quantified Workplace</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/po-actueel-qwp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 22:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/po-actueel-qwp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: TEDxYouth Groningen, 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/tedxyouth-groningen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:23:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/tedxyouth-groningen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎁 Wishlist</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:17:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is my wishlist, if there&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve done for you and you would like to give me something in return, this could serve as a list of inspiration. ✌️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;physical-stuff-trinkets-andor-activities&#34;&gt;Physical stuff, trinkets and/or activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://choosingkeeping.com/collections/light-mills/products/clear-light-mill-two-sizes?variant=4349774921756&#34;&gt;light mill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Spinthariscope&#34;&gt;spinthariscope&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcpoodle.com/collections/home/products/volty-bit-for-leatherman-multi-tool&#34;&gt;Volty bit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One big &lt;a href=&#34;https://shop.houseofmarbles.com/product/space-explorer-marble/&#34;&gt;marble&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/articles/Euler&#39;s_Disk&#34;&gt;Euler&amp;rsquo;s Disk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://kleinbottle.com/&#34;&gt;Klein Bottle&lt;/a&gt;. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a zero-volume bottle or infinite space?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://offgrid.co/products/off-grid-bag?variant=30205371383890&#34;&gt;OffGrid Bag&lt;/a&gt; with faraday function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Garmin &lt;a href=&#34;https://buy.garmin.com/nl-NL/NL/p/592606&#34;&gt;InReach Mini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comics drawn by &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Giraud&#34;&gt;Moebius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schaakengo.nl/goshop-keima/spelmateriaal/sets/go-beginnersset-luxe&#34;&gt;Go set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-already-gave-me&#34;&gt;People already gave me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Diresta &lt;a href=&#34;https://imakeny.com/collections/tools/products/diresta-ice-pick&#34;&gt;Ice Pick&lt;/a&gt; (Thanks Simon!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buitenontbijtjes.nl/winkel/buitenstoel/&#34;&gt;Rollstoel&lt;/a&gt; (Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;Kees&lt;/a&gt;!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hang_(instrument)&#34;&gt;Hang&lt;/a&gt; (Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.detoevalligeontmoeting.be/&#34;&gt;toevallige ontmoeting&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.leatherman.com/ratchet-driver-931030.html&#34;&gt;ratcheting driver&lt;/a&gt; for the leatherman I own. (Thanks Mei &amp;amp; Kees!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.taschenboeken.nl/atlas-bookstand-yellow.html&#34;&gt;book stand&lt;/a&gt; (Dankjewel &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jennapostma.nl/&#34;&gt;Jenna&lt;/a&gt;!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makerscabinet.com/collections/all-flagship-products/products/iris&#34;&gt;Iris&lt;/a&gt; by Makers Cabinet (Thanks Martijn!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/Electric-State-Simon-St%C3%A5lenhag/dp/1501181416?tag=jplattel-21&#34;&gt;The Electric State&lt;/a&gt; (hardcover).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forge my own axe and/or blades (Thanks Chantal! ❤️)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.nl/Tales-Loop-Simon-Stalenhag/dp/1624650392&#34;&gt;Tales from the Loop&lt;/a&gt; (hardcover).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bol.com/nl/p/things-from-the-flood/9200000129251022/&#34;&gt;Things from the flood&lt;/a&gt; (hardcover).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Every-Tools-Hammer-Life-What/dp/1982113472&#34;&gt;Every tool&amp;rsquo;s a hammer&lt;/a&gt; by Adam Savage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://puzzle.lamingtondrive.com/&#34;&gt;This puzzle&lt;/a&gt; (thanks Nathalie!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bol.com/nl/p/cool-tools/9200000020982860/&#34;&gt;Cool Tools&lt;/a&gt; book, thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vitaminecommunicatie.nl/&#34;&gt;Vitamine Communicatie&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.taschen.com/pages/en/catalogue/art/all/04639/facts.dali_les_diners_de_gala.htm?gclid=Cj0KEQjwg8i_BRCT9dHt5ZSGi90BEiQAItdjpMqOS3gORWwVrFL8DHsHtD0IkavXJryJbxaRuclqvKYaAnVa8P8HAQ&#34;&gt;cooking book&lt;/a&gt; by Dali&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moebius Library: The World of Edena, thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/daanbuse?ppe=1&#34;&gt;Daan&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isolation_tank&#34;&gt;Float&lt;/a&gt; in total darkness (thanks Marjolein!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timothy Ferriss: Tools of Titans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lacie.com/us/products/product.htm?id=10564&#34;&gt;Lacie Rugged Mini&lt;/a&gt; HD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/nl/shop/product/MM4T2ZM/A/apple-remote&#34;&gt;Apple Remote&lt;/a&gt; (old one, not for the new apple TV)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://cargorecordsdirect.co.uk/collections/fm3-buddha-machines&#34;&gt;Buddha Machine&lt;/a&gt; thanks Elpine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Gerber multi-tool, thanks Casper!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1Password License for Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulse Sensor for Arduino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Grid It (Thanks, Santa!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dopper Steel (Thanks Eric!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soldering station thanks Wouter Groenewold!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soft Brew Coffee pot, thank you Ilse!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makey Makey, thanks Loes!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neurosky Mindband (A Zeo with a raw data library is better 🤓)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote Pro-account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vibram Five Fingers Bikila (maatje 43) (Thanks @FiveFingersNL!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zeo Sleep Coach (Thanks Zeo!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help with my trip to the US for the first Quantified Self Conference (Thanks everybody fo your help!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self community</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/quantifiedself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:10:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/quantifiedself/</guid>
      <description>I co-founded the QS Amsterdam group &amp;amp; started the QS Conference in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Groene Amsterdammer, Het alziend oog van de baas</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/media/groene_amsterdammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:05:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/media/groene_amsterdammer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Corner of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/curious_corner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 20:38:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/curious_corner/</guid>
      <description>A (almost) monthly newsletter stocked with the stuff I find on the corners of the internet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about my phone usage</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-26-talking-about-my-phone-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-26-talking-about-my-phone-usage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year before I went on holiday to Portugal I had the opportunity to give a talk at the Quantified Self 2017 Conference in Amsterdam. I decided just the night before to talk about how much I use my phone (or better how much I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use it!). The wonderful folks over at QS Labs created a page with &lt;a href=&#34;http://qs17.quantifiedself.com/program/&#34;&gt;all the videos&lt;/a&gt; with transcripts. I&amp;rsquo;ve embedded my video below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/227178744&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;My vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating smart bubble counter fermentation process tracking</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-07-creating-smart-bubble-counter-fermentation-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-07-creating-smart-bubble-counter-fermentation-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I spend my time on electronics, with a specific goal in mind, automating the tracking of a fermentation vessel that I use for brewing. My starting point was a Wemos D1 mini lite, which is a cheap arduino compatible chip with wifi options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to track how many bubbles we&amp;rsquo;re sent past the airlock and also needed a photo interupter gate. So in the end everything is pretty cheap and I only needed some more LEDs, an enclosure, spare wires and some free time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2017</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-03-836pm-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2018-01-03-836pm-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past 7 years now, I made a movie out of all the 8:36pm pictures I took this year. It&amp;rsquo;s embedded below from Vimeo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/249402769&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can spot yourself, thanks for being part of my life this year! It&amp;rsquo;s been great fun and I&amp;rsquo;ll take some time to update some of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustrans</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/sustrans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 19:01:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/sustrans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Sustrans in the United Kingdom I made a custom dashboard that allows people to gain insights into their own mobility based on the Moves app (sadly, now deprecated!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with a LoRaWan gateway</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-06-03-getting-started-with-a-lorawan-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-06-03-getting-started-with-a-lorawan-gateway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the work I do is software related, but sometimes I do dabble in hardware. As a result I receive more and more requests for hardware related projects. As an aspiring maker I do want to explore this side of technology more so these projects are perfect opportunities for me to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while learning I thought it would be nice to share what I learned so far as well! I&amp;rsquo;ve been building a LoRaWan gateway with at least 10 connected nodes. And in the past few weeks I got the gateway working, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to show which steps I took and what hardware is required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting energy usage with Prophet</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-03-16-predicting-energy-usage-with-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-03-16-predicting-energy-usage-with-prophet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook recently released &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebookincubator/prophet/&#34;&gt;Prophet&lt;/a&gt;, a library that makes it easy to create predictions based on time-series data. When the time was right to tinker around, I thought of a dataset I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting for some time now, which is the smart energy meter we have for our house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with some tinkering to get Prophet to play nice with my containers and Jupyter I had my first prediction in a few minutes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All my 8:36pm photos of 2016</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-01-02-836pm-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 20:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2017-01-02-836pm-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy new year! Hope you had a blast the past few weeks! I surely did :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tradition when a new year starts, I had to make a movie of all my 8:36pm photos of past year. And this time its easier as every, since I saved the After Effects project template of last year. Here&amp;rsquo;s the video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/197810495&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why shoot a picture everyday you might ask? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4_nhIF2coKk&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s the answer! And in case you want to get all your photos of Mobypicture as well, here&amp;rsquo;s the gist:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing beer in a modified kettle</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-11-15-brewing-beer-in-a-modified-kettle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 15:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-11-15-brewing-beer-in-a-modified-kettle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me a while, but I managed to write this post about the thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time on in the last few months: brewing beer. I started collecting things for my own setup a while ago and took the plunge to buy a kettle: &lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/kettle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A modified kettle for brewing beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now the temperature will be manually controlled, and I will be stirring for a while, but I&amp;rsquo;m slowly working towards and enclosure that covers the pump and a PID for temperature control. For the brewing method I use the brew-in-a-bag system, which lets me easily get out all the malts, but the filtering proces ain&amp;rsquo;t perfect yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On holiday in Italy: Rome, Florence, Pisa &amp; Cinque Terre</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I spend 2 weeks in Italy together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://chantalvankempen.nl/&#34;&gt;Chantal&lt;/a&gt;. We started off in Rome, spending our time in Trastevere. We visited all the main tourist attractions, because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t visited Rome before. Time passed by pretty quickly and we traveled to Florence by BlaBlaCar. After a day of traveling, it&amp;rsquo;s great to jump in a pool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florence is an amazing city, especially when you can watch the sun set over the city, the food is good and if you dive a bit into Italian culture you&amp;rsquo;ll find hidden gems! Next up was San Gimigniano, a little town with lots of towers. We stayed in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://agriturismo.it&#34;&gt;agriturismo&lt;/a&gt; for 1 night, I cannot recommend this enough if you are somewhere in Tuscania. We visited Pisa before going to La Spezia, which would be our take off point for the main goal of our trip: Cinque Terre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SETUP - Utrecht</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 19:01:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For SETUP I contributed on several projects by building prototypes on the topics on ethics, privacy and technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London on a double-bike</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On sunday the 10th of June I left my parents place on a double-bike. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://fei.je/&#34;&gt;a friend&lt;/a&gt; we cycled to Zwolle, took a train and prepared ourselves in the evening for a trip to London. As we took the boat to Harwich the next day I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect as I hadn&amp;rsquo;t visited England before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_8747.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_8747-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Processed with VSCO with c1 preset&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we talked with locals it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s much more enjoyable if you take the small hilly roads towards your destination. This also ensures more scenic views and much more nature, unfortunately this also introduced some off-road paths which our bike didn&amp;rsquo;t take that well.. (as did we!). Before long we reached London and did a quick tourist route covering the most important landmarks:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qount.us</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/project/qountus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:29:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/project/qountus/</guid>
      <description>How can we use personal data to improve the way we do our work? Qount.us was a dashboard collecting personal data with a goal to increase insights that might boost the quality of life surrounding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A talk about the many things a little experiment can teach you</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-06-02-many-things-little-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 10:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-06-02-many-things-little-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 14th of March 2016 I gave a short talk at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/tedxyouthgroningen/&#34;&gt;TEDxYouth Groningen&lt;/a&gt;, and the video is finally online! I&amp;rsquo;ve embedded the video below, it&amp;rsquo;s in dutch but I&amp;rsquo;m sure the subtitles will be available shortly. My talk is about the all the photos I took so far at 8:36pm. I started without any specific reason, but found out that you could figure it out while doing it as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve collected over 5 years of photos and I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on quitting any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing (LinkedIn) interfaces with Chrome plugins</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-05-02-fixing-interfaces-with-chrome-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 22:19:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-05-02-fixing-interfaces-with-chrome-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online services tend to change their functionality or interaction. Sometimes in a good way, other times in a bad way. Most recently LinkedIn made a little change in the way accepting (and replying to) invites works. I personally use LinkedIn as a address book and leave it alone at times, never inviting people but combing trough the invites. I used to reply with a text-expander snippet too see if a connection is valuable, but this seemed to be impossible lately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Waves</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:32:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-03-08-making-waves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far today has been enjoyable, until around noon when someone texted me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nu.nl/gadgets/4226833/bedrijven-mogen-gezondheid-medewerkers-niet-volgen-via-wearables.html&#34;&gt;a url pointing to nu.nl&lt;/a&gt;, showing an article about the Data Protection Authority telling me it is forbidden for employers to use wearables to track their employees (also on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tweakers.net/nieuws/109089/werkgevers-mogen-gezondheidsgegevens-werknemers-niet-volgen-met-wearables.html&#34;&gt;tweakers.net&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&#34;https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/nieuws/ap-verwerking-gezondheidsgegevens-wearables-door-werkgevers-mag-niet&#34;&gt;The research&lt;/a&gt; the article points to is actually two companies that run my dashboards. Before I get into details, let me state the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The privacy of an employee is of utmost importance! Employee first, employer last (or not at all!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Data Protection Authority is one of the most important organisations in regard to the coming technological expansion, we need them more then ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The grey area and boundaries existing the current space of law require meticulous investigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the article carefully, you will notice it is still acceptable for a third-party to collect data with a wearable, but showing the data (in any way) to the employer is a no-go. This is something I totally agree with, but it conflicts partially with the requirements of a good employer to take care of their employees. A deeper exploration is required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy &amp; Gracefully revealing depth</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-23-privacy-gracefully-revealing-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 14:11:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-23-privacy-gracefully-revealing-depth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of days ago I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.atlassian.com/blog/2016/02/6-secret-bitbucket-features/?categories=git&#34;&gt;a post from Atlassian&lt;/a&gt; explaining some new features, but the most interesting aspect was that they explore gracefully revealing depth. To me this same concept can also be applied to privacy, ethics and more problems. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s about functionality, the same can be applied to complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we are faced with interesting problems about privacy and ethics, would the way of gracefully revealing complexity work for making the right choices or settings the right parameters? I think it does, and that&amp;rsquo;s why I started building &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/gradual-privacy-personal-data/&#34;&gt;gradual privacy&lt;/a&gt;, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t end there, the other way around is also fascinating, as some functions might not be thought of beforehand. This relates to privacy and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/musings-on-transparency/&#34;&gt;transparency&lt;/a&gt; even more, could we cover all scenarios with these depths? Or how deep are these depths?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on transparency</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-16-musings-on-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 15:10:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-02-16-musings-on-transparency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about and exploring transparency a lot lately. As I&amp;rsquo;m building &lt;a href=&#34;http://qount.us&#34;&gt;dashboards&lt;/a&gt; for employees, transparency is one of the key factors of integration within the workforce. But there are some funny things about transparency and this is why most companies and organisations are having difficulty adopting a transparant way of working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ownership is spread when sharing processes, this lessens your level of power, but this world is not just about ownership any more, access is what it is all about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparency limits the degrees of freedom, when accountability is shown, you are less likely to choose a more adventurous path. Culture is key here, because if you do create a culture were failing is accepted, adding transparency to the mix might prevent people to make the same mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing seems to limit choices due to shortening the feedback loop. But thinking about it, done the correct way I think it could increase choices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The risks of transparency are not yet enough explored. It&amp;rsquo;s a grey area in which the rules aren&amp;rsquo;t yet enough established. The internet itself can be seen as an early precursor of what radical full transparency could be within a organisation. It can be used in both good and bad ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, most of the situations involve data and technology in relation with transparency, ethics and privacy. It&amp;rsquo;s a very big grey area in which there&amp;rsquo;s enough discovery to be done!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On solving annoying things</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-29-on-solving-annoying-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 10:33:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-29-on-solving-annoying-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dutch government and other (bigger) organisations seem to have a habit to annoy people. One of the reasons they do so is security by obscurity. It has it’s flaw as shown in this blogpost by &lt;a href=&#34;https://levels.io/gov-y-u-suck/&#34;&gt;@levelsio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wrote a little script that fetches and forwards all the email, which everyone can do after loggin in with DigiD. As shown, this takes a lot of steps. Automating it can be done with less then 50 lines of code. Following his blogpost I also decided to open-source my script, which has the same functionality. I’ve uploaded the code on Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/berichtenbox-forwarder&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jplattel/berichtenbox-forwarder&lt;/a&gt;. You still need a little knowledge of python to install it, but it’s one step closer to an easy life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous-vide food with a rice cooker</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-20-sous-vide-rice-cooker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 15:56:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-20-sous-vide-rice-cooker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been on my &lt;em&gt;tinker-list&lt;/em&gt; for around 4 years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around doing it. I made a little temperature controlled relay to my rice-cooker which enables me to use it as a sous-vide apparatus. That&amp;rsquo;s wonderful, because it&amp;rsquo;s now easier to prepare meat, and most importantly, eat 67 °C eggs. So how did I do it? I bought a really cheap PID &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dx.com/p/digital-temperature-controller-66334?r=41389038&#34;&gt;from DealExtreme&lt;/a&gt;, and with some help of Martin Deen I had everything set up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and reflections about 2015</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 17:34:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year passed an I&amp;rsquo;m due to update my projects page and create another one for next year! To close past year and explore the next I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yearcompass.com/&#34;&gt;YearCompass&lt;/a&gt; for my reflections. It took me over 3 afternoons to completely fill it out, but it&amp;rsquo;s an enjoyable ride! It&amp;rsquo;s great looking backwards into your calendar and see all that you have achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also concatenated all my 8:36pm photos into a video like I do every year. Sadly during some time this year, my phone broke down more often and I&amp;rsquo;ve left it on the table too much to my liking&amp;hellip; Next year will be better, I promise! Here&amp;rsquo;s the video:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lecture in Ghent</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:25:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I gave a lecture in Ghent, a beautiful city and so I decided to spend the weekend at an AirBnB host to enjoy the city! Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture I took:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_6578.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_6578.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded all the slides from the lecture on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/jsplattel/slideshelf&#34;&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt; for you to enjoy. It was my longest lecture and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned some useful things while doing so. I find that having a storyline with little pieces is harder to keep up over longer times, so next time I will try to venture more in depth of some of my personal tracking experiments, for example my &lt;a href=&#34;www.jplattel.nl/quantified-phone-usage-ipython/&#34;&gt;phone usage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Phone Usage with iPython</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:35:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology is making it easier to collect data, for example phone usage. From the 1st of January I tracked how much I&amp;rsquo;ve used my phone by installing an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/moment-track-how-much-you/id771541926?mt=8&#34;&gt;Moment&lt;/a&gt;. It runs in the background and silently tracks how much you use your phone. As said, the first step towards behaviour-change is providing insight in current behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring iPython for data-analysis and sharing snippets of data. I&amp;rsquo;ve started a Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/notebooks&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; that contains some notebooks I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka for holiday!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 14:30:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long overdue, but now I have some time to spend writing a blogpost. The previous month I&amp;rsquo;ve spend 3 weeks in Sri Lanka! For two weeks, we discovered the island, visiting beaches, jungle, towns and cities. The culture is wonderful and people are very friendly. It&amp;rsquo;s also been a great opportunity to try out some new things, for example dabbling in photography and exploring apps like &lt;a href=&#34;http://vsco.co/film&#34;&gt;VSCO&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, all of the pictures have been shot with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.canon.nl/for_home/product_finder/cameras/digital_camera/powershot/powershot_s120/&#34;&gt;S-120&lt;/a&gt; and then improved with VSCO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday to Denmark, Berlin and the south of France</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 10:11:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-07-28-holiday-to-denmark-berlin-and-the-south-of-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on holiday for most the past month. The urge to travel has been growing since a few years, and this year I&amp;rsquo;ve been to several new cities in Europe. After the QS Conference in San Francisco in June, I came back, only to pack my bags once again to hop on a bus to Denmark. My father organises a yearly travel group to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://haervejsmarchen.nl/&#34;&gt;Haervejsmarchen&lt;/a&gt;. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://chantalvankempen.nl/&#34;&gt;Chantal&lt;/a&gt; we joined him! Here&amp;rsquo;s a little picture of the heathland we walked trough:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interview for the Perfect Human and other publications</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-06-08-perfect-human-vpro-tv-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 07:55:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-06-08-perfect-human-vpro-tv-publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4450.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4450-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4450&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Two months ago I spent some time before a camera for a documentary series of the VPRO. The series is called The Perfect Human and explores how technology helps us create a better being. My project with Colliers: The Quantified Workplace is highlighted in the interview. You can watch it online &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npo.nl/de-volmaakte-mens/03-06-2015/VPWON_1231936?start_at=1697&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the past year, I spend an afternoon at the Ministry of Health, Welfare and Sport, to contribute towards a document about e-Health. The publication about wearables and technology in healthcare has finally been published. I&amp;rsquo;ve received the printed publication and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the end result. Hopefully this will be the first step towards a better system for people and healthcare. I hope to contribute to more initiatives like this to promote digital literacy in the Healthcare sector. You can read about it at the website of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rvz.net/publicaties/bekijk/consumenten-ehealth&#34;&gt;RVZ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something&#39;s brewing!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 11:12:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-18-somethings-brewing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s beer! Well it&amp;rsquo;s stored now and bubbling away! Yesterday afternoon I&amp;rsquo;ve brewed my first batch of beer. With the gear and knowledge of a friend, we manufactured 48 liters of pale ale. The sunny afternoon also was a perfect opportunity for my new camera, so I took some tests shots. Here&amp;rsquo;s the brewery in my backyard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_0047-e1431897438556-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe we decided on included star-anise and lemongrass. Sadly the coriander seeds got lost and we skipped those. Hopefully the taste will turn out great! First tasting was pretty good! Here we are happy with the progress:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lago di Garda</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 17:43:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-05-14-lago-di-garda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a little holiday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4792.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4792-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4792&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The destination was Moniga del Garda, Italy. And I&amp;rsquo;ve shot some great panorama&amp;rsquo;s that I wanted to share with you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4680.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4680-1024x221.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4680&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4711.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4711-1024x223.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4711&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4669.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_4669-1024x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4669&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer I&amp;rsquo;m visiting Sri Lanka and I bought a little pocket camera to help me with some better pictures. I chose the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.canon.nl/for_home/product_finder/cameras/digital_camera/powershot/powershot_s120/&#34;&gt;S120&lt;/a&gt;, because of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ddL-ycOksHM&#34;&gt;Neistat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradual Privacy for personal data</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-26-gradual-privacy-personal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 11:03:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-26-gradual-privacy-personal-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been building &lt;a href=&#34;http://qount.us/&#34;&gt;more and more dashboards&lt;/a&gt; for clients. The idea of collecting personal data however always raises questions about privacy. To solve this, I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a way to implement gradual privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradual privacy is a way to let the end-user decide who can see what data. The best way to explain, is just to show it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/Screen-Shot-2015-02-26-at-10.53.33-AM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/Screen-Shot-2015-02-26-at-10.53.33-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gradual Privacy settings&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The columns are the kind of data. And the rows are the parties you could share with. Naturally you would want to see all data, so &amp;lsquo;personal&amp;rsquo; is checked by default. In the case of one dashboard, you can share data within the organization, the company doctor and scientific research. The next option could even be sharing it publicly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the Intelligence Room</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been steadily involved with a project that aims to recreate an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.nl/search?q=control+room&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=Y2LPVOz2BMP7UOrJgrAF&amp;amp;ved=0CAgQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1276&amp;amp;bih=705&#34;&gt;war/control/intelligence room&lt;/a&gt; that you see in movies. The one difference is that the room is ment for decision-makers within bigger companies. Often, urgent en relevant questions go unanswered, but the Intelligence Room helps fixing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigimprovementday.nl/&#34;&gt;Big Improvement Day&lt;/a&gt; we showcased our concept and I&amp;rsquo;ve created a little Django app that matches all attendees based on topics they provided when signing up for the event. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it worked:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm, a 2014 video!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 01:16:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-01-06-836pm-2014-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my fourth year that I&amp;rsquo;m taking pictures everyday at 8:36pm. A little something that I plan to keep on doing for my entire life. Every year I make a small movie off all the pictures! Have a look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/115863678&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of this year including a holiday across the netherlands, moving to a new home and Italy! Hope 2015 will be as great as last year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printing lampshades or any object based on data.</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-12-14-3d-printing-objects-and-lampshades-based-on-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 23:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-12-14-3d-printing-objects-and-lampshades-based-on-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I stayed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://herman.kopinga.nl/&#34;&gt;Herman&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; place for a couple of days. While there we primarily discussed buttons, 3D printers and other nerdy stuff. As it happend I&amp;rsquo;d look over on his desk and found some test prints for lampshades made of ABS. That got me thinking.. Just a few hours later I was knees deep in code trying to generate something that would look like a 3D model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/Screen-Shot-2014-12-12-at-11.56.18-AM-1024x655.png&#34; alt=&#34;A 3D model in Openscad&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning about power-usage data from my home</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-21-learning-about-power-usage-data-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 10:32:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-21-learning-about-power-usage-data-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently moved to a new home, and I got a freshly installed new electricity meter that&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more intelligent. It was now possible for me to sign up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://slimmemeterportal.nl&#34;&gt;slimmemeterportal.nl&lt;/a&gt;, that let&amp;rsquo;s you access the power-usage data from the meter by a 15 minute window. That&amp;rsquo;s quite some data to play with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being interested in the data, I wrote a little scraper that collects it for me and stores it in a SQL database, from there on, with Flask and Peewee it was quite simple to create a little API for my own dataset. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.github.io/react/&#34;&gt;react.js&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; to learn them both a bit and explore what it possible. Here&amp;rsquo;s one of the first graphs:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/power-usage-graph.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/power-usage-graph-1024x262.png&#34; alt=&#34;Power Usage of my own home over the past 9 days&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve put &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/smp-scraper&#34;&gt;the scraper-code on Github&lt;/a&gt; for everyone to use! I suggest if you want to liberate your data, that&amp;rsquo;s the way to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My server got hacked, this is what I did</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-10-my-server-got-hacked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 09:18:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-11-10-my-server-got-hacked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On friday evening local time (GMT+1) around 21:00 hours my server got hacked, it&amp;rsquo;s CPU immediately shot up towards 100% and my provider removed the box from it&amp;rsquo;s hypervisor node around 18 hours later. Just a few minutes later I got a call from a friend who uses one of my developed applications that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trying SSH-ing into the server (which failed), I logged on to the dashboard for managing my VPS, looking at the CPU usage:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Years of computing</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-10-04-3-years-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 22:42:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-10-04-3-years-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This picture below might seem blurry to you, and indeed it is, but for me it is a significant picture that reflect 3 years of working behind my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/joost.png&#34; alt=&#34;average-webcam-shot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wanderingstan/Lifeslice&#34;&gt;Lifeslice&lt;/a&gt; program for over 3 years now and I thought it was about time to do something with it! The picture above is generated with over 4000 webcamshots taken during that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a trove of other data in too. For example the location of my computer (not necessarily me!) and all screens over time. Have a look at the simple vizualisations I&amp;rsquo;ve made:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned building Django projects: 2</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-09-16-lessons-learned-building-django-projects-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:42:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-09-16-lessons-learned-building-django-projects-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started my graduation phase of my current study. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get my own project in for my graduation thesis, which means I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending more time developing with Django. This post is more of a reminder of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far&amp;hellip; The previous post can be read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/lessons-learned-building-django-projects/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/django-admin/#django-admin-inspectdb&#34;&gt;inspectdb&lt;/a&gt; tool is priceless when using other databases in which you have no schema&amp;rsquo;s yet! During the past month I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with a database from wordpress, including payment plugins. With the inspectdb tool it&amp;rsquo;s easy to generate a schema so you can continue building managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned the hard way: Managers are the go-to option for model-logic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting most of my logic in the views.py, but it grows quickly the more complex your application gets. And I&amp;rsquo;ve seen myself copy-pasting code a lot, hey, that&amp;rsquo;s no &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/misc/design-philosophies/#don-t-repeat-yourself-dry&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m exploring &lt;a href=&#34;http://celery.readthedocs.org&#34;&gt;celery&lt;/a&gt; for a task-queue. It&amp;rsquo;s a new way of thinking for cronjobs and other tasks&amp;hellip; Curious if I could integrate it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/squ1b3r/Djaneiro&#34;&gt;Djaneiro&lt;/a&gt; saves you a hell of a lot of time, recommended if you use Sublime!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From east to west in The Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-08-07-east-west-netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 15:53:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-08-07-east-west-netherlands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s holiday, and I&amp;rsquo;ve spend most of my time last month in The Netherlands hiking. From the east to the west, to complement what we did two years ago. And I wanted to share some pictures of my adventure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2898-1024x764.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2898&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2864-764x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2864&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2918-764x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2918&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_3253-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_3253&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 19 days we hiked over 360 kilometers, staying at farmers, friends, campinggrounds or somewhere else. It was a blast! We&amp;rsquo;ll see where we end up next year! For those interested, the route is called the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marskramerpad&#34;&gt;Marskramerspad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinkering with the Meetup API</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-07-02-meetup-api-tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 13:46:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-07-02-meetup-api-tinkering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/&#34;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; is a service that I use and have been using to organize events for networks. Even though I like Meetup as a service, there are some thing you just cannot do. For example it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hard to make use of the internal knowledge or connections that people have within the network itself. And you are limited to Meetup for sending messages to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a week ago I sat down to explore &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/meetup_api/&#34;&gt;their API&lt;/a&gt;, to see if you could somehow build upon their service. Turns out, you can! I&amp;rsquo;ve written a custom wrapper for the Meetup API, and within a few days my prototype was up and running. For the &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/PermanentBeta/&#34;&gt;Permanent Beta Meetup&lt;/a&gt; we organized I&amp;rsquo;ve build a dashboard which would let people explore the community and it&amp;rsquo;s interest. You could type in anything you would like to explore and what kind of interests you share with other people from the Meetup. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metabiography, written in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 22:04:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-07-metabiography-written-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, most of my time was spend on a project for &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuriveerman.nl/&#34;&gt;Yuri Veerman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.linkedin.com/in/elsbethfraanje&#34;&gt;Elsbeth Fraanje&lt;/a&gt;, who are part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://quantifiedreality.nl/&#34;&gt;Quantified Reality&lt;/a&gt; project by het Mediafonds &amp;amp; the Sandberg Institute. Elsbeth and Yuri are exploring the possiblities of (auto)generating a biography from somebody&amp;rsquo;s meta-data and created the the aptly named Metabiography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was asked by Yuri &amp;amp; Elsbeth to build a working prototype For now, it&amp;rsquo;s in pre-beta phase, but below is a screenshot how it could look like. And functions are still changing around as Yuri &amp;amp; Eslbeth tinker on the concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought Kinetics at Coded Matters: Extended Senses</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-02-thought-kinetics-coded-matters-extended-senses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 18:33:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-06-02-thought-kinetics-coded-matters-extended-senses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last sunday &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es/&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; and I had an exhibition with &lt;a href=&#34;http://thoughtkinetics.com&#34;&gt;Thought Kinetics&lt;/a&gt; and artist-talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codedmatters.nl/event/extended-senses/&#34;&gt;Coded Matters: Extended Senses&lt;/a&gt;. We showed our static prototype exploring the visualization of datasets that are collect and visualized in a static way. This is our first step towards a more realtime system where we can use any data and visualize it on a canvas in an abstract way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/thoughtkinetics-1024x943.png&#34; alt=&#34;Thought Kinetics Artist Talk&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also gave a talk about our process how we got from a prototype towards a more solid system that uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;Node.JS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://unity3d.com/&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt; (for now) for transforming data into visuals. At the end, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jarlschulp.nl/about/&#34;&gt;Jarl&lt;/a&gt; asked us about our vision on privacy and design, and we both share an interesting but exploratory look on the future. The fine balance between dystopian and utopian views is one of my main viewpoints on the use of data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self Europe Conference #3</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-05-14-quantified-self-europe-conference-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 10:35:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-05-14-quantified-self-europe-conference-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I spend my time at the Casa400 hotel for the &lt;a href=&#34;quantifiedself.com/2014/05/2014-qs-europe-conference/&#34;&gt;Quantified Self Europe Conference&lt;/a&gt;. With around 250 attendees and 30% of the people giving a talk, you could truly say that&amp;rsquo;s been an carefully curated unconference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2345-1024x764.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;QS Europe Conference&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a lunch-time ignite talk about my project &lt;a href=&#34;http://qount.us/&#34;&gt;Qount.us&lt;/a&gt; and people liked it! Hopefully the video will be up soon. And I pre-ordered a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vitalconnect.com/&#34;&gt;Vitalconnect&lt;/a&gt; patches for experimenting, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://thoughtkinetics.com/&#34;&gt;Thought Kinetics&lt;/a&gt;. And thanks to all the people I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending time with I&amp;rsquo;m getting on track for the Qount.us project and which way it is heading. For now I&amp;rsquo;ll have it planned for my graduation project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The curious corner on video</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 20:21:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-04-19-curious-corner-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve curated 6 editions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://jplattel.nl/corner&#34;&gt;the Curious Corner of the Internet&lt;/a&gt; until this day. It started out as an experiment of just showing my saved-for-later links in a presentation. The newsletter essentially was a second format, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t explore my chances for a talk much further. Until now, during the Week for the Entrepreneur in the Netherlands, that I&amp;rsquo;d give it another shot. Sadly, it&amp;rsquo;s in dutch, but here&amp;rsquo;s the video:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I made it into another book and co-authored my first white-paper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-27-made-into-another-book-and-white-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 22:52:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-27-made-into-another-book-and-white-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I gave a little talk at the Cross Media Cafe in Hilversum. Happily afterwards I gave a little interview and people took a few photos. This year started pretty nice with some media coverage, but at the end of february a book landed in the mail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/10157012_10201917506443299_729360140_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Book: Trends en Ontwikkeling in de Crossmedia&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a scan of the page and it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/211599572/Cross-Media-Cafe-Apps-Data-Joost-Plattel&#34;&gt;available on Scribd&lt;/a&gt;. And together with the working group of patient generated data, we&amp;rsquo;ve written a white paper about the data that persons generate that healthcare could use. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/214276409/Zelfmetingen-en-de-Nederlandse-Gezondheidszorg&#34;&gt;put it up on Scribd too&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on publishing more!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned building Django projects</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-09-lessons-learned-building-django-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 23:39:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-09-lessons-learned-building-django-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; as my go-to framework for the past few months. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the ride, but have learned some things that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During project setup, create a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/virtualenv&#34;&gt;virtual environment&lt;/a&gt; for yourself to work in. Use the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;pip freeze&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; for creating a requirements.txt that helps you manage dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use any paths within the views. Instead, use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/urlresolvers/#reverse&#34;&gt;reverse function&lt;/a&gt; for looking up routes that correspond to the url. This helps a lot when you run Django in a folder on a server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logic should be integrated into models. I&amp;rsquo;m just getting used to this, but helps creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/misc/design-philosophies/#don-t-repeat-yourself-dry&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/a&gt;-er code. In the next version I will be doing this for most of my dashboard functionalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;http://south.aeracode.org/&#34;&gt;South&lt;/a&gt; for your database migrations. It helps moving data around when you change your models during development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ss64.com/bash/alias.html&#34;&gt;Alias&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;python manage.py&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;django&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; in your bash or zsh config for easy access to functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use different &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/django-admin/#django-admin-option---settings&#34;&gt;settings files&lt;/a&gt; for development, staging and production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When deploying, it took me a while to figure out, but it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use a virtual environment for your app too. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to take it one step further by exploring &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.io/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with company activity dashboards</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-02-07-experimenting-company-activity-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 14:44:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-02-07-experimenting-company-activity-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an experiment, I&amp;rsquo;m collecting data from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://moves-app.com&#34;&gt;Moves app&lt;/a&gt; from multiple persons within a organisation. The goal is to find out what&amp;rsquo;s possible with the amount of data the persons generate each day. Currently, the collection of data is ongoing and the next step would be the visualization of the data. Here are some simple graphs you can make with the data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/graphs-1024x524.png&#34; alt=&#34;activity-dashboard-for-groups&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further steps could be exploring what a group wants from visualisations like this. It&amp;rsquo;s the most benificial if the change of behavior sustains after the initial period of interest. This could be investigated by using different ways for reminders, notifications or possibly reward systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the 8:36pm photos of 2013</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:06:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like last year, I made a small video of all my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jplattel.nl/836pm&#34;&gt;8:36pm photos&lt;/a&gt;. With a bit of help from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt;, I managed to get everything into after effects and put it together. Let the nostalgia commence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/84538247&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back in a glance, the things I notice are: less computer work, more socializing and the increment in the amount of beverages and food photos. Next to that, I failed keeping up this year and missed a lot of photos. Sometimes for a reason (no internet or phone), while on other dates I simply seem to forget. My goal for this year is to decrease the time from taking a photo and uploading it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taping interviews</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-13-taping-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 13:23:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-13-taping-interviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I&amp;rsquo;ve spend some time before camera lenses. On wednesday I got a call for an interview for RTL Nieuws about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cesweb.org/&#34;&gt;CES&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://tweakers.net/reviews/3376/de-trends-van-ces-2014-uhd-gebogen-schermen-en-wearables.html&#34;&gt;wearables&lt;/a&gt;. A quick interview got me &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rtlxl.nl/#!/rtl-nieuws-132237/dd7a5c61-4887-3127-ba7f-d0af85626b81&#34;&gt;2 minutes of fame (on from 18:10) on  television&lt;/a&gt;. On thursday, a longer interview for Arte TV, that will be shown later this month (viewable online too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/50c310a87c4a11e3a0000e8b33fa4d87_8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;camera-lens&#34;&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking up and getting down in Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 15:54:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-27-cooking-up-and-stepping-back-into-chemistry-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made a small visit to Paris at the start of November and I had the opportunity to visit the Lab Store. I&amp;rsquo;ve read about the concept in a book called The Lab that I&amp;rsquo;ve bought during my first visit to San Francisco. It&amp;rsquo;s just pure luck that I come across that book in a little bookstore, but it feels like the adventure is just about to start..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While visiting &lt;a href=&#34;http://labstore-paris.com&#34;&gt;the Lab Store&lt;/a&gt; I had to buy one of the Le Whaf&amp;rsquo;s. It&amp;rsquo;s sold out in the webstore, but I&amp;rsquo;m just too much into chemistry and cooking to let it go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Moves data for?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:29:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-12-18-using-moves-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/python-library-moves-app-api/&#34;&gt;a little wrapper for the Moves App API&lt;/a&gt;. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t develop the ideas I had for it any further due to time constraints. But other projects got me into it and I wanted to share what I&amp;rsquo;m currently  building. I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn the same concept of a fitbit dashboard over to a Moves Dashboard, so we can use the same data. And I&amp;rsquo;ve got some friends who come up with great ideas too! Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikeverbruggen.nl/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m explore the possiblity of using Moves to log car-mileage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Corner of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-27-curious-corner-of-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 20:47:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-27-curious-corner-of-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been walking around with a newsletter idea for some months now. It all started at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.permanentbeta.nl&#34;&gt;Permanent Beta&lt;/a&gt; where I gave a talk together with my &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;twin&lt;/a&gt;. Basically it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a talk, just a roadshow of awesome stuff we come across on our daily surf on the web. The audience loved it! Why not curate this content into a newsletter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just what I did with &lt;a href=&#34;http://curiouscorner.nl/&#34;&gt;The Curious Corner of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;, a monthly newsletter stocked with the stuff I find during that last month. However, curating would have taken a lot of my time if I didn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to manage it all. Coding to the rescue! A small Node.js app and bookmarklet for Chrome (or extension even) and within 2 hours I had a basic management system running. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/curious-corner&#34;&gt;code is up on github&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jawbone API Python library</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:15:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-11-15-jawbone-api-python-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jawbone.com/up&#34;&gt;Jawbone UP&lt;/a&gt; for the last few months. There are things I like about it, the app, the sleep interface and the options you have for notifications. Some other things I dislike, the 3.5mm jack for syncing for example&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s annoying. They have it solved with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jawbone.com/up&#34;&gt;the next version&lt;/a&gt; though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/jawbone-up-620x311.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jawbone-up-620x311&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all the other devices that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing I wanted to get the data out of it. And luckily Jawbone offers an API. So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/PyJawbone/&#34;&gt;the code is up on Github&lt;/a&gt; for you to use and fork.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twins in New York!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-29-twins-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 21:31:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-29-twins-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being in de United States is a perfect excuse for visiting my brother! After enjoying a 5 hour flight (with wifi!) and a delayed subway ride: here&amp;rsquo;s the two of us before the skyline of New York City:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/0c0a30ae346a11e3bc2722000a1faee5_8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kees and Joost&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had 8 days to explore the city, mostly by foot and metro. The first I found the most enjoyable, while the latter turned out to be faster most of the time. At least I walked all three off the main bridges to Manhatten and strolled trough Central Park and The Highline:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of your phone invoices</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-21-making-sense-of-your-phone-invoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 10:02:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-21-making-sense-of-your-phone-invoices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Telephone companies tend to have a lot of data about a user. This data includes some information that could help you decide whether you could pay for another subscription that fits more to your usage. To fix that problem I&amp;rsquo;ve build a dashboard which uses all the information available trough the invoices my current company (T-mobile) provides in a PDF. (FYI, I got a version running that&amp;rsquo;s also working with receipts from Vodafone)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&amp;rsquo;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be in. And what about the view:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick list of all my recent things in the media</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 09:22:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-09-30-recent-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September has been good on me so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve started my third year of my bachelor degree while on the opposite end my work seems to increase. I&amp;rsquo;ve been interviewed for a new TV-programme called Toekomstmakers. It&amp;rsquo;s in dutch but the video is can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uitzendinggemist.net/aflevering/232949/Toekomstmakers_rtl_Z.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also written a column about the Quantified Self an the influences it could create within the health sector. The column has been added to the book Diagnose Zorginnovatie and has been presented at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.diagnosetechnologie.nl/&#34;&gt;Diagnose Zorg Innovatie congres&lt;/a&gt;. A photo of my column(in dutch, click to enlarge) below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fitbit organisation dashboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 18:54:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-15-fitbit-organisation-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitbit.com&#34;&gt;Fitbit&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best tools for activity tracking.The interface is nice and the hardware is durable and syncs wirelessly. For a personal level is good, but using group-wise or equipping all employees with a Fitbit turns out to be non-existent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve spend some time building a dashboard that lets people see the data from all users within a group. It gets all data trough the Fitbit API and summarizes it into a view per day/week/month. Next to that I also plan to provide leaderboards, custom graphs and statistics. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of the app so far:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a tandem bicycle to Bregenz</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 17:40:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I left the small village of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.nl/maps/preview#!q=Sloten%2C+Friesland&amp;amp;data=!4m10!1m9!4m8!1m3!1d35409!2d5.6342587!3d52.8864423!3m2!1i1276!2i706!4f13.1&#34;&gt;Sloten&lt;/a&gt; in The Netherlands with a lofty goal, to reach Rome in Italy. On a tandem bicycle with a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/leaving.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Leaving on the tandem bicycle to Rome&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total distance around 2300km was meant to be covered. In the fourth day, we left the Netherlands and went into Germany.. Traveling trough the Ruhr area and cycling next to the Rhine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swabian_Jura&#34;&gt;Swabian Jura&lt;/a&gt; and with 2 weeks we covered most of Germany. Just before reaching Austria, our baggage carriage decided to break down and among some other things we decided we would quit at Bregenz. We finished a wonderfull adventure with 1125km on the odometer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A python library for the Moves App API</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 19:52:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-09-python-library-moves-app-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Quantified Self starters I recommend the really nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://moves-app.com/&#34;&gt;Moves App&lt;/a&gt;. The interface is really nice and the battery drain isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad if you recharge it twice a day. They recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.moves-app.com&#34;&gt;opened up their API enabling developers&lt;/a&gt; like me to create apps based on their platform. For me the first step towards creating an app is a easier way to communicate with the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/moves1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moves App&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the fitbit, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a open-source library for you to use! It&amp;rsquo;s available trough &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/PyMoves&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to improve my code, feel free to fork me! I will use this library for creating a website which let&amp;rsquo;s you export all data from Moves more easily. Because freedom of data is important, getting it out is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late night TekTok, talking QS and education</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-04-late-night-tektok-talking-qs-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 22:22:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-07-04-late-night-tektok-talking-qs-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month a give a small talk around the Quantified Self and how it fits into the education:&lt;/p&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9anEVAU7-eU?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What amazed me was that the room was full of inspiring people designing stuff for the &amp;rsquo;now&amp;rsquo;, thus implementing it only when the future is already happening. Nevertheless I&amp;rsquo;m sure some good things will follow because people are aware and the connectedness helps solving these things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into hardware!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-06-12-moving-into-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 20:34:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-06-12-moving-into-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software is not all there is, I&amp;rsquo;m diving into hardware! For the last month a lot of electronics have passed my hands, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://op-innovations.com&#34;&gt;sensors&lt;/a&gt;, arduinos and others. I&amp;rsquo;ve been given a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeymakey.com&#34;&gt;Makey Makey&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://loesberkhout.nl/&#34;&gt;Loes&lt;/a&gt; and now doing a hardware project in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://setup.nl&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/a&gt; and it involves this big red button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to keep you posted of my hardware adventures!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe Conference</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 11:42:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-15-qs-europe-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/8727272957_3e9c88504b_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;QS Europe Conference&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spend past weekend enjoying what I do most, submerge in a community driven event, to come out two days later sleep deprived but full with ideas and enthusiasm. As one of the organisers of the conference you might think that it&amp;rsquo;s a though thing to do, coordinating it all, but with a wonderful group of people from america and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/qsamsterdam/&#34;&gt;QS Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; team it was a blast!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small bite of news</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 20:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-05-07-small-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just two quick bits of newsworthy stuff I wanted to share with you since I got back from Italy (which was really wonderful!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a small interview about big-data for the dutch television programme Bedrijf in Beeld. Quite happy with the result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/65384154&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we reached the local dutch newspaper De Spits. The Quantified Self was mentioned by the Rode Kater, a famous little comic:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-up</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/client/partup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 22:55:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/client/partup/</guid>
      <description>Data strategy &amp;amp; API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Health Dashboard with Panic&#39;s Statusboard</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-15-building-personal-health-dashboard-panics-statusboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 22:43:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-15-building-personal-health-dashboard-panics-statusboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Panic released their &lt;a href=&#34;http://panic.com/statusboard/&#34;&gt;Statusboard app&lt;/a&gt; and I discovered it was possible to use JSON and html to embed it into pages, my mind raced with ideas about what to build. Both the Zeo and Fitbit API offer JSON output thus could be embeddable. To give a quick overview what it looks like with dummy data embedded, have a look at the following image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/photo.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Personal Health Dashboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to implement a simple server side script that shapes and caches the JSON data in the correct format. We&amp;rsquo;ll make that a weekend project. And you&amp;rsquo;re not limited to Fitbit or Zeo data any more, any API or maybe even trough &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stathat.com/&#34;&gt;StatHat&lt;/a&gt; could offer a way for making it visual for the personal health dashboard :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-visualisation for the Hogeschool van Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-11-data-visualisation-hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 21:49:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-11-data-visualisation-hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://heinzehavinga.nl/&#34;&gt;Heinze&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve guided and taught several students from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hva.nl/&#34;&gt;Hogeschool van Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; about data and data-visualisation. In 3 days packed with GPS-trackers, stories, examples and code we&amp;rsquo;ve made some interesting visualisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some were shown in Carre during the education conference organised by the Hogeschool van Amsterdam. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.captainvideo.nl/&#34;&gt;Captain Video&lt;/a&gt; for the awesome setup with a cube:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/carre.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carre, video and data-visualisation setup by Captain Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ofcourse I&amp;rsquo;ve also made my own data-visualisation. The data consists of minute-by-minute data available trough the Fitbit data API. This data is stored in a simple CSV file and visualised with D3, my favorite SVG library for visualisations, the result is a canvas with triangles related to the Hogeschool itself:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Mondrian like art with D3 &amp; Javascript</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-03-05-generating-mondrian-art-d3-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 15:38:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-03-05-generating-mondrian-art-d3-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://setup.nl/&#34;&gt;SETUP&lt;/a&gt; is holding a &lt;a href=&#34;http://elegant.setup.nl/&#34;&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt; to get programming known as modern day craftwork. I whole-fully agree to this and decided to enter the contest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a small part of my time spend while traveling I and finally finishing up I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/mondriaantje/&#34;&gt;my last version up and running&lt;/a&gt;. I use javascript and D3 (SVG) for drawing the elements as this is a library that I wanted to explore. The ease of use and adoption rate of it made a good starting point for me to quickly get to a result. Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s my version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Victory_Boogie-Woogie&#34;&gt;Victory Boogie-Woogie&lt;/a&gt;, but instead of inspired by a song, you manually input a text-string like a name:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the TV for VPRO Labyrint</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:47:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On sunday evening, the VPRO aired a new episode of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wetenschap24.nl/programmas/labyrint.html&#34;&gt;Labyrint&lt;/a&gt;, a show for popular science. This episode included coverage of the Quantified Self and an interview with me (in dutch)! I&amp;rsquo;ve included the video for you to watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pecha Kucha about The Quantified Self and Permanent Beta</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 14:55:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-12-pecha-kucha-quantified-self-permanent-beta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th of February I gave my first Pecha Kucha talk. Together with Jan-Henk Bouman we introduced the crowd (around 100 people) into the world of QS. With a geek to non-geek dialogue we kept our pace trough our 6:40 of fame. The video is below (in dutch):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/59338428&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/PermanentBeta/&#34;&gt;Permanent Beta meetup group&lt;/a&gt; for upcoming events about The Quantified Self!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8:36pm - 2012</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 23:26:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-01-29-836pm-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without further comments, all my 8:36pm photo moments collected during 2012, stitched together in &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/58417424&#34;&gt;a movie&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/58417424&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can say is, thanks to all the people who made 2012 an awesome year! I&amp;rsquo;m sure 2013 is going to be the same!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolite testing with Talking20</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 20:13:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-12-16-metabolite-testing-with-talking20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I arrived home this weekend, a small package was waiting for me. It included the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.talking20.com/&#34;&gt;Talking20 metabolite kit&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d pre-ordered. And tonight I finally got around of donating some of my blood to the spot card. The package included, 3 spot cards and envelopes, and for each spot-card: an alcohol wipe, bandage and 3 lancets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/photo-1-1024x764.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Talking20 kit includes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy to get started, but I also got some helpful assistance from my mother :). Anyhow, this is how the spot-card turned up:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Weekend Utrecht</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-11-20-startup-weekend-utrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 11:31:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-11-20-startup-weekend-utrecht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I participated in &lt;a href=&#34;http://utrecht.startupweekend.org&#34;&gt;Startup Weekend Utrecht&lt;/a&gt;. At almost 100 attendees, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the 8th floor of the Nijenoord building pretty stocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I predicted, I got an idea during the pitching process. Luckily I was able to pitch it anyhow and after the voting procedure the announcement was made that I made it to the top 13 viable ideas. So now I had to go and create a team! However, organising a team around my idea failed (too bad, reason: to complex for a startup weekend)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quantified Self and the New Aesthetic</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 01:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-28-the-quantified-self-new-aesthetic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Quantified Self is all about getting data about ourselves. We distill information and use that to our knowledge to improve our lives and that of others. Self-knowledge trough numbers. As we use algorithms in our lives we don&amp;rsquo;t think that often about how they see us, but this is exactly what the New Aesthetic is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/pixel_water_full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A pipe full of data, typical view of the New Aesthetic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the cross-over between the &lt;a href=&#34;new-aesthetic.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;New Aesthetic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quantifiedself.com&#34;&gt;QS&lt;/a&gt;. Machines and algorithms run our lives, and how they look at the world causes us to act. Can we view a part&lt;br&gt;
of the New Aesthetic in changes in behavior? Can we reflect to ourselves with the help of machine interpretation or vision?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karlskrona, Sweden</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-18-karlskrona-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:07:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-18-karlskrona-sweden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/ef93033e18ad11e295351231381d448e_7.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Karlskrona - Sweden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just here for a few days, united with my brother. Travelling trough Kopenhagen and the lower country-side of Sweden. Visiting Hyper Island while my brother finishes his project and going by train to Malmö on the last day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Heuristics</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:21:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-09-24-plugin-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the third &lt;a href=&#34;http://quantifiedself.com/conference/Palo-Alto-2012/&#34;&gt;Quantified Self Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Stanford last week I gave a talk about Plugin Heuristcs, a term that describes something I&amp;rsquo;ve come across during my years of self-tracking experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugin Heuristics confines an architecture that I propose for self-tracking things with a side-effect. For example when tracking my food intake for at least a month, it changed the way my brain remembers all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten. When I got started I could barely remember one day of intake, when a month has passed, your memory for food specific things increases to almost a week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking 500 kilometers</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-08-25-hiking-500-kilometers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 18:50:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-08-25-hiking-500-kilometers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I did this summer, together with a friend. And here&amp;rsquo;s one of the pictures I took:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_5618-e1345916976523-764x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The river Vecht near Ommen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(if your interested, you can find the route as KML &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.nl/maps?q=http://www.ge-paden.nl/pieterpad/kml-files/pieterpad.kml&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;source=websearch&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showertrack!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-07-15-showertrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 22:06:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-07-15-showertrack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So much projects, so little time&amp;hellip; But hey, let&amp;rsquo;s just use some of my spare time for keeping you guys updated on the stuff I do. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing several things, but the most interesting right now is a new iPhone app concept that we&amp;rsquo;ve been developing since last month. Together with Nils Waanders and Willemijn Edens we are creating an app which helps people save water while showering. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.showertrack.com/&#34;&gt;Showertrack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storify as slides for talks</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 15:34:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-05-31-storify-as-slides-for-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like &lt;a href=&#34;http://storify.com&#34;&gt;Storify&lt;/a&gt;, a service that lets you curate your own story based from sources like Twitter, Facebook or other social networks. And sometimes I wonder what would happen if you let people curate it live on a beamer during festivals or want to use it for public talks&amp;hellip; Then the website isn&amp;rsquo;t that handy or slide-enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that hard to extract all data from Storify and glue everything together into a slide-ready format right? With that idea in mind, I whipped up a quick little Bottle.py app on OpenShift provided by RedHat. Within 3 hours I connected the timeline from &lt;a href=&#34;http://timeline.verite.co&#34;&gt;Verite&lt;/a&gt; to Storify and &lt;a href=&#34;http://timeline-joost.rhcloud.com/&#34;&gt;Storify to Timeline&lt;/a&gt; was born:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Zeo Raw Data for performances</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-03-27-using-zeo-raw-data-for-performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:11:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-03-27-using-zeo-raw-data-for-performances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; I run a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hoofdbeelden.nl/&#34;&gt;little experiment called Hoofdbeelden&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a exploration for both of us as an artist and how we can use data generated by me as a person can be used for audio/visual performances. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a few gigs so far, but our last at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fiberfestival.nl/&#34;&gt;Fiber Festival&lt;/a&gt; certainly made sure for the both of us that this is something we want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short Hoofdbeelden is a system which allows us tap into devices hooked onto my body for real-time information. I wrote a little piece of software which reads all different kinds of devices and outputs OSC (Open Sound Control) messages so my brother can use those for visuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video&#39;s of a few talks I gave last few months</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-02-15-videos-of-a-few-talks-i-gave-last-few-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 13:03:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-02-15-videos-of-a-few-talks-i-gave-last-few-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve given several talks about the Quantified Self and lifehacking. The video&amp;rsquo;s of two of these talks are embedded below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban Screens
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/33543264&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspirationshot #3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/36606207&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datavisualisatie voor het CBS</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-16-datavisualisatie-voor-het-cbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 11:43:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-16-datavisualisatie-voor-het-cbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Het CBS organiseert &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datavisualisatiesinbeweging.nl/&#34;&gt;de eerste seminar over interactieve data visualisaties&lt;/a&gt; op 3 februari in Den Haag. Voor de seminar is een wedstrijd gemaakt en ik had een vrije middag over om er mee aan de slag te gaan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadat ik alle drie de data-sets heb bekeken leek het mij het beste om de derde (&lt;a href=&#34;http://statline.cbs.nl/StatWeb/publication/?VW=T&amp;amp;DM=SLNL&amp;amp;PA=80786NED&amp;amp;D1=0,2&amp;amp;D2=0&amp;amp;D3=a&amp;amp;D4=0,5-16&amp;amp;D5=a&amp;amp;HD=111129-0915&amp;amp;HDR=T,G1,G4&amp;amp;STB=G2,G3&#34;&gt;Landbouw; economische omvang naar omvangsklasse, hoofdbedrijfstype &amp;amp; regio&lt;/a&gt;) aan de slag te gaan. Nadat ik de data had gedownload heb ik eerst &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/google-refine/&#34;&gt;Google Refine&lt;/a&gt; gebruikt om de data schoon te maken en te filteren.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011, A Summary</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-01-2011-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 16:35:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-01-01-2011-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year has been full with adventures! Going to San Francisco, organizing QS Europe and starting another bachelor degree in Media Technology&amp;hellip; And of course I continued with taking a picture everyday at 8:36pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/34264892&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see what 2012 brings!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Europe 2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:02:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-12-19-qs-europe-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one year I started with my idea to go the the first Quantified Self Conference in San Francisco, Mountain View. The idea brought me there, with all the helping hands of people supporting me. When Martijn and me got back, we agreed to organize a second conference in Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The QS Amsterdam crew joined in and at the 26 &amp;amp; 27th of November we organized QS Europe. I never organized a conference so big and it was truly fantastic to see 250 people enjoying their time at the conference. To give a quick impression I wanted to share a video my brother made:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going interactive!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-21-going-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 11:24:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-21-going-interactive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of you may have noticed it already, but from now on, I&amp;rsquo;m available as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/freelance/&#34;&gt;freelancer&lt;/a&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;ve made the last step towards it two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m now registered at the Chamber of Commerce. Most of the projects are covered with this. And one of them is an interactive showcase for the Freemote festival in Utrecht in the beginning of December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; we are building a hybrid manifestation of visualizing brainwaves and other personal metrics. We combine our knowledge about programming, interfaces, visuals and self-quantification. Our project is called &amp;lsquo;hoofdbeelden&amp;rsquo; which means: &amp;lsquo;head images&amp;rsquo;. In the future I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to extend this visual project to include more metric about a person, including sociale network analysis and realtime streaming of heartrates or other bodily things you can measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up Inspiration: Mijn Reis naar #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:41:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 19th of september I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.standupinspiration.com&#34;&gt;Stand Up Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; and I could tell my story of my trip to San Francisco &amp;amp; the Quantified Self conference. The story is in dutch, but if you&amp;rsquo;re curious, have a look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/30073493&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moon phases and sleep patterns</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-06-moon-phases-and-sleep-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 10:54:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-06-moon-phases-and-sleep-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even before I got a Zeo, I was wondering if the phases of the moon are of influence of my sleep quality. With &lt;a href=&#34;http://myzeo.com&#34;&gt;the Zeo&lt;/a&gt; that offers an API, I finally had a chance to investigate. As it turns out after four months of experimenting: the phase of the moon doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any influence on my sleep quality or the time it takes to fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been building my own interface for the Zeo, because the flash based website doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit my needs, here&amp;rsquo;s a small screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing personal caloric values</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 09:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-27-publishing-personal-caloric-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started tracking my food intake with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodzy.com&#34;&gt;Foodzy&lt;/a&gt; about 13 days ago. And while doing that I already came across some interesting things. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been fully tracking my food intake, but the Foodzy app on my iPhone with extensive database (including typical dutch food) makes it quite easy. I&amp;rsquo;ve been tracking for thirteen days now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step I wanted to take is to generate a baseline of my typical food consumption(and thus caloric values), this way I can see where I can make improvements and measure the changes. A few days after I got started I was already more aware of my eating habits and started to make small changes. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where everything ends up, but there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I would like to share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview of my San Francisco Report</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 10:39:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-09-01-preview-of-my-san-francisco-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/SF-Report.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the people who sponsored me for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/san-francisco-2011-qs2011/&#34;&gt;my trip to San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m building a report inspired my &lt;a href=&#34;http://feltron.com/ar10_01.html&#34;&gt;Nicholas Felton&lt;/a&gt; about my trip. I wanted to show you a small preview on the right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to have at least 4 page worth of data to show you. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve never dived deep into Processing, the building time is somewhat extended, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know when it&amp;rsquo;ll be finished. I started studying Media Technology as well, so spare time is a little bit limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I would like to write.</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-08-17-how-i-would-like-to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 09:50:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-08-17-how-i-would-like-to-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From how to live safely in a sciencefictional universe by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Yu&#34;&gt;Charles Yu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m typing, even though strictly speaking I am using the TM-31’s cognitive-visual-motor-sound-activated recording module, which operates, as you might guess, by simultaneously tracking output from the user’s neural activity, voice, finger movements, retinal movements, and facial muscle contractions. It’s part keyboard, part microphone, part optical scan, and part brain scan. When I want to type, I raise my hands up in front of me, palms down, in a position approximating typing, and a virtual QWERTY layout materializes in front of me. When I want to switch to voice, I just start reading the book, and the unit switches to an auditory-recognition transcription system, converting my voice into modifications in the written text. If I get tired of typing and voice modes, I can simply read the text to myself, and the unit will track my eye movements to determine, with near-perfect accuracy, what word I am reading, based on the minute ups and downs, lefts and rights of my retinas, and then matching those movements, using brain activity data as a kind of rough double check, against the blood flow and heat output of various areas of my language- and concept-processing lobes and sublobes of my brain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python library for the FitBit API</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 20:50:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-18-python-library-fitbit-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My quest of building API wrappers in python continues with the FitBit. The handy devices tracks most of my activities and movements during daytime. So it&amp;rsquo;s an excellent self-tracking device, especially with the wireless sync. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t an API interface available in python, so with some &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/group/fitbit-api/browse_thread/thread/0a45d0ebed3ebccb&#34;&gt;borrowed code&lt;/a&gt; I decided to build my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jplattel/FitBit.py&#34;&gt;GitHub repository with the code and an example for you to use&lt;/a&gt;. Please fork and correct any changes that you think would be useful for me to learn! Also let me know where your using it, I would really like to know ;-).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync Kindle notes and clippings to Evernote</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-08-kindle-notes-evernote-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 12:11:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-07-08-kindle-notes-evernote-sync/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I got my Kindle I started reading a lot more books and articles. And one of the nice things you can do is add notes and clip certain pieces of text. The Kindle saves all those things into a text file for easy access, but I wanted those to be searchable as well in my system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a small python script that extracts all notes and clippings from the text file and creates a new note in Evernote for each of them. It&amp;rsquo;s quite crappy python, but at least my skills are improving a bit. You can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/1071682&#34;&gt;source-code on this gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First nights with the Zeo sleep monitor</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:53:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-22-zeo-sleep-monitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the QS Conference the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myzeo.com/&#34;&gt;awesome guys from Zeo&lt;/a&gt; gifted me one of their sleep monitors. And 1 week ago it arrived by mail. I promised to create as much value in return if I liked the Zeo. And I do, I absolutely do. Here is why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an average person sleep 8 hours a day you spend 1/3 of your life lying in bed&amp;hellip; That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time spend. The Zeo provides me with a much detailed insight into how my sleep and dreams progress during the night. My sleep is quite good, but I could never figure out how many times I awoke during the night or how much rem-sleep I got, but now I do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2559.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/IMG_2559-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Joost @ Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco&#34; title=&#34;Joost @ Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/amerika/&#34;&gt;to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/resourcerer&#34;&gt;Martijn Aslander&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My effort for a better readinglist</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-05-08-my-effort-for-a-better-readinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 10:24:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-05-08-my-effort-for-a-better-readinglist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.readitlaterlist.com/&#34;&gt;Read It Later List&lt;/a&gt; service. Each day I save about 20-30 articles from Google Reader or my Twitter client so I can read them later. However, these amounts make it hard for me to process all the things I save. That&amp;rsquo;s why I need a readinglist that has additional filtering/speed/shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my endeavors with Python continue, for the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing my own version of the perfect readinglist build upon the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.readitlaterlist.com/api/&#34;&gt;API of Read It Later List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My method for improving dream recall</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-19-my-method-for-improving-dream-recall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 20:26:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-19-my-method-for-improving-dream-recall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On average, a human spends one third (8 hours) of it&amp;rsquo;s time sleeping. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot and one of the reasons I decided to dip my interest into dreaming and dream recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/f04c71f48e4c3002feac28c5ed05f94d.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With trial and error, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a modified version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.world-of-lucid-dreaming.com/wake-induced-lucid-dreams.html&#34;&gt;WILD&lt;/a&gt; method that works for me with a success-rate of about 80% for dream recall, no lucid state yet. So here is how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the amount of sleep you want to get (preferring a multiple of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep#cite_note-12&#34;&gt;1.5 hours&lt;/a&gt; such as 7.5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set two alarm clocks, one half an hour in advance of the other. The last alarm should be the time you want to wake up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the first alarm in reach so you can turn it off immediately after it wakes you up (I use my iPhone for this one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I place the second one straight across the room which forces me to get out of bed (harsh but it works).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Done, now go forth and sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup improved my dream-recall and works about 80% of the time. I ordered a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitbit.com/&#34;&gt;FitBit&lt;/a&gt; to track movements during sleep for additional statistics, but as Tim Ferriss notes in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fourhourbody.com/&#34;&gt;4 Hour Body&lt;/a&gt;, movement does not equal certain sleep-states like REM or deep sleep. Nevertheless it should give me more insight in how my sleep progresses during the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extendability</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-15-extendability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 08:52:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-15-extendability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It started millions of years ago with fire and the invention of language. Then simple tools and in later stages, clothing and shoes. Nowadays the trend continues with more sophisticated technology. Smartphones and watches are some of the things we keep on us at all times. Humans have developed the habit to extend themselves by using technology. In such a way that it sprouted a certain feeling of loss when not having access to the technology of which we&amp;rsquo;ve made our own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobypicture Export</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-10-mobypicture-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 19:42:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-04-10-mobypicture-export/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobypicture.com/&#34;&gt;Mobypicture&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s the service I use to post my pictures onto Twitter, Flickr and Facebook. It makes uploading photos from my mobile phone as simple as it could possibly be. Even better, the service is free to use, unlike Flickr which only allows access to last 200 images if you go with their freemium model. But sadly using Mobypicture isn&amp;rsquo;t without downsides. There is no export functionality as of yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what am I tracking?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 12:26:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-31-what-am-i-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll figured out to publish this, not only for my archives, but also to share some insight into the data that a person could generate. Have a look at the things I&amp;rsquo;m tracking to function as an archive or feedback loop. If I have some more time, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the things I use to make this all possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distance travelled (which cities did I visit?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which people do I meet everyday?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What projects did I work on? And how much time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much work got done? (productivity, scale 1-10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I physically and mentally? (1-10 scale for both)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top 5 of nice and bad things that happend today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General rate of the day (1-10 scale)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much coffee, tea, water etc did I drink (no other food tracking yet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I exercise? Is the activity logged by Runkeeper? (speed &amp;amp; GPS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreams (not quite everyday but interesting as I&amp;rsquo;m exploring lucid dreaming)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many hours did I sleep (and how well rested am I each morning?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a picture everyday at 8:36pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily photo of myself with the Everyday App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading patterns (mashup through Read It Later list)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software usage with Rescue Time &amp;amp; Wakoopa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casually I track my mouse patterns with MacLogger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lifelapses (only on special events)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition there are other data-stream which can be used for data collection:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Brussels</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 21:55:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I travelled to Brussels so I could give a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Quantified-Self-Show-Tell-Brussels/&#34;&gt;Quantified Self Meetup&lt;/a&gt; group there. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in the startup &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/scanadude&#34;&gt;Scanadu&lt;/a&gt; which is about broadcasting your health. Together with people like &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/walterdebrouwer&#34;&gt;Walter de Brouwer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/mishachellam&#34;&gt;Misha Chellam&lt;/a&gt; we are going to take a different approach to health. During my stay in Brussels I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot (including my level of French, it&amp;rsquo;s really bad!). Really liked the city though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring mouse interaction</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 22:12:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-02-27-measuring-mouse-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an avid user of shortcuts and like to improve my workflow and I would like to discover hidden patterns. This is what happens next. When I bought my Mac 2 months ago I dumped my mouse in favor of the trackpad. Did this influence my mouse/trackpad interaction? Sadly I can&amp;rsquo;t draw any conclusions about it because I switched my operating system too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However more recently I started using MacLogger and together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://gedachtes.van.jelleakkerman.nl/&#34;&gt;Jelle&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve made some custom python and processing scripts that should offer more insight into my mouse usage. When I showed the screenshot below to Jelle he noticed I don&amp;rsquo;t use my dock, as there are almost no points of rest at the side or bottom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dabblings in Processing</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-08-dabblings-in-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 14:20:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-08-dabblings-in-processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The collected data of 2010, mostly trough &lt;a href=&#34;http://PersonalStats.nl&#34;&gt;PersonalStats&lt;/a&gt;, but Foursquare and Twitter too, is a huge amount. Next to interpreting this data and using the information to create a feedback moment, the data can also turned into art. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feltron.com&#34;&gt;Nicholas Felton&lt;/a&gt; makes a perfect example: his highly interesting Annual Report fascinates me in both visual and informational ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;Kees&lt;/a&gt; discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.processing.org&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt;, it left me wondering what I could do with it. Just before 2011 I decided to make a Annual Report with Processing as my weapon of choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010, A summary</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-31-2010-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 12:16:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-31-2010-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; title: 2010, A summary date: 2010-12-31 12:16:04.000000000 +01:00 &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year passed with an excellent speed, not to quick, but certainly not slowly. I think pictures say more then words so I would like to share with you every picture I took at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/836pm/&#34;&gt;8:36pm&lt;/a&gt; during 2010:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/18211916&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Huge thanks to my brother &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ikbenke.es&#34;&gt;Kees&lt;/a&gt; who was so kind to make a video of it!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geolocation based grocery reminders</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-04-geolocation-based-grocery-reminders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 14:26:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-04-geolocation-based-grocery-reminders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t like shopping for groceries and I developed the habit to forget half of my groceries&amp;hellip;. A digital grocery list would be perfect&amp;hellip;. shortly after discussing todo-lists with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/resourcerer&#34;&gt;Martijn Aslander&lt;/a&gt; I was inspired to build a mashup to solve my problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/Image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/&#34;&gt;information gathered&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://instamapper.com/&#34;&gt;Instamapper&lt;/a&gt; in combination with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haversine_formula&#34;&gt;Haversine formula&lt;/a&gt; it is possible to calcuate the distance between two points on a sphere. When the distance is small enough a push notification including a link to my digital grocery list is send to my iPhone &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.notifo.com/&#34;&gt;trough the Notifo API&lt;/a&gt;. My knowledge of python and App Engine is slowly growing and these kind of mashups are great exercises!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on data portability</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 14:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-25-thoughts-on-data-portability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am troubled by data portability. It is a highly overlooked factor. And in many services I used for collecting the export function was simply not present.. If i left the service I lost my data, a sad case&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent actions of social networks like facebook allow a user to export data, but only by rules set by facebook. Another example could be Runkeeper, which i use to collect my efforts of exercising. Runkeeper currently does not allow for any export, but i can make use of my tweets send out by the applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shoot a photo at 8:36pm?</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-09-why-shoot-a-photo-at-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 11:24:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-11-09-why-shoot-a-photo-at-836pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the second of January 2010 I started &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/836pm/&#34;&gt;shooting a picture everyday at 8:36pm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://enjoymentland.com/2009/02/07/836pm/&#34;&gt;inspired by Buster Benson&lt;/a&gt;. Curiosity brought me into it, and if people asked me why I often could not give a sufficient answer. As if it were a form of art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I often wonder about history&amp;hellip; How people lived and how further back you go, the less we remember or can find. Technology nowadays could help us bring a more complete image to our future. That&amp;rsquo;s why I am shooting a picture everyday: &lt;em&gt;to bring current history to a more complete image in the future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My view of technology</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-06-my-view-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 18:42:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-10-06-my-view-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;random&lt;/strong&gt; train of thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When biology is technology and man tries to grasp the amount of data generated and collected, most people think of this as unnatural. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s true that mankind can not yet understand the potential of ambient measuring of information streams. Ubiquitous capture of data could bring insight in how technology and specifically our body (which is a perfect example of technology in it&amp;rsquo;s own right) works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QS Amsterdam Recap #1</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 11:41:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-09-27-qs-amsterdam-recap-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 20 september the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/qsamsterdam/&#34;&gt;Quantified Self Amsterdam Meetup&lt;/a&gt; took place in &lt;em&gt;het volkskrantgebouw&lt;/em&gt;. More then 60 people attended and we had guests from Germany and France! A &lt;a href=&#34;http://quantifiedself.com/&#34;&gt;full recap&lt;/a&gt; can be found on the main QS blog and the video’s on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/qsams&#34;&gt;vimeo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ter-burg.nl/&#34;&gt;Sebastiaan ter Burg&lt;/a&gt; provided the video/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/qsams&#34;&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt; capture and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ikbenke.es/&#34;&gt;Kees Plattel&lt;/a&gt; made a wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/14967809&#34;&gt;intro&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this amazing meetup with interesting talks! If you are interested sign up for our meetup group and we will let you know when the next event is! Or do you have a personal story to share, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/contact/&#34;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoTracking: streaming GPS locations</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 21:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-08-31-geotracking-streaming-gps-locations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am trying to publish my blogposts in English to reach a wider public. However since English is my second language please forgive me my spelling errors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reading about self-tracking I was fascinated by GPS location and geospatial analysis. As it turns out …. experiments had been done before and I wanted to experience what you could do with the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/8545134&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wondered if it were possible for me recreate this, using my less then basic programming skills and no more utilities then my iPhone. So I ventured into python and after reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://eric-blue.com/2010/08/28/geolocation-gps-and-self-tracking/&#34;&gt;Eric Blue’s blog&lt;/a&gt; I came up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👨‍💻 About</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;profile-image&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/joost_plattel.png&#34;
    alt=&#34;Joost Plattel&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;👋 Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m Joost, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to call myself an &lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;auxiliary&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; technologist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I facilitate organisations and individuals with technology. The daunting task to strategize in a changing world is made hard by the lack of transparency and previous experiences. I explore the fringes of new technology and keep a wide network of people to draw from different avenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By building prototypes, tinkering and iterating publicly we can discover what may lie ahead. Whether you would like physical device that measures something or an headless API that serves your customers, I&amp;rsquo;ll be delighted to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📫 Contact</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to get in touch we me, the easiest way is to reach out by email. You can email me at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jsplattel@gmail.com&#34;&gt;jsplattel@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foar de kofje net eamelje!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;~ A frisian saying meaning: don&amp;rsquo;t whine before we had a coffee.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>