<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantified self on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>http://jplattel.nl/tags/quantified-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantified self on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:25:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jplattel.nl/tags/quantified-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A lecture in Ghent</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 11:25:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-12-02-a-lecture-in-ghent/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I gave a lecture in Ghent, a beautiful city and so I decided to spend the weekend at an AirBnB host to enjoy the city! Here&#39;s a picture I took:
I&#39;ve uploaded all the slides from the lecture on Slideshare for you to enjoy.

It was my longest lecture and I&#39;ve learned some useful things while doing so. I find that having a storyline with little pieces is harder to keep up over longer times, so next time I will try to venture more in depth of some of my personal tracking experiments, for example my phone usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Phone Usage with iPython</title>
      <link>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:35:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jplattel.nl/post/2015-10-12-quantified-phone-usage-ipython/</guid>
      <description>Technology is making it easier to collect data, for example phone usage. From the 1st of January I tracked how much I&#39;ve used my phone by installing an app called Moment. It runs in the background and silently tracks how much you use your phone. As said, the first step towards behaviour-change is providing insight in current behaviour. Lately I&#39;ve been exploring iPython for data-analysis and sharing snippets of data. I&#39;ve started a Github repository that contains some notebooks I&#39;m working on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>