<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joost on Joost Plattel</title>
    <link>https://jplattel.nl/categories/joost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Joost on Joost Plattel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:42:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jplattel.nl/categories/joost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On holiday in Italy: Rome, Florence, Pisa &amp; Cinque Terre</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 15:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-08-25-holiday-italy-cinque-terre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I spend 2 weeks in Italy together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://chantalvankempen.nl/&#34;&gt;Chantal&lt;/a&gt;. We started off in Rome, spending our time in Trastevere. We visited all the main tourist attractions, because I hadn&#39;t visited Rome before. Time passed by pretty quickly and we traveled to Florence by BlaBlaCar. After a day of traveling, it&#39;s great to jump in a pool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florence is an amazing city, especially when you can watch the sun set over the city, the food is good and if you dive a bit into Italian culture you&#39;ll find hidden gems! Next up was San Gimigniano, a little town with lots of towers. We stayed in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://agriturismo.it&#34;&gt;agriturismo&lt;/a&gt; for 1 night, I cannot recommend this enough if you are somewhere in Tuscania. We visited Pisa before going to La Spezia, which would be our take off point for the main goal of our trip: Cinque Terre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cinque Terre is series of villages at the waterfront of Liguria, and I&#39;d like to show you one image for every village:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jplattel.nl/img/2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riomaggiore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-large wp-image-3536&#34; src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/2-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Riomaggiore, one of the five villages of cinque terre&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London on a double-bike</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:09:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-07-25-double-bike-london/</guid>
      <description>On sunday the 10th of June I left my parents place on a double-bike. Together with a friend we cycled to Zwolle, took a train and prepared ourselves in the evening for a trip to London. As we took the boat to Harwich the next day I didn&#39;t know what to expect as I hadn&#39;t visited England before.

As we talked with locals it turns out it&#39;s much more enjoyable if you take the small hilly roads towards your destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and reflections about 2015</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 17:34:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2016-01-02-data-reflections-2015/</guid>
      <description>Another year passed an I&#39;m due to update my projects page and create another one for next year! To close past year and explore the next I&#39;ve used YearCompass for my reflections. It took me over 3 afternoons to completely fill it out, but it&#39;s an enjoyable ride! It&#39;s great looking backwards into your calendar and see all that you have achieved.
I&#39;ve also concatenated all my 8:36pm photos into a video like I do every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka for holiday!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 14:30:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-09-22-sri-lanka-for-holiday/</guid>
      <description>Long overdue, but now I have some time to spend writing a blogpost. The previous month I&#39;ve spend 3 weeks in Sri Lanka! For two weeks, we discovered the island, visiting beaches, jungle, towns and cities. The culture is wonderful and people are very friendly. It&#39;s also been a great opportunity to try out some new things, for example dabbling in photography and exploring apps like VSCO. In this post, all of the pictures have been shot with a S-120 and then improved with VSCO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the Intelligence Room</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2015-02-02-creating-intelligence-room/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months I&#39;ve been steadily involved with a project that aims to recreate an war/control/intelligence room that you see in movies. The one difference is that the room is ment for decision-makers within bigger companies. Often, urgent en relevant questions go unanswered, but the Intelligence Room helps fixing this.
During the Big Improvement Day we showcased our concept and I&#39;ve created a little Django app that matches all attendees based on topics they provided when signing up for the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I made it into another book and co-authored my first white-paper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-27-made-into-another-book-and-white-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 22:52:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-03-27-made-into-another-book-and-white-paper/</guid>
      <description>Last year I gave a little talk at the Cross Media Cafe in Hilversum. Happily afterwards I gave a little interview and people took a few photos. This year started pretty nice with some media coverage, but at the end of february a book landed in the mail:

I made a scan of the page and it&#39;s available on Scribd. And together with the working group of patient generated data, we&#39;ve written a white paper about the data that persons generate that healthcare could use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the 8:36pm photos of 2013</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:06:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2014-01-20-836pm-photos-2013/</guid>
      <description>Like last year, I made a small video of all my 8:36pm photos. With a bit of help from my brother, I managed to get everything into after effects and put it together. Let the nostalgia commence:

Looking back in a glance, the things I notice are: less computer work, more socializing and the increment in the amount of beverages and food photos. Next to that, I failed keeping up this year and missed a lot of photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and #QS13</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:56:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-10-14-san-francisco-and-qs13/</guid>
      <description>Taking a week off from my study, hopping on the plane to San Francisco on monday morning at 10 o&#39;clock. Arrived at noon and we managed to hack our way into the AirBnB place. Uptime: 24 hours. Grab a beer with Yuri and Peter. Decide to visit the Apple Store and do some misc shopping. Italian dinner. Crash on a couch. Conclusion: way better then classes I&#39;m supposed to be in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a tandem bicycle to Bregenz</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 17:40:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-08-05-on-a-tandem-bicycle-to-bregenz/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I left the small village of Sloten in The Netherlands with a lofty goal, to reach Rome in Italy. On a tandem bicycle with a friend.
A total distance around 2300km was meant to be covered. In the fourth day, we left the Netherlands and went into Germany.. Traveling trough the Ruhr area and cycling next to the Rhine.
Next, the Swabian Jura and with 2 weeks we covered most of Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-visualisation for the Hogeschool van Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-11-data-visualisation-hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 21:49:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-04-11-data-visualisation-hogeschool-van-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>Together with Heinze I&#39;ve guided and taught several students from the Hogeschool van Amsterdam about data and data-visualisation. In 3 days packed with GPS-trackers, stories, examples and code we&#39;ve made some interesting visualisations.
Some were shown in Carre during the education conference organised by the Hogeschool van Amsterdam. Thanks Captain Video for the awesome setup with a cube:
Ofcourse I&#39;ve also made my own data-visualisation. The data consists of minute-by-minute data available trough the Fitbit data API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the TV for VPRO Labyrint</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:47:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2013-02-26-vpro-labyrint/</guid>
      <description>On sunday evening, the VPRO aired a new episode of Labyrint, a show for popular science. This episode included coverage of the Quantified Self and an interview with me (in dutch)! I&#39;ve included the video for you to watch below:

I&#39;m very happy with the end result! As tracking becomes more ubiquitous more people will start to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karlskrona, Sweden</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-18-karlskrona-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:07:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2012-10-18-karlskrona-sweden/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;attachment_2476&#34; align=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;612&#34; caption=&#34;Karlskrona - Sweden&#34;][/caption]
Just here for a few days, united with my brother. Travelling trough Kopenhagen and the lower country-side of Sweden. Visiting Hyper Island while my brother finishes his project and going by train to Malmö on the last day. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going interactive!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-21-going-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 11:24:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-11-21-going-interactive/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may have noticed it already, but from now on, I&#39;m available as freelancer! I&#39;ve made the last step towards it two weeks ago and I&#39;m now registered at the Chamber of Commerce. Most of the projects are covered with this. And one of them is an interactive showcase for the Freemote festival in Utrecht in the beginning of December.
Together with my brother we are building a hybrid manifestation of visualizing brainwaves and other personal metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up Inspiration: Mijn Reis naar #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:41:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-10-10-stand-up-inspiration-mijn-reis-naar-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>Op 19 september was ik bij Stand Up Inspiration en mocht daar mijn verhaal van mijn reis vertellen. Gelukkig is dit op video opgenomen door Daan van Bergen (Videologic). Ik startte wat zenuwachtig, maar ben wel erg blij met het resultaat:
http://vimeo.com/30073493</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco 2011 &amp; #QS2011</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:49:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-06-07-san-francisco-2011-qs2011/</guid>
      <description>On the 25th of may my trip started with a 11 hour long flight straight to San Francisco to visit the Quantified Self Conference in Mountain View. The trip was funded by donations, ideas and people.
Together with Martijn Aslander I&#39;ve spent the first few days as a tourist and visited most of the spots that represent San Francisco. Then we boarded the Caltrain for Mountain View.
I volunteered at the the conference which brought me way more then being just there as a guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actie voor mijn reis naar San Francisco!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-18-actie-voor-mijn-reis-naar-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 14:30:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-18-actie-voor-mijn-reis-naar-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>Het gaat keihard met mijn spaarpotje voor mijn reis naar Amerika(San Francisco), heel veel mensen hebben al geholpen door te doneren of door het verder te verspreiden. Inmiddels ben ik over de 60%, en heb ik nog twee maanden te gaan. Dat ga ik dus met deze snelheid prima redden!
Om de hele actie een boost te geven heb ik het volgende bedacht:
Ik verloot 1 middag sparren/hulp/brainstormen/(invullen) met mij over bijvoorbeeld Slimmer Werken of The Quantified Self of een ander onderwerp waarbij ik jou kan helpen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Brussels</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 21:55:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-03-13-trip-to-brussels/</guid>
      <description>This week I travelled to Brussels so I could give a talk at the Quantified Self Meetup group there. And I&#39;ve been involved in the startup Scanadu which is about broadcasting your health. Together with people like Walter de Brouwer and Misha Chellam we are going to take a different approach to health. During my stay in Brussels I&#39;ve learned a lot (including my level of French, it&#39;s really bad!). Really liked the city though!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De durftevragen nieuwjaarsboost!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-23-de-durftevragen-nieuwjaarsboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 13:04:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2011-01-23-de-durftevragen-nieuwjaarsboost/</guid>
      <description>Via Jeroen was ik uitgenodigd om een workshop te geven bij de Durftevragen Nieuwjaarsboost 2011. Helemaal in Eindhoven! Maar na een lange reis vanuit het zuidwesten van Friesland belandde ik op mijn bestemming. Ik liep naar buiten en keek op mijn iPhone waar ik naar toe moest.... Oei, dat was nog wel een kilometer of 2 te voet. Een goed moment om de LifeLapse uit te testen, daarover in een andere blogpost meer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010, A summary</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-31-2010-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 12:16:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-12-31-2010-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>This year passed with an excellent speed, not to quick, but certainly not slowly. I think pictures say more then words so I would like to share with you every picture I took at 8:36pm during 2010:
 (Huge thanks to my brother Kees who was so kind to make a video of it!)
Not only did I finish my bachelor degree this year, but I also started Qs Amsterdam and some other interesting projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Minute of Fame - Stand Up Inspiration: 8:36pm</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-18-1-minute-of-fame-stand-up-inspiration-836pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 13:56:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-18-1-minute-of-fame-stand-up-inspiration-836pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://standupinspiration.com/&#34;&gt;Stand Up Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; Ideeën, gedachten en visies, gebracht door kritische en enthousiaste denkers uit verschillende werelden; inspiratie in interactie met de zaal. Dat is in een notendop #SUI. De laatste editie was gisteren op 17 mei 2010, de 16e. Deze post gaat over die daarvoor, nummer 15. Toen had ik mijn 1 minute of fame vlak na de pauze:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;object classid=&#34;clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;src&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11817627&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11817627&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kort samengevat: blubber in alle kleuren van de regenboog maar trots dat ik het gedaan heb! :D&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mede-auteur van 150 lifehackingtips!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-13-mede-auteur-van-150-lifehackingtips-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 12:34:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2010-05-13-mede-auteur-van-150-lifehackingtips-2/</guid>
      <description>Hij ligt al bijna 2 maanden in de winkel, maar ik wou het graag met jullie delen: ik ben sindskort mede-auteur van het boek 150 lifehackingtips. Begonnen als hulpschrijver voor Martijn en inmiddels volledig zelf schrijver(Al moet er binnenkort weer eens een postje uit!).
150 #lifehacking tips is de volgende iteratie van 100 lifehacking tips welke al eerder was uitgebracht bij Van Duuren.
Patrick Mackaaij heeft een prima lijstje met auteurs verzameld!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Totaal onverwacht: In de spits!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-26-totaal-onverwacht-in-de-spits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 10:41:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-26-totaal-onverwacht-in-de-spits/</guid>
      <description>Julien Hogemans wist mij vandaag te spotten in de Spits! Totaal niet verwacht dat ik in de krant zou belanden.. Samen met Martijn Aslander! Het interview dat ik voor Nobiles.nl had gegeven is ook gepubliceerd in de Spits. Goede reclame voor lifehacking! Een screenshot of download de PDF(27 mb!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview voor Nobiles.nl Magazine</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-17-interview-voor-nobiles-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 11:57:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-10-17-interview-voor-nobiles-magazine/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; caption=&#34;Stukje Nobiles Magazine&#34;][/caption]
Begin september ben ik voor de eerste keer geïnterviewd. Het interview was voor nobiles.nl een blad voor studenten en alumni en het ging over lifehacking! Ze waren opzoek naar studenten die lifehacking gebruiken voor de studie of in het dagelijkse leven. Via Google kwamen ze terecht op mijn blog :) Het interview is samengevat en gebruikt voor het grote artikel over lifehacking.
Het stukje over mij heb ik even ingescand en is hiernaast te lezen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardlopen met RunKeeper</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-27-hardlopen-met-runkeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 18:28:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-27-hardlopen-met-runkeeper/</guid>
      <description>Ze zijn nu 4 weken in mijn bezit en lopen nogsteeds heerlijk. Ik heb het over mijn Vibram Five Fingers :D Omdat ik graag wat data wil zien, en graag mag klooien met mashups, was ik opzoek gegaan naar een iPhone applicatie die voor mij het loggen van een stuk hardlopen overnam. Voorheen tekende ik braaf een lijntje op Google Maps erbij, maar dat kostte teveel moeite.
En ik ben dan wel zo iemand die het zichzelf zo gemakkelijk mogelijk maakt ;) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Op blote voeten Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-16-op-blote-voeten-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 13:57:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-16-op-blote-voeten-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&#34;&#34; align=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; caption=&#34;Vibram Five Fingers - Classic Black&#34;][/caption]
Naar aanleiding van mijn vorige post even een vervolg. Ik loop nu al 2 en een halve week op de Vibram Five Fingers. Niet elke dag, want af en toe wil ik ook wel wat anders, omdat ik last heb van spierpijn in mijn voeten.
Ik ben inmiddels al 3 keer wezen hardlopen, driemaal 5 kilometer. Maar toch krijg ik het niet voor elkaar om alles in een keer uit te lopen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joost loopt op Vibram Five Fingers</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-06-joost-loopt-op-vibram-five-fingers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 15:36:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-09-06-joost-loopt-op-vibram-five-fingers/</guid>
      <description>Sommige hebben we er al op zien lopen rondbazuinen, andere mensen vinden ze lelijk , maar nog veel meer mensen staren heel lang naar je voeten...
Waar heb ik het over? Over het genot om over op blote voeten te lopen, want daar houd ik van. En gelukkig kan dat nu, overal! Ik kwam de schoenen tegen op de blog van Tim Ferris, toen vond ik ze nog wat apart, maar nieuwsgierig als ik was heb ik toch nog even gegoogled en het bleek dat er veel mensen zijn die er positief over waren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Your Happiness!</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-21-track-your-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 11:47:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-08-21-track-your-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;De afgelopen 2 maanden heb ik meegewerkt aan het &lt;a title=&#34;Track Your Happiness&#34; href=&#34;https://www.trackyourhappiness.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Track Your Happiness&lt;/a&gt; project. Dat is een wetenschappelijk onderzoek in een online jasje, dat onderzoek doet naar de &#39;happiness&#39; van alle mensen die eraan meewerken. Elke dag kreeg je 3 keer een email met een link naar een interview, deze vulde je in. En 2 maanden later was er een rapport van jezelf opgesteld, voor mij waren dit de meest opzienbarende resultaten:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Dagen Daytum</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-07-11-100-dagen-daytum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 13:46:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-07-11-100-dagen-daytum/</guid>
      <description>Self-tracking, personal informatics of voor de lol, Daytum houd ik inmiddels al 100 dagen bij, daar om even een lijst met punten wat ik inmiddels van mezelf heb geleerd.
In 100 dagen heb ik:  1226 keer gedronken, alles totaal dus  257 keer water 206 keer koffie 118 keer limonade 387 keer bier (diverse soorten)   411 boterhammen gegeten  vruchtenhageslag is het lekkerste met 41 keer daarna sandwichspread met 39 keer ook krentenbollen zijn goed te kanen met 32 keer   35 ijsjes, waarvan 20 raketten :) Mjum!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifehacking Academy</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-05-27-lifehacking-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 11:44:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-05-27-lifehacking-academy/</guid>
      <description>Gister was lifehacking academy in Groningen, met 6 man gingen we dinsdag vroeg op pad. Eenmaal de groep bij elkaar, en zittend in de trein, werd ik gebeld door Martijn Aslander, of wij op het Palace of Wisdom zouden willen staan met ons zessen. Natuurlijk willen wij dat, als beginnende groep slimmer werken coaches kunnen wij de experts uithangen en de nodige reclame maken en connecties gebruiken.
Om ongeveer 11 uur waren wij aanwezig in Images, en zochten wij een mooie plaats uit in de grote zaal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C2W Expo: Personal Brand Award 2009</title>
      <link>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-03-26-c2w-expo-personal-brand-award-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 12:23:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jplattel.nl/post/2009-03-26-c2w-expo-personal-brand-award-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;C2W Career Expo&#34; src=&#34;https://jplattel.nl/img/logo_button.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;190&#34; height=&#34;130&#34; /&gt;De C2W Expo is een expo voor mensen die geintresseerd zijn in Life Sciences. Gister werd deze expo gehouden in het Beatrix Gebouw te Utrecht. Na de opening om ongeveer 10 uur waren en workshops te bezoeken. En een hele diversiteit aan stands van bedrijven waren ook aanwezig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik had besloten om naar de workshop van &lt;a title=&#34;Bert Van Dijk&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bertvandijk.eu/&#34;&gt;Bert Van Dijk&lt;/a&gt; te gaan. De workshop ging over de Power Of Persuasion, hoe kan je het beste iemand overtuigen? Allereerst maakt Bert Van Dijk onderscheid tussen ratten en schatten. Een rat is iemand die alles doet om zichzelf goed neer te zetten, een schat daarin tegen geeft alles weg aan collega&#39;s en vrienden, maar dan bleef er niets meer over voor jezelf. Als je dus iemand wil overtuigen moet je eigenlijk er precies tussen in zitten. Een aantal sketches werden gespeeld met een acteur van GTST (Ik kijk geen TV, teminste bijna niet, dus die naam ben ik alweer vergeten, ik geloof dat het Bas ..... was?) Uit de sketches bleek dat ook non-verbale comminucatie ook een grote rol speelt of je iemand kunt overtuigen. Een hele nuttige workshop dus, maar om het echt goed te kunnen begrijpen, zal je het vaak moeten oefenen en je er goed in moeten verdiepen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pauze! Even snel wat broodjes gescoord en nog even wat stands van bedrijven bezocht. Er zater wel een aantal bedrijven bij waarmee met passie werd gesproken, maar bijna niemand durfde over de negatieve kanten te praten. Jammer :( want om een goed beeld te krijgen heb je natuurlijk het hele plaatje nodig!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om 14:00 starte de presentatie van &lt;a title=&#34;Tom Scholte: Personal Branding&#34; href=&#34;http://www.tomscholte.com/&#34;&gt;Tom Scholte&lt;/a&gt;. Tom is specialist omtrend personal branding. Alvorens zijn presentatie wilde hij graag eerst een prijs uitreiken. Aan wie? Tsja, ik wist het zelf ook niet, maar ik was de winnaar van de C2W Personal Branding Award :) ! Tom had ik alleen een aantal dagen via &lt;a title=&#34;Twitter - Tom Scholte&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/TomScholte&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; aangesproken omdat ik benieuwd was naar zijn presentatie! Nou hier heb je hem, de presentatie die daarna volgde, en waarin ik zonder dat ik het wist een grote rol zou spelen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>